
0 Thailand's -- -- O
1 Muslim -- -- O
2 south -- -- O
3 hit -- -- O
4 with -- -- O
5 daily -- -- O
6 killings -- -- O

7 BANGKOK -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
8 , -- -- O
9 June -- -- O
10 16 -- -- O
11 ( -- -- O
12 AFP -- -- O
13 ) -- -- O

14 A -- -- O
15 policeman -- -- O
16 and -- -- O
17 a -- -- O
18 school -- -- O
19 employee -- -- O
20 have -- -- O
21 been -- -- O
22 shot -- -- O
23 dead -- -- O
24 in -- -- O
25 southern -- -- O
26 Thailand -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
27 , -- -- O
28 the -- -- O
29 latest -- -- O
30 victims -- -- O
31 of -- -- O
32 a -- -- O
33 wave -- -- O
34 of -- -- O
35 violence -- -- O
36 which -- -- O
37 has -- -- O
38 claimed -- -- O
39 the -- -- O
40 lives -- -- O
41 of -- -- O
42 at -- -- O
43 least -- -- O
44 200 -- -- O
45 people -- -- O
46 this -- -- O
47 year -- -- O
48 , -- -- O
49 police -- -- O
50 said -- -- O
51 Wednesday -- -- O
52 . -- -- O

53 Policeman -- -- O
54 Veerasak -- -- B-PER.Police
55 Thipmanee -- -- I-PER.Police
56 , -- -- O
57 50 -- -- O
58 , -- -- O
59 was -- -- O
60 gunned -- -- O
61 down -- -- O
62 Tuesday -- -- O
63 in -- -- O
64 Narathiwat -- -- B-GPE.Provincestate.Provincestate
65 province's -- -- O
66 Tak -- -- B-GPE
67 Bai -- -- I-GPE
68 district -- -- O
69 near -- -- O
70 the -- -- O
71 Malaysian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
72 border -- -- O
73 as -- -- O
74 he -- -- O
75 rode -- -- O
76 his -- -- O
77 motorbike -- -- O
78 to -- -- O
79 work -- -- O
80 , -- -- O
81 a -- -- O
82 local -- -- O
83 police -- -- O
84 officer -- -- O
85 said -- -- O
86 . -- -- O

87 " -- -- O
88 The -- -- O
89 shooting -- -- O
90 is -- -- O
91 probably -- -- O
92 part -- -- O
93 of -- -- O
94 the -- -- O
95 current -- -- O
96 violence -- -- O
97 as -- -- O
98 there -- -- O
99 are -- -- O
100 shootings -- -- O
101 every -- -- O
102 day -- -- O
103 now -- -- O
104 ," -- -- O
105 he -- -- O
106 told -- -- O
107 AFP -- -- O
108 . -- -- O

109 Within -- -- O
110 an -- -- O
111 hour -- -- O
112 of -- -- O
113 the -- -- O
114 killing -- -- O
115 , -- -- O
116 a -- -- O
117 janitor -- -- O
118 at -- -- O
119 a -- -- O
120 school -- -- O
121 near -- -- O
122 Narathiwat's -- -- O
123 provincial -- -- O
124 capital -- -- O
125 was -- -- O
126 also -- -- O
127 shot -- -- O
128 dead -- -- O
129 on -- -- O
130 his -- -- O
131 way -- -- O
132 to -- -- O
133 work -- -- O
134 by -- -- O
135 two -- -- O
136 motorcycle -- -- O
137 gunmen -- -- O
138 . -- -- O

139 Police -- -- O
140 would -- -- O
141 not -- -- O
142 say -- -- O
143 whether -- -- O
144 Mongkol -- -- O
145 Saidaew's -- -- O
146 death -- -- O
147 was -- -- O
148 linked -- -- O
149 to -- -- O
150 the -- -- O
151 violence -- -- O
152 in -- -- O
153 the -- -- O
154 southern -- -- O
155 provinces -- -- O
156 , -- -- O
157 where -- -- O
158 six -- -- O
159 people -- -- O
160 have -- -- O
161 been -- -- O
162 shot -- -- O
163 dead -- -- O
164 and -- -- O
165 three -- -- O
166 security -- -- O
167 forces -- -- O
168 wounded -- -- O
169 since -- -- O
170 last -- -- O
171 weekend -- -- O
172 , -- -- O
173 but -- -- O
174 the -- -- O
175 attack -- -- O
176 fit -- -- O
177 a -- -- O
178 pattern -- -- O
179 of -- -- O
180 assaults -- -- O
181 committed -- -- O
182 by -- -- O
183 gunmen -- -- O
184 thought -- -- O
185 to -- -- O
186 be -- -- O
187 separatist -- -- O
188 militants -- -- O
189 . -- -- O

190 Violence -- -- O
191 by -- -- O
192 suspected -- -- O
193 Islamic -- -- O
194 separatists -- -- O
195 in -- -- O
196 the -- -- O
197 southern -- -- O
198 provinces -- -- O
199 has -- -- O
200 left -- -- O
201 more -- -- O
202 than -- -- O
203 200 -- -- O
204 people -- -- O
205 dead -- -- O
206 since -- -- O
207 January -- -- O
208 and -- -- O
209 traumatized -- -- O
210 the -- -- O
211 region -- -- O
212 . -- -- O

213 Defence -- -- O
214 Minister -- -- O
215 Chetta -- -- B-PER.Politician
216 Thanajaro -- -- I-PER.Politician
217 , -- -- O
218 who -- -- O
219 recently -- -- O
220 toured -- -- O
221 the -- -- O
222 southern -- -- O
223 provinces -- -- O
224 , -- -- O
225 said -- -- O
226 in -- -- O
227 the -- -- O
228 Thai -- -- O
229 press -- -- O
230 Wednesday -- -- O
231 that -- -- O
232 the -- -- O
233 daily -- -- O
234 killings -- -- O
235 were -- -- O
236 " -- -- O
237 unacceptable -- -- O
238 " -- -- O
239 and -- -- O
240 strong -- -- O
241 measures -- -- O
242 were -- -- O
243 needed -- -- O
244 to -- -- O
245 bring -- -- O
246 the -- -- O
247 crisis -- -- O
248 to -- -- O
249 an -- -- O
250 end -- -- O
251 . -- -- O

252 " -- -- O
253 We -- -- O
254 have -- -- O
255 to -- -- O
256 listen -- -- O
257 to -- -- O
258 him -- -- O
259 , -- -- O
260 as -- -- O
261 he -- -- O
262 is -- -- O
263 there -- -- O
264 and -- -- O
265 we -- -- O
266 have -- -- O
267 to -- -- O
268 respect -- -- O
269 a -- -- O
270 person -- -- O
271 who -- -- O
272 is -- -- O
273 on -- -- O
274 the -- -- O
275 ground -- -- O
276 , -- -- O
277 but -- -- O
278 solving -- -- O
279 these -- -- O
280 problems -- -- O
281 needs -- -- O
282 patience -- -- O
283 ," -- -- O
284 Deputy -- -- O
285 Prime -- -- O
286 Minister -- -- O
287 Chavalit -- -- B-PER.Politician
288 Yongchaiyudh -- -- I-PER.Politician
289 told -- -- O
290 reporters -- -- O
291 . -- -- O

292 " -- -- O
293 It -- -- O
294 will -- -- O
295 not -- -- O
296 take -- -- O
297 long -- -- O
298 if -- -- O
299 we -- -- O
300 increase -- -- O
301 force -- -- O
302 and -- -- O
303 use -- -- O
304 good -- -- O
305 and -- -- O
306 intensified -- -- O
307 measures -- -- O
308 ," -- -- O
309 he -- -- O
310 said -- -- O
311 . -- -- O

312 The -- -- O
313 deputy -- -- O
314 premier -- -- O
315 who -- -- O
316 is -- -- O
317 tasked -- -- O
318 with -- -- O
319 overseeing -- -- O
320 national -- -- O
321 security -- -- O
322 , -- -- O
323 also -- -- O
324 expressed -- -- O
325 his -- -- O
326 support -- -- O
327 for -- -- O
328 plans -- -- O
329 for -- -- O
330 teachers -- -- O
331 in -- -- O
332 public -- -- O
333 schools -- -- O
334 in -- -- O
335 the -- -- O
336 troubled -- -- O
337 south -- -- O
338 to -- -- O
339 carry -- -- O
340 handguns -- -- O
341 , -- -- O
342 a -- -- O
343 policy -- -- O
344 that -- -- O
345 has -- -- O
346 triggered -- -- O
347 controversy -- -- O
348 . -- -- O

349 " -- -- O
350 I -- -- O
351 think -- -- O
352 it -- -- O
353 is -- -- O
354 okay -- -- O
355 , -- -- O
356 if -- -- O
357 necessary -- -- O
358 . -- -- O

359 But -- -- O
360 they -- -- O
361 have -- -- O
362 to -- -- O
363 use -- -- O
364 the -- -- O
365 guns -- -- O
366 only -- -- O
367 to -- -- O
368 defend -- -- O
369 themselves -- -- O
370 and -- -- O
371 not -- -- O
372 to -- -- O
373 attack -- -- O
374 innocent -- -- O
375 people -- -- O
376 ," -- -- O
377 Chavalit -- -- B-PER.Politician
378 said -- -- O
379 . -- -- O

380 Thailand's -- -- O
381 south -- -- O
382 has -- -- O
383 endured -- -- O
384 decades -- -- O
385 of -- -- O
386 separatist -- -- O
387 violence -- -- O
388 . -- -- O

389 After -- -- O
390 a -- -- O
391 period -- -- O
392 of -- -- O
393 relative -- -- O
394 peace -- -- O
395 , -- -- O
396 trouble -- -- O
397 flared -- -- O
398 again -- -- O
399 in -- -- O
400 January -- -- O
401 with -- -- O
402 bombings -- -- O
403 and -- -- O
404 murders -- -- O
405 targeting -- -- O
406 officials -- -- O
407 , -- -- O
408 security -- -- O
409 forces -- -- O
410 and -- -- O
411 Buddhist -- -- O
412 monks -- -- O
413 . -- -- O

414 The -- -- O
415 violence -- -- O
416 reached -- -- O
417 a -- -- O
418 peak -- -- O
419 on -- -- O
420 April -- -- O
421 28 -- -- O
422 when -- -- O
423 108 -- -- O
424 suspected -- -- O
425 Muslim -- -- O
426 rebels -- -- O
427 were -- -- O
428 killed -- -- O
429 after -- -- O
430 launching -- -- O
431 raids -- -- O
432 on -- -- O
433 police -- -- O
434 posts -- -- O
435 and -- -- O
436 checkpoints -- -- O
437 . -- -- O


0 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
1 dismisses -- -- O
2 punishment -- -- O
3 for -- -- O
4 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
5 nuke -- -- O
6 facility -- -- O

7 PITTSBURGH -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
8 2009-09-25 -- -- O
9 18:23:02 -- -- O
10 UTC -- -- O

11 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
12 on -- -- O
13 Friday -- -- O
14 batted -- -- O
15 down -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 notion -- -- O
18 of -- -- O
19 punishing -- -- O
20 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
21 with -- -- O
22 additional -- -- O
23 sanctions -- -- O
24 for -- -- O
25 developing -- -- O
26 a -- -- O
27 secret -- -- O
28 nuclear -- -- O
29 facility -- -- O
30 , -- -- O
31 saying -- -- O
32 negotiations -- -- O
33 are -- -- O
34 a -- -- O
35 better -- -- O
36 way -- -- O
37 of -- -- O
38 dealing -- -- O
39 with -- -- O
40 Tehran -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
41 . -- -- O

42 Chinese -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
43 officials -- -- O
44 told -- -- O
45 reporters -- -- O
46 at -- -- O
47 the -- -- O
48 Group -- -- O
49 of -- -- O
50 20 -- -- O
51 economic -- -- O
52 summit -- -- O
53 that -- -- O
54 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
55 should -- -- O
56 cooperate -- -- O
57 with -- -- O
58 the -- -- O
59 U.N -- -- O
60 . -- -- O
61 nuclear -- -- O
62 watchdog -- -- O
63 agency -- -- O
64 as -- -- O
65 it -- -- O
66 investigates -- -- O
67 the -- -- O
68 facility -- -- O
69 . -- -- O

70 Asked -- -- O
71 if -- -- O
72 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
73 would -- -- O
74 support -- -- O
75 punishing -- -- O
76 measures -- -- O
77 against -- -- O
78 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
79 at -- -- O
80 the -- -- O
81 U.N -- -- O
82 . -- -- O
83 Security -- -- O
84 Council -- -- O
85 , -- -- O
86 Vice -- -- O
87 Foreign -- -- O
88 Minister -- -- O
89 He -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
90 Yafei -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
91 said -- -- O
92 , -- -- O
93 " -- -- O
94 Personally -- -- O
95 , -- -- O
96 I -- -- O
97 don't -- -- O
98 like -- -- O
99 the -- -- O
100 word -- -- O
101 punishment -- -- O
102 . -- -- O

103 " -- -- O
104 I -- -- O
105 think -- -- O
106 that -- -- O
107 all -- -- O
108 the -- -- O
109 issues -- -- O
110 can -- -- O
111 only -- -- O
112 be -- -- O
113 solved -- -- O
114 through -- -- O
115 dialogue -- -- O
116 and -- -- O
117 negotiation -- -- O
118 ." -- -- O

119 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
120 , -- -- O
121 a -- -- O
122 growing -- -- O
123 economic -- -- O
124 , -- -- O
125 military -- -- O
126 and -- -- O
127 diplomatic -- -- O
128 world -- -- O
129 power -- -- O
130 , -- -- O
131 is -- -- O
132 a -- -- O
133 veto-holding -- -- O
134 member -- -- O
135 of -- -- O
136 the -- -- O
137 Security -- -- B-ORG.Government.Council
138 Council -- -- I-ORG.Government.Council
139 . -- -- O

140 But -- -- O
141 Beijing -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
142 has -- -- O
143 deep -- -- O
144 trading -- -- O
145 ties -- -- O
146 with -- -- O
147 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
148 and -- -- O
149 has -- -- O
150 been -- -- O
151 reluctant -- -- O
152 to -- -- O
153 take -- -- O
154 a -- -- O
155 strong -- -- O
156 line -- -- O
157 on -- -- O
158 Iran's -- -- O
159 alleged -- -- O
160 nuclear -- -- O
161 aspirations -- -- O
162 . -- -- O

163 The -- -- O
164 leaders -- -- O
165 of -- -- O
166 the -- -- O
167 United -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
168 States -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
169 , -- -- O
170 France -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
171 and -- -- O
172 Britain -- -- B-LOC.Land
173 are -- -- O
174 demanding -- -- O
175 that -- -- O
176 Tehran -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
177 fully -- -- O
178 disclose -- -- O
179 its -- -- O
180 nuclear -- -- O
181 ambitions -- -- O
182 . -- -- O

183 The -- -- O
184 U.S -- -- O
185 . -- -- O
186 and -- -- O
187 others -- -- O
188 hope -- -- O
189 the -- -- O
190 disclosure -- -- O
191 of -- -- O
192 the -- -- O
193 previously -- -- O
194 secret -- -- O
195 Iranian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
196 nuclear -- -- O
197 facility -- -- O
198 will -- -- O
199 increase -- -- O
200 pressure -- -- O
201 on -- -- O
202 the -- -- O
203 global -- -- O
204 community -- -- O
205 to -- -- O
206 impose -- -- O
207 new -- -- O
208 sanctions -- -- O
209 on -- -- O
210 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
211 if -- -- O
212 it -- -- O
213 refuses -- -- O
214 to -- -- O
215 stop -- -- O
216 its -- -- O
217 nuclear -- -- O
218 program -- -- O
219 . -- -- O

220 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
221 and -- -- O
222 Russia -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
223 are -- -- O
224 seen -- -- O
225 as -- -- O
226 the -- -- O
227 key -- -- O
228 to -- -- O
229 meaningful -- -- O
230 sanctions -- -- O
231 . -- -- O

232 Senior -- -- O
233 U.S -- -- O
234 . -- -- O
235 officials -- -- O
236 told -- -- O
237 reporters -- -- O
238 in -- -- O
239 a -- -- O
240 briefing -- -- O
241 that -- -- O
242 the -- -- O
243 United -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
244 States -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
245 has -- -- O
246 been -- -- O
247 consulting -- -- O
248 with -- -- O
249 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
250 about -- -- O
251 the -- -- O
252 facility -- -- O
253 in -- -- O
254 the -- -- O
255 last -- -- O
256 two -- -- O
257 days -- -- O
258 . -- -- O

259 They -- -- O
260 spoke -- -- O
261 on -- -- O
262 condition -- -- O
263 of -- -- O
264 anonymity -- -- O
265 to -- -- O
266 let -- -- O
267 the -- -- O
268 statements -- -- O
269 from -- -- O
270 world -- -- O
271 leaders -- -- O
272 remain -- -- O
273 the -- -- O
274 focus -- -- O
275 . -- -- O

276 He -- -- O
277 , -- -- O
278 speaking -- -- O
279 through -- -- O
280 an -- -- O
281 interpreter -- -- O
282 , -- -- O
283 said -- -- O
284 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
285 is -- -- O
286 following -- -- O
287 the -- -- O
288 matter -- -- O
289 closely -- -- O
290 and -- -- O
291 hopes -- -- O
292 international -- -- O
293 meetings -- -- O
294 on -- -- O
295 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
296 next -- -- O
297 month -- -- O
298 will -- -- O
299 " -- -- O
300 produce -- -- O
301 positive -- -- O
302 results -- -- O
303 ." -- -- O

304 Chinese -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
305 foreign -- -- O
306 ministry -- -- O
307 spokesman -- -- O
308 Ma -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition.Spokesperson
309 Zhaoxu -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition.Spokesperson
310 earlier -- -- O
311 told -- -- O
312 reporters -- -- O
313 that -- -- O
314 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
315 wants -- -- O
316 Iran -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
317 to -- -- O
318 cooperate -- -- O
319 with -- -- O
320 the -- -- O
321 International -- -- B-ORG.International
322 Atomic -- -- I-ORG.International
323 Energy -- -- I-ORG.International
324 Agency -- -- I-ORG.International
325 . -- -- O

326 Iranian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
327 President -- -- O
328 Mahmoud -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
329 Ahmadinejad -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
330 said -- -- O
331 his -- -- O
332 country -- -- O
333 has -- -- O
334 complied -- -- O
335 with -- -- O
336 rules -- -- O
337 of -- -- O
338 the -- -- O
339 U.N -- -- O
340 . -- -- O
341 nuclear -- -- O
342 agency -- -- O
343 that -- -- O
344 require -- -- O
345 that -- -- O
346 it -- -- O
347 be -- -- O
348 informed -- -- O
349 of -- -- O
350 any -- -- O
351 new -- -- O
352 enrichment -- -- O
353 facility -- -- O
354 six -- -- O
355 months -- -- O
356 before -- -- O
357 it -- -- O
358 becomes -- -- O
359 operational -- -- O
360 . -- -- O


0 Philippines -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
1 says -- -- O
2 World -- -- B-ORG.International
3 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
4 shifted -- -- O
5 fund -- -- O
6 focus -- -- O

7 MANILA -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
8 , -- -- O
9 Philippines -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
10 2008-10-16 -- -- O
11 08:39:35 -- -- O
12 UTC -- -- O

13 The -- -- O
14 Philippine -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
15 trade -- -- O
16 secretary -- -- O
17 said -- -- O
18 discussions -- -- O
19 among -- -- O
20 Asian -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
21 finance -- -- O
22 officials -- -- O
23 on -- -- O
24 a -- -- O
25 regional -- -- O
26 bailout -- -- O
27 fund -- -- O
28 were -- -- O
29 only -- -- O
30 preliminary -- -- O
31 after -- -- O
32 the -- -- O
33 World -- -- B-ORG.International
34 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
35 on -- -- O
36 Thursday -- -- O
37 denied -- -- O
38 committing -- -- O
39 to -- -- O
40 any -- -- O
41 such -- -- O
42 initiative -- -- O
43 . -- -- O

44 Trade -- -- O
45 Secretary -- -- O
46 Peter -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
47 Favila -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
48 confronted -- -- O
49 the -- -- O
50 puzzled -- -- O
51 media -- -- O
52 as -- -- O
53 he -- -- O
54 tried -- -- O
55 to -- -- O
56 shield -- -- O
57 President -- -- O
58 Gloria -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
59 Macapagal -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
60 Arroyo -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
61 from -- -- O
62 potential -- -- O
63 embarrassment -- -- O
64 , -- -- O
65 a -- -- O
66 day -- -- O
67 after -- -- O
68 she -- -- O
69 announced -- -- O
70 that -- -- O
71 the -- -- O
72 World -- -- B-ORG.International
73 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
74 agreed -- -- O
75 to -- -- O
76 contribute -- -- O
77 US$10 -- -- O
78 billion -- -- O
79 to -- -- O
80 a -- -- O
81 new -- -- O
82 regional -- -- O
83 liquidity -- -- O
84 fund -- -- O
85 to -- -- O
86 help -- -- O
87 Asian -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
88 nations -- -- O
89 cope -- -- O
90 with -- -- O
91 the -- -- O
92 global -- -- O
93 financial -- -- O
94 crisis -- -- O
95 . -- -- O

96 Arroyo -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
97 claimed -- -- O
98 the -- -- O
99 agreement -- -- O
100 was -- -- O
101 reached -- -- O
102 in -- -- O
103 Washington -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
104 in -- -- O
105 meetings -- -- O
106 with -- -- O
107 finance -- -- O
108 officials -- -- O
109 from -- -- O
110 the -- -- O
111 10-member -- -- O
112 Association -- -- B-ORG.International
113 of -- -- I-ORG.International
114 Southeast -- -- I-ORG.International
115 Asian -- -- I-ORG.International
116 Nations -- -- I-ORG.International
117 and -- -- O
118 their -- -- O
119 partners -- -- O
120 from -- -- O
121 Japan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
122 , -- -- O
123 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
124 and -- -- O
125 South -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
126 Korea -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
127 and -- -- O
128 multilateral -- -- O
129 lending -- -- O
130 institutions -- -- O
131 . -- -- O

132 In -- -- O
133 a -- -- O
134 statement -- -- O
135 in -- -- O
136 Washington -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
137 , -- -- O
138 Jim -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
139 Adams -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
140 , -- -- O
141 the -- -- O
142 World -- -- O
143 Bank's -- -- O
144 vice -- -- O
145 president -- -- O
146 for -- -- O
147 East -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
148 Asia -- -- I-LOC.Position.Region
149 and -- -- O
150 the -- -- O
151 Pacific -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
152 , -- -- O
153 said -- -- O
154 the -- -- O
155 bank -- -- O
156 did -- -- O
157 not -- -- O
158 anticipate -- -- O
159 the -- -- O
160 establishment -- -- O
161 of -- -- O
162 such -- -- O
163 a -- -- O
164 fund -- -- O
165 and -- -- O
166 has -- -- O
167 not -- -- O
168 " -- -- O
169 discussed -- -- O
170 commitments -- -- O
171 of -- -- O
172 funds -- -- O
173 at -- -- O
174 the -- -- O
175 regional -- -- O
176 level -- -- O
177 ." -- -- O

178 " -- -- O
179 East -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
180 Asian -- -- I-LOC.Position.Region
181 economies -- -- O
182 continue -- -- O
183 to -- -- O
184 perform -- -- O
185 strongly -- -- O
186 and -- -- O
187 have -- -- O
188 made -- -- O
189 significant -- -- O
190 changes -- -- O
191 since -- -- O
192 the -- -- O
193 1997 -- -- O
194 Asian -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
195 financial -- -- O
196 crisis -- -- O
197 making -- -- O
198 them -- -- O
199 more -- -- O
200 resilient -- -- O
201 to -- -- O
202 the -- -- O
203 impacts -- -- O
204 of -- -- O
205 the -- -- O
206 current -- -- O
207 global -- -- O
208 turbulence -- -- O
209 ," -- -- O
210 he -- -- O
211 said -- -- O
212 . -- -- O

213 " -- -- O
214 Like -- -- O
215 all -- -- O
216 countries -- -- O
217 , -- -- O
218 Asian -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
219 economies -- -- O
220 must -- -- O
221 be -- -- O
222 prepared -- -- O
223 to -- -- O
224 deal -- -- O
225 with -- -- O
226 any -- -- O
227 effects -- -- O
228 of -- -- O
229 the -- -- O
230 turmoil -- -- O
231 ," -- -- O
232 he -- -- O
233 said -- -- O
234 . -- -- O

235 Adams -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
236 confirmed -- -- O
237 that -- -- O
238 numerous -- -- O
239 discussions -- -- O
240 with -- -- O
241 individual -- -- O
242 governments -- -- O
243 were -- -- O
244 held -- -- O
245 during -- -- O
246 the -- -- O
247 recent -- -- O
248 Annual -- -- O
249 Meetings -- -- O
250 of -- -- O
251 the -- -- O
252 World -- -- B-ORG.International
253 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
254 and -- -- O
255 the -- -- O
256 International -- -- B-ORG.International
257 Monetary -- -- I-ORG.International
258 Fund -- -- I-ORG.International
259 , -- -- O
260 and -- -- O
261 the -- -- O
262 institutions -- -- O
263 " -- -- O
264 stand -- -- O
265 ready -- -- O
266 to -- -- O
267 support -- -- O
268 all -- -- O
269 of -- -- O
270 our -- -- O
271 member -- -- O
272 countries -- -- O
273 across -- -- O
274 East -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
275 Asia -- -- I-LOC.Position.Region
276 to -- -- O
277 deal -- -- O
278 with -- -- O
279 the -- -- O
280 challenges -- -- O
281 arising -- -- O
282 from -- -- O
283 the -- -- O
284 financial -- -- O
285 crisis -- -- O
286 ." -- -- O

287 Favila -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
288 insisted -- -- O
289 the -- -- O
290 US$10 -- -- O
291 billion -- -- O
292 figure -- -- O
293 for -- -- O
294 an -- -- O
295 ASEAN -- -- B-ORG.International
296 fund -- -- O
297 was -- -- O
298 discussed -- -- O
299 in -- -- O
300 a -- -- O
301 meeting -- -- O
302 attended -- -- O
303 by -- -- O
304 the -- -- O
305 World -- -- B-ORG.International
306 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
307 , -- -- O
308 IMF -- -- B-ORG.International
309 , -- -- O
310 Asian -- -- B-ORG.International
311 Development -- -- I-ORG.International
312 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
313 and -- -- O
314 ASEAN -- -- B-ORG.International
315 finance -- -- O
316 ministers -- -- O
317 . -- -- O

318 " -- -- O
319 It -- -- O
320 was -- -- O
321 preliminary -- -- O
322 in -- -- O
323 character -- -- O
324 ," -- -- O
325 he -- -- O
326 said -- -- O
327 . -- -- O

328 But -- -- O
329 in -- -- O
330 a -- -- O
331 second -- -- O
332 meeting -- -- O
333 , -- -- O
334 Favila -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
335 quoted -- -- O
336 Adams -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
337 as -- -- O
338 saying -- -- O
339 the -- -- O
340 bank -- -- O
341 was -- -- O
342 looking -- -- O
343 at -- -- O
344 providing -- -- O
345 funds -- -- O
346 on -- -- O
347 a -- -- O
348 global -- -- O
349 scale -- -- O
350 . -- -- O

351 " -- -- O
352 It -- -- O
353 was -- -- O
354 in -- -- O
355 the -- -- O
356 second -- -- O
357 meeting -- -- O
358 that -- -- O
359 Jim -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
360 Adams -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
361 did -- -- O
362 say -- -- O
363 they -- -- O
364 are -- -- O
365 now -- -- O
366 looking -- -- O
367 at -- -- O
368 a -- -- O
369 bilateral -- -- O
370 approach -- -- O
371 , -- -- O
372 not -- -- O
373 regional -- -- O
374 , -- -- O
375 not -- -- O
376 as -- -- O
377 a -- -- O
378 bloc -- -- O
379 ," -- -- O
380 he -- -- O
381 said -- -- O
382 . -- -- O

383 " -- -- O
384 The -- -- O
385 commitment -- -- O
386 of -- -- O
387 the -- -- O
388 World -- -- B-ORG.International
389 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
390 is -- -- O
391 still -- -- O
392 there -- -- O
393 ." -- -- O

394 Favila -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
395 refused -- -- O
396 to -- -- O
397 call -- -- O
398 it -- -- O
399 a -- -- O
400 case -- -- O
401 of -- -- O
402 miscommunication -- -- O
403 between -- -- O
404 Arroyo -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
405 and -- -- O
406 Finance -- -- O
407 Secretary -- -- O
408 Margarito -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
409 Teves -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
410 , -- -- O
411 who -- -- O
412 was -- -- O
413 in -- -- O
414 Washington -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
415 attending -- -- O
416 the -- -- O
417 meetings -- -- O
418 , -- -- O
419 or -- -- O
420 concede -- -- O
421 that -- -- O
422 the -- -- O
423 president -- -- O
424 made -- -- O
425 a -- -- O
426 premature -- -- O
427 statement -- -- O
428 . -- -- O

429 Associated -- -- O
430 Press -- -- O
431 writers -- -- O
432 Teresa -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition.Journalist
433 Cerojano -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition.Journalist
434 and -- -- O
435 Oliver -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition.Journalist
436 Teves -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition.Journalist
437 contributed -- -- O
438 to -- -- O
439 this -- -- O
440 report -- -- O
441 . -- -- O

442 ------ -- -- O

443 On -- -- O
444 the -- -- O
445 Net -- -- O
446 : -- -- O

447 World -- -- B-ORG.International
448 Bank -- -- I-ORG.International
449 : -- -- O
450 http://www.worldbank.org -- -- O


0 Rangers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
1 beats -- -- O
2 Hearts -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
3 to -- -- O
4 maintain -- -- O
5 title -- -- O
6 charge -- -- O

7 GLASGOW -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
8 , -- -- O
9 Scotland -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
10 2010-03-27 -- -- O
11 18:00:48 -- -- O
12 UTC -- -- O

13 Rangers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
14 coasted -- -- O
15 to -- -- O
16 a -- -- O
17 4-1 -- -- O
18 victory -- -- O
19 at -- -- O
20 Hearts -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
21 on -- -- O
22 Saturday -- -- O
23 to -- -- O
24 stay -- -- O
25 on -- -- O
26 target -- -- O
27 to -- -- O
28 defend -- -- O
29 its -- -- O
30 Scottish -- -- B-ORG.Commercialorganization
31 Premier -- -- I-ORG.Commercialorganization
32 League -- -- I-ORG.Commercialorganization
33 title -- -- O
34 . -- -- O

35 Rangers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
36 remains -- -- O
37 10 -- -- O
38 points -- -- O
39 ahead -- -- O
40 of -- -- O
41 Celtic -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
42 , -- -- O
43 whose -- -- O
44 first -- -- O
45 game -- -- O
46 under -- -- O
47 interim -- -- O
48 manager -- -- O
49 Neil -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
50 Lennon -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
51 ended -- -- O
52 in -- -- O
53 a -- -- O
54 3-1 -- -- O
55 victory -- -- O
56 over -- -- O
57 Kilmarnock -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
58 . -- -- O

59 Celtic -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
60 has -- -- O
61 played -- -- O
62 two -- -- O
63 games -- -- O
64 more -- -- O
65 than -- -- O
66 its -- -- O
67 Glasgow -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
68 rival -- -- O
69 . -- -- O

70 Danny -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
71 Wilson -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
72 scored -- -- O
73 his -- -- O
74 first -- -- O
75 goal -- -- O
76 for -- -- O
77 Rangers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
78 after -- -- O
79 just -- -- O
80 four -- -- O
81 minutes -- -- O
82 . -- -- O

83 Suso -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
84 Santana -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
85 leveled -- -- O
86 for -- -- O
87 Hearts -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
88 , -- -- O
89 but -- -- O
90 Kenny -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
91 Miller -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
92 put -- -- O
93 Rangers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
94 back -- -- O
95 in -- -- O
96 front -- -- O
97 on -- -- O
98 31 -- -- O
99 minutes -- -- O
100 before -- -- O
101 Steven -- -- O
102 Naismith's -- -- O
103 second-half -- -- O
104 double -- -- O
105 put -- -- O
106 the -- -- O
107 visitors -- -- O
108 in -- -- O
109 control -- -- O
110 . -- -- O

111 Robbie -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
112 Keane -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
113 scored -- -- O
114 twice -- -- O
115 for -- -- O
116 Celtic -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
117 to -- -- O
118 take -- -- O
119 his -- -- O
120 tally -- -- O
121 to -- -- O
122 11 -- -- O
123 goals -- -- O
124 in -- -- O
125 11 -- -- O
126 games -- -- O
127 since -- -- O
128 arriving -- -- O
129 on -- -- O
130 loan -- -- O
131 from -- -- O
132 Tottenham -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
133 in -- -- O
134 the -- -- O
135 January -- -- O
136 transfer -- -- O
137 window -- -- O
138 . -- -- O

139 Scott -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
140 Brown -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
141 added -- -- O
142 Celtic's -- -- O
143 third -- -- O
144 before -- -- O
145 Kilmarnock -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
146 captain -- -- O
147 Craig -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
148 Bryson -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
149 scored -- -- O
150 a -- -- O
151 consolation -- -- O
152 . -- -- O


0 THIS -- -- O
1 FLU -- -- O
2 SEASON -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 A -- -- O
5 JUMP -- -- O
6 IN -- -- O
7 DOCTOR -- -- O
8 VISITS -- -- O
9 AND -- -- O
10 DEATHS -- -- O

11 The -- -- O
12 current -- -- O
13 flu -- -- O
14 season -- -- O
15 has -- -- O
16 been -- -- O
17 more -- -- O
18 severe -- -- O
19 than -- -- O
20 the -- -- O
21 last -- -- O
22 three -- -- O
23 , -- -- O
24 with -- -- O
25 more -- -- O
26 doctor -- -- O
27 visits -- -- O
28 and -- -- O
29 more -- -- O
30 deaths -- -- O
31 from -- -- O
32 flu -- -- O
33 and -- -- O
34 pneumonia -- -- O
35 , -- -- O
36 federal -- -- O
37 health -- -- O
38 officials -- -- O
39 are -- -- O
40 reporting -- -- O
41 . -- -- O

42 The -- -- O
43 season -- -- O
44 peaked -- -- O
45 in -- -- O
46 February -- -- O
47 , -- -- O
48 when -- -- O
49 flulike -- -- O
50 illnesses -- -- O
51 accounted -- -- O
52 for -- -- O
53 5.9 -- -- O
54 percent -- -- O
55 of -- -- O
56 doctor -- -- O
57 visits -- -- O
58 . -- -- O

59 Overall -- -- O
60 , -- -- O
61 doctor -- -- O
62 visits -- -- O
63 for -- -- O
64 these -- -- O
65 illnesses -- -- O
66 were -- -- O
67 higher -- -- O
68 than -- -- O
69 normal -- -- O
70 for -- -- O
71 13 -- -- O
72 consecutive -- -- O
73 weeks -- -- O
74 . -- -- O

75 The -- -- O
76 death -- -- O
77 rate -- -- O
78 related -- -- O
79 to -- -- O
80 flu -- -- O
81 and -- -- O
82 pneumonia -- -- O
83 was -- -- O
84 also -- -- O
85 higher -- -- O
86 than -- -- O
87 usual -- -- O
88 for -- -- O
89 13 -- -- O
90 consecutive -- -- O
91 weeks -- -- O
92 ; -- -- O
93 at -- -- O
94 the -- -- O
95 worst -- -- O
96 point -- -- O
97 , -- -- O
98 in -- -- O
99 March -- -- O
100 , -- -- O
101 the -- -- O
102 illnesses -- -- O
103 were -- -- O
104 listed -- -- O
105 as -- -- O
106 underlying -- -- O
107 or -- -- O
108 contributing -- -- O
109 causes -- -- O
110 of -- -- O
111 death -- -- O
112 in -- -- O
113 9.1 -- -- O
114 percent -- -- O
115 of -- -- O
116 deaths -- -- O
117 . -- -- O

118 Any -- -- O
119 rate -- -- O
120 over -- -- O
121 6.9 -- -- O
122 percent -- -- O
123 is -- -- O
124 considered -- -- O
125 unusually -- -- O
126 high -- -- O
127 . -- -- O

128 The -- -- O
129 deaths -- -- O
130 included -- -- O
131 65 -- -- O
132 children -- -- O
133 under -- -- O
134 18 -- -- O
135 . -- -- O

136 The -- -- O
137 youngest -- -- O
138 was -- -- O
139 a -- -- O
140 month -- -- O
141 old -- -- O
142 , -- -- O
143 and -- -- O
144 the -- -- O
145 median -- -- O
146 age -- -- O
147 was -- -- O
148 4.5 -- -- O
149 years -- -- O
150 . -- -- O

151 In -- -- O
152 each -- -- O
153 of -- -- O
154 the -- -- O
155 three -- -- O
156 previous -- -- O
157 flu -- -- O
158 seasons -- -- O
159 , -- -- O
160 46 -- -- O
161 to -- -- O
162 74 -- -- O
163 children -- -- O
164 died -- -- O
165 . -- -- O

182 The -- -- O
183 main -- -- O
184 reason -- -- O
185 for -- -- O
186 the -- -- O
187 increased -- -- O
188 severity -- -- O
189 this -- -- O
190 season -- -- O
191 is -- -- O
192 that -- -- O
193 a -- -- O
194 more -- -- O
195 virulent -- -- O
196 type -- -- O
197 of -- -- O
198 virus -- -- O
199 , -- -- O
200 called -- -- O
201 A(H3N2 -- -- O
202 ), -- -- O
203 has -- -- O
204 predominated -- -- O
205 , -- -- O
206 said -- -- O
207 Dr -- -- O
208 . -- -- O

209 Dan -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
210 Jernigan -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
211 , -- -- O
212 deputy -- -- O
213 director -- -- O
214 of -- -- O
215 the -- -- O
216 influenza -- -- O
217 division -- -- O
218 at -- -- O
219 the -- -- O
220 disease -- -- O
221 centers -- -- O
222 . -- -- O

223 There -- -- O
224 are -- -- O
225 many -- -- O
226 A(H3N2 -- -- O
227 ) -- -- O
228 variants -- -- O
229 , -- -- O
230 and -- -- O
231 this -- -- O
232 particular -- -- O
233 one -- -- O
234 was -- -- O
235 first -- -- O
236 identified -- -- O
237 in -- -- O
238 Brisbane -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
239 , -- -- O
240 Australia -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
241 , -- -- O
242 in -- -- O
243 2007 -- -- O
244 . -- -- O

245 The -- -- O
246 virus -- -- O
247 caught -- -- O
248 vaccine -- -- O
249 makers -- -- O
250 off -- -- O
251 guard -- -- O
252 . -- -- O

253 Though -- -- O
254 the -- -- O
255 current -- -- O
256 vaccine -- -- O
257 does -- -- O
258 contain -- -- O
259 an -- -- O
260 A(H3N2 -- -- O
261 ) -- -- O
262 strain -- -- O
263 related -- -- O
264 to -- -- O
265 the -- -- O
266 Brisbane -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
267 variant -- -- O
268 , -- -- O
269 it -- -- O
270 is -- -- O
271 not -- -- O
272 exactly -- -- O
273 the -- -- O
274 same -- -- O
275 , -- -- O
276 making -- -- O
277 the -- -- O
278 vaccine -- -- O
279 less -- -- O
280 effective -- -- O
281 than -- -- O
282 it -- -- O
283 might -- -- O
284 have -- -- O
285 been -- -- O
286 . -- -- O

287 A -- -- O
288 study -- -- O
289 found -- -- O
290 that -- -- O
291 the -- -- O
292 vaccine -- -- O
293 reduced -- -- O
294 people's -- -- O
295 risk -- -- O
296 of -- -- O
297 contracting -- -- O
298 any -- -- O
299 type -- -- O
300 of -- -- O
301 influenza -- -- O
302 A -- -- O
303 by -- -- O
304 58 -- -- O
305 percent -- -- O
306 . -- -- O

307 But -- -- O
308 when -- -- O
309 vaccine -- -- O
310 strains -- -- O
311 are -- -- O
312 well -- -- O
313 matched -- -- O
314 to -- -- O
315 viruses -- -- O
316 , -- -- O
317 they -- -- O
318 can -- -- O
319 cut -- -- O
320 the -- -- O
321 risk -- -- O
322 by -- -- O
323 70 -- -- O
324 percent -- -- O
325 to -- -- O
326 90 -- -- O
327 percent -- -- O
328 in -- -- O
329 healthy -- -- O
330 adults -- -- O
331 . -- -- O

332 Generally -- -- O
333 , -- -- O
334 the -- -- O
335 vaccines -- -- O
336 do -- -- O
337 not -- -- O
338 work -- -- O
339 as -- -- O
340 well -- -- O
341 in -- -- O
342 the -- -- O
343 elderly -- -- O
344 or -- -- O
345 in -- -- O
346 small -- -- O
347 children -- -- O
348 . -- -- O

349 Normally -- -- O
350 , -- -- O
351 if -- -- O
352 100 -- -- O
353 people -- -- O
354 who -- -- O
355 are -- -- O
356 not -- -- O
357 vaccinated -- -- O
358 are -- -- O
359 exposed -- -- O
360 to -- -- O
361 the -- -- O
362 flu -- -- O
363 , -- -- O
364 10 -- -- O
365 will -- -- O
366 get -- -- O
367 sick -- -- O
368 . -- -- O

369 But -- -- O
370 if -- -- O
371 100 -- -- O
372 who -- -- O
373 are -- -- O
374 vaccinated -- -- O
375 are -- -- O
376 exposed -- -- O
377 , -- -- O
378 and -- -- O
379 the -- -- O
380 vaccine -- -- O
381 is -- -- O
382 70 -- -- O
383 percent -- -- O
384 effective -- -- O
385 , -- -- O
386 then -- -- O
387 only -- -- O
388 three -- -- O
389 will -- -- O
390 get -- -- O
391 sick -- -- O
392 . -- -- O

393 Flu -- -- O
394 vaccines -- -- O
395 generally -- -- O
396 contain -- -- O
397 three -- -- O
398 types -- -- O
399 of -- -- O
400 virus -- -- O
401 , -- -- O
402 and -- -- O
403 this -- -- O
404 year's -- -- O
405 vaccine -- -- O
406 has -- -- O
407 a -- -- O
408 second -- -- O
409 mismatch -- -- O
410 as -- -- O
411 well -- -- O
412 : -- -- O
413 it -- -- O
414 is -- -- O
415 completely -- -- O
416 inactive -- -- O
417 against -- -- O
418 the -- -- O
419 kind -- -- O
420 of -- -- O
421 influenza -- -- O
422 B -- -- O
423 virus -- -- O
424 that -- -- O
425 has -- -- O
426 been -- -- O
427 circulating -- -- O
428 this -- -- O
429 year -- -- O
430 . -- -- O

431 Jernigan -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
432 said -- -- O
433 mismatches -- -- O
434 could -- -- O
435 occur -- -- O
436 because -- -- O
437 vaccine -- -- O
438 makers -- -- O
439 must -- -- O
440 decide -- -- O
441 which -- -- O
442 strains -- -- O
443 to -- -- O
444 include -- -- O
445 by -- -- O
446 February -- -- O
447 , -- -- O
448 many -- -- O
449 months -- -- O
450 before -- -- O
451 the -- -- O
452 flu -- -- O
453 season -- -- O
454 begins -- -- O
455 , -- -- O
456 so -- -- O
457 that -- -- O
458 they -- -- O
459 can -- -- O
460 make -- -- O
461 the -- -- O
462 vaccine -- -- O
463 in -- -- O
464 time -- -- O
465 for -- -- O
466 autumn -- -- O
467 . -- -- O

468 Sometimes -- -- O
469 , -- -- O
470 he -- -- O
471 said -- -- O
472 , -- -- O
473 " -- -- O
474 a -- -- O
475 virus -- -- O
476 will -- -- O
477 emerge -- -- O
478 that -- -- O
479 was -- -- O
480 not -- -- O
481 even -- -- O
482 available -- -- O
483 at -- -- O
484 the -- -- O
485 time -- -- O
486 the -- -- O
487 decision -- -- O
488 had -- -- O
489 to -- -- O
490 be -- -- O
491 made -- -- O
492 ." -- -- O

493 The -- -- O
494 vaccine -- -- O
495 for -- -- O
496 the -- -- O
497 next -- -- O
498 flu -- -- O
499 season -- -- O
500 has -- -- O
501 been -- -- O
502 formulated -- -- O
503 ; -- -- O
504 it -- -- O
505 will -- -- O
506 contain -- -- O
507 three -- -- O
508 completely -- -- O
509 different -- -- O
510 strains -- -- O
511 from -- -- O
512 the -- -- O
513 ones -- -- O
514 used -- -- O
515 this -- -- O
516 year -- -- O
517 . -- -- O

518 Articles -- -- O
519 published -- -- O
520 Thursday -- -- O
521 in -- -- O
522 two -- -- O
523 scientific -- -- O
524 journals -- -- O
525 , -- -- O
526 Science -- -- O
527 and -- -- O
528 Nature -- -- O
529 , -- -- O
530 discussed -- -- O
531 the -- -- O
532 evolution -- -- O
533 and -- -- O
534 spread -- -- O
535 of -- -- O
536 influenza -- -- O
537 A -- -- O
538 viruses -- -- O
539 . -- -- O

540 Researchers -- -- O
541 have -- -- O
542 long -- -- O
543 believed -- -- O
544 that -- -- O
545 new -- -- O
546 flu -- -- O
547 viruses -- -- O
548 originated -- -- O
549 each -- -- O
550 year -- -- O
551 in -- -- O
552 Asia -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
553 , -- -- O
554 and -- -- O
555 the -- -- O
556 Science -- -- O
557 article -- -- O
558 provided -- -- O
559 evidence -- -- O
560 that -- -- O
561 the -- -- O
562 theory -- -- O
563 was -- -- O
564 correct -- -- O
565 . -- -- O

566 Its -- -- O
567 authors -- -- O
568 analyzed -- -- O
569 13,000 -- -- O
570 flu -- -- O
571 virus -- -- O
572 samples -- -- O
573 from -- -- O
574 around -- -- O
575 the -- -- O
576 world -- -- O
577 and -- -- O
578 traced -- -- O
579 them -- -- O
580 to -- -- O
581 East -- -- O
582 and -- -- O
583 Southeast -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
584 Asia -- -- I-LOC.Position.Region
585 . -- -- O

586 Many -- -- O
587 scientists -- -- O
588 had -- -- O
589 believed -- -- O
590 southern -- -- O
591 China -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
592 was -- -- O
593 the -- -- O
594 main -- -- O
595 source -- -- O
596 of -- -- O
597 flu -- -- O
598 viruses -- -- O
599 , -- -- O
600 but -- -- O
601 the -- -- O
602 new -- -- O
603 study -- -- O
604 suggests -- -- O
605 they -- -- O
606 come -- -- O
607 from -- -- O
608 other -- -- O
609 parts -- -- O
610 of -- -- O
611 Asia -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
612 as -- -- O
613 well -- -- O
614 . -- -- O

615 The -- -- O
616 viruses -- -- O
617 reach -- -- O
618 Europe -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
619 and -- -- O
620 North -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
621 America -- -- I-LOC.Land.Continent
622 six -- -- O
623 to -- -- O
624 nine -- -- O
625 months -- -- O
626 later -- -- O
627 and -- -- O
628 then -- -- O
629 after -- -- O
630 a -- -- O
631 few -- -- O
632 more -- -- O
633 months -- -- O
634 arrive -- -- O
635 in -- -- O
636 South -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
637 America -- -- I-LOC.Land.Continent
638 , -- -- O
639 where -- -- O
640 they -- -- O
641 die -- -- O
642 out -- -- O
643 . -- -- O

644 The -- -- O
645 disease -- -- O
646 centers -- -- O
647 estimates -- -- O
648 that -- -- O
649 every -- -- O
650 year -- -- O
651 5 -- -- O
652 percent -- -- O
653 to -- -- O
654 20 -- -- O
655 percent -- -- O
656 of -- -- O
657 the -- -- O
658 U.S -- -- O
659 . -- -- O
660 population -- -- O
661 gets -- -- O
662 the -- -- O
663 flu -- -- O
664 , -- -- O
665 and -- -- O
666 that -- -- O
667 more -- -- O
668 than -- -- O
669 200,000 -- -- O
670 people -- -- O
671 are -- -- O
672 hospitalized -- -- O
673 because -- -- O
674 of -- -- O
675 flu -- -- O
676 complications -- -- O
677 and -- -- O
678 about -- -- O
679 36,000 -- -- O
680 die -- -- O
681 . -- -- O


0 China's -- -- O
1 Wang -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
2 Scores -- -- O
3 Career-High -- -- O
4 as -- -- O
5 Mavericks -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
6 Upset -- -- O
7 Nets -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team

8 WASHINGTON -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
9 , -- -- O
10 February -- -- O
11 6 -- -- O
12 ( -- -- O
13 Xinhua -- -- O
14 ) -- -- O

15 China's -- -- O
16 Wang -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
17 Zhizhi -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
18 had -- -- O
19 a -- -- O
20 career-high -- -- O
21 15 -- -- O
22 points -- -- O
23 as -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 Dallas -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
26 Mavericks -- -- I-ORG.Association.Team
27 beat -- -- O
28 the -- -- O
29 New -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
30 Jersey -- -- I-ORG.Association.Team
31 Nets -- -- I-ORG.Association.Team
32 112-100 -- -- O
33 on -- -- O
34 Wednesday -- -- O
35 night -- -- O
36 . -- -- O

37 The -- -- O
38 win -- -- O
39 gave -- -- O
40 Dallas -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
41 a -- -- O
42 team -- -- O
43 record-tying -- -- O
44 seventh -- -- O
45 consecutive -- -- O
46 road -- -- O
47 win -- -- O
48 and -- -- O
49 ended -- -- O
50 the -- -- O
51 Nets -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
52 ' -- -- O
53 eight-game -- -- O
54 home -- -- O
55 winning -- -- O
56 streak -- -- O
57 . -- -- O

58 Dirk -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
59 Nowitzki -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
60 had -- -- O
61 22 -- -- O
62 points -- -- O
63 , -- -- O
64 Tim -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
65 Hardaway -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
66 scored -- -- O
67 11 -- -- O
68 , -- -- O
69 and -- -- O
70 Steve -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
71 Nash -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
72 added -- -- O
73 18 -- -- O
74 points -- -- O
75 and -- -- O
76 12 -- -- O
77 assists -- -- O
78 for -- -- O
79 Dallas -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
80 , -- -- O
81 while -- -- O
82 Kenyon -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
83 Martin -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
84 had -- -- O
85 26 -- -- O
86 points -- -- O
87 , -- -- O
88 Keith -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
89 Van -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
90 Horn -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
91 added -- -- O
92 21 -- -- O
93 , -- -- O
94 and -- -- O
95 Jason -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
96 Kidd -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
97 had -- -- O
98 14 -- -- O
99 points -- -- O
100 and -- -- O
101 12 -- -- O
102 assists -- -- O
103 for -- -- O
104 the -- -- O
105 Nets -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
106 . -- -- O

107 In -- -- O
108 Boston -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
109 , -- -- O
110 Peja -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
111 Stojakovic -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
112 scored -- -- O
113 24 -- -- O
114 points -- -- O
115 and -- -- O
116 Vlade -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
117 Divac -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
118 had -- -- O

119 his -- -- O
120 seventh -- -- O
121 career -- -- O
122 triple-double -- -- O
123 to -- -- O
124 lead -- -- O
125 Sacramento -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
126 past -- -- O
127 Boston -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
128 102-85 -- -- O
129 . -- -- O

130 Divac -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
131 had -- -- O
132 15 -- -- O
133 points -- -- O
134 , -- -- O
135 14 -- -- O
136 rebounds -- -- O
137 and -- -- O
138 10 -- -- O
139 assists -- -- O
140 for -- -- O
141 the -- -- O
142 Kings -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
143 , -- -- O
144 who -- -- O
145 entered -- -- O
146 the -- -- O
147 All-Star -- -- O
148 break -- -- O
149 with -- -- O
150 an -- -- O
151 NBA-best -- -- O
152 record -- -- O
153 of -- -- O
154 37-11 -- -- O
155 . -- -- O

156 Antoine -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
157 Walker -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
158 scored -- -- O
159 26 -- -- O
160 points -- -- O
161 for -- -- O
162 the -- -- O
163 Celtics -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
164 , -- -- O
165 who -- -- O
166 lost -- -- O
167 for -- -- O
168 the -- -- O
169 fourth -- -- O
170 time -- -- O
171 in -- -- O
172 six -- -- O
173 games -- -- O
174 and -- -- O
175 closed -- -- O
176 out -- -- O
177 their -- -- O
178 first -- -- O
179 half -- -- O
180 with -- -- O
181 a -- -- O
182 record -- -- O
183 of -- -- O
184 28-21 -- -- O
185 . -- -- O

186 In -- -- O
187 Cleveland -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
188 , -- -- O
189 Andre -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
190 Miller -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
191 scored -- -- O
192 31 -- -- O
193 points -- -- O
194 , -- -- O
195 and -- -- O
196 Lamond -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
197 Murray -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
198 scored -- -- O
199 the -- -- O
200 go-ahead -- -- O
201 basket -- -- O
202 with -- -- O
203 21 -- -- O
204 seconds -- -- O
205 remaining -- -- O
206 and -- -- O
207 blocked -- -- O
208 a -- -- O

209 shot -- -- O
210 in -- -- O
211 the -- -- O
212 last -- -- O
213 9 -- -- O
214 seconds -- -- O
215 as -- -- O
216 Cleveland -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
217 snapped -- -- O
218 a -- -- O
219 three-game -- -- O
220 losing -- -- O
221 streak -- -- O
222 with -- -- O
223 a -- -- O
224 111-109 -- -- O
225 win -- -- O
226 over -- -- O
227 Houston -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
228 . -- -- O

229 Miller -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
230 finished -- -- O
231 with -- -- O
232 13 -- -- O
233 assists -- -- O
234 , -- -- O
235 and -- -- O
236 Zydrunas -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
237 Ilgauskas -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
238 scored -- -- O
239 all -- -- O
240 12 -- -- O
241 of -- -- O
242 his -- -- O
243 points -- -- O
244 in -- -- O
245 the -- -- O
246 fourth -- -- O
247 quarter -- -- O
248 for -- -- O
249 the -- -- O
250 Cavaliers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
251 . -- -- O

252 Cuttino -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
253 Mobley -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
254 scored -- -- O
255 29 -- -- O
256 points -- -- O
257 , -- -- O
258 and -- -- O
259 Francis -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
260 added -- -- O
261 25 -- -- O
262 for -- -- O
263 Houston -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
264 . -- -- O

265 In -- -- O
266 Minneapolis -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
267 , -- -- O
268 Wally -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
269 Szczerbiak -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
270 snapped -- -- O
271 out -- -- O
272 of -- -- O
273 his -- -- O
274 scoring -- -- O
275 slump -- -- O
276 with -- -- O
277 30 -- -- O
278 points -- -- O
279 , -- -- O
280 six -- -- O
281 rebounds -- -- O
282 and -- -- O
283 five -- -- O
284 assists -- -- O
285 as -- -- O
286 Minnesota -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
287 beat -- -- O
288 Portland -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
289 113-103 -- -- O
290 for -- -- O
291 its -- -- O
292 third -- -- O
293 win -- -- O
294 in -- -- O
295 nine -- -- O
296 games -- -- O
297 . -- -- O

298 Szczerbiak -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
299 shot -- -- O
300 11-for-16 -- -- O
301 from -- -- O
302 the -- -- O
303 floor -- -- O
304 and -- -- O
305 5-for-5 -- -- O
306 from -- -- O
307 the -- -- O
308 foul -- -- O
309 line -- -- O
310 . -- -- O

311 Joe -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
312 Smith -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
313 had -- -- O
314 21 -- -- O
315 points -- -- O
316 , -- -- O
317 while -- -- O
318 Gary -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
319 Trent -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
320 added -- -- O
321 14 -- -- O
322 in -- -- O
323 a -- -- O
324 reserve -- -- O

325 role -- -- O
326 for -- -- O
327 Minnesota -- -- B-GPE.Provincestate.Provincestate
328 , -- -- O
329 which -- -- O
330 was -- -- O
331 coming -- -- O
332 off -- -- O
333 a -- -- O
334 30-point -- -- O
335 loss -- -- O
336 to -- -- O
337 San -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
338 Antonio -- -- I-ORG.Association.Team
339 on -- -- O
340 Monday -- -- O
341 . -- -- O

342 Bonzi -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
343 Wells -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
344 scored -- -- O
345 a -- -- O
346 career-high -- -- O
347 35 -- -- O
348 points -- -- O
349 for -- -- O
350 Portland -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
351 , -- -- O
352 which -- -- O
353 lost -- -- O
354 for -- -- O
355 the -- -- O
356 fifth -- -- O
357 time -- -- O
358 in -- -- O
359 17 -- -- O
360 games -- -- O
361 . -- -- O

362 In -- -- O
363 Seattle -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
364 , -- -- O
365 Brent -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
366 Barry -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
367 scored -- -- O
368 21 -- -- O
369 points -- -- O
370 , -- -- O
371 and -- -- O
372 Vin -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
373 Baker -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
374 added -- -- O
375 17 -- -- O
376 points -- -- O
377 and -- -- O
378 nine -- -- O
379 rebounds -- -- O
380 as -- -- O
381 Seattle -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
382 snapped -- -- O
383 a -- -- O
384 three-game -- -- O
385 home -- -- O
386 losing -- -- O
387 streak -- -- O
388 with -- -- O
389 a -- -- O
390 90-79 -- -- O
391 victory -- -- O
392 over -- -- O
393 Phoenix -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
394 . -- -- O

395 Gary -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
396 Payton -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
397 added -- -- O
398 11 -- -- O
399 points -- -- O
400 for -- -- O
401 the -- -- O
402 Sonics -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
403 , -- -- O
404 who -- -- O
405 ended -- -- O
406 a -- -- O
407 four -- -- O
408 - -- -- O
409 game -- -- O
410 losing -- -- O
411 streak -- -- O
412 against -- -- O
413 the -- -- O
414 Suns -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
415 . -- -- O

416 Shawn -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
417 Marion -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
418 led -- -- O
419 the -- -- O
420 Suns -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
421 with -- -- O
422 19 -- -- O
423 points -- -- O
424 . -- -- O

425 Jake -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
426 Tsakalidis -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
427 had -- -- O
428 his -- -- O
429 first -- -- O
430 career -- -- O
431 double-double -- -- O
432 with -- -- O
433 16 -- -- O
434 rebounds -- -- O
435 and -- -- O
436 10 -- -- O
437 points -- -- O
438 , -- -- O
439 and -- -- O

440 Stephon -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
441 Marbury -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
442 added -- -- O
443 16 -- -- O
444 points -- -- O
445 and -- -- O
446 12 -- -- O
447 assists -- -- O
448 for -- -- O
449 Phoenix -- -- O
450 . -- -- O

451 In -- -- O
452 Los -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
453 Angeles -- -- I-GPE.Urbanarea.City
454 , -- -- O
455 Marcus -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
456 Fizer -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
457 scored -- -- O
458 15 -- -- O
459 of -- -- O
460 his -- -- O
461 21 -- -- O
462 points -- -- O
463 in -- -- O
464 the -- -- O
465 second -- -- O
466 half -- -- O
467 as -- -- O
468 Chicago -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
469 beat -- -- O
470 two-time -- -- O
471 defending -- -- O
472 NBA -- -- B-ORG.Association
473 champion -- -- O
474 Los -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
475 Angeles -- -- I-ORG.Association.Team
476 Lakers -- -- I-ORG.Association.Team
477 for -- -- O
478 the -- -- O
479 second -- -- O
480 time -- -- O
481 this -- -- O
482 season -- -- O
483 . -- -- O

484 This -- -- O
485 game -- -- O
486 ended -- -- O
487 97 -- -- O
488 - -- -- O
489 89 -- -- O
490 . -- -- O

491 Shaquille -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
492 O'Neal -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
493 sat -- -- O
494 out -- -- O
495 the -- -- O
496 Lakers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
497 ' -- -- O
498 final -- -- O
499 game -- -- O
500 before -- -- O
501 the -- -- O
502 All -- -- O
503 - -- -- O
504 Star -- -- O
505 break -- -- O
506 to -- -- O
507 rest -- -- O
508 his -- -- O
509 aching -- -- O
510 feet -- -- O
511 , -- -- O
512 and -- -- O
513 was -- -- O
514 greatly -- -- O
515 missed -- -- O
516 . -- -- O

517 Kobe -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
518 Bryant -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
519 scored -- -- O
520 38 -- -- O
521 points -- -- O
522 and -- -- O
523 Slava -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
524 Medvedenko -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
525 added -- -- O
526 11 -- -- O
527 for -- -- O
528 the -- -- O
529 Lakers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
530 . -- -- O

531 Samaki -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
532 Walker -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
533 had -- -- O
534 eight -- -- O
535 points -- -- O
536 and -- -- O
537 14 -- -- O
538 rebounds -- -- O
539 . -- -- O

540 The -- -- O
541 Bulls -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
542 ( -- -- O
543 11-36 -- -- O
544 ) -- -- O
545 have -- -- O
546 the -- -- O
547 NBA's -- -- O
548 worst -- -- O
549 record -- -- O
550 , -- -- O
551 but -- -- O
552 beat -- -- O
553 the -- -- O
554 Lakers -- -- B-ORG.Association.Team
555 twice -- -- O
556 in -- -- O
557 as -- -- O
558 many -- -- O
559 games -- -- O
560 this -- -- O
561 season -- -- O
562 - -- -- O
563 the -- -- O
564 only -- -- O
565 team -- -- O
566 they've -- -- O
567 beaten -- -- O
568 more -- -- O
569 than -- -- O
570 once -- -- O
571 this -- -- O
572 season -- -- O
573 . -- -- O

574 Their -- -- O
575 3-22 -- -- O
576 road -- -- O
577 record -- -- O
578 is -- -- O
579 also -- -- O
580 the -- -- O
581 league's -- -- O
582 worst -- -- O
583 . -- -- O


0 Saturday -- -- O
1 , -- -- O
2 November -- -- O
3 15 -- -- O

4 11-07-03 -- -- O
5 19:04:00EST -- -- O

6 Today -- -- O
7 is -- -- O
8 Saturday -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 Nov -- -- O
11 . -- -- O

20 There -- -- O
21 are -- -- O
22 46 -- -- O
23 days -- -- O
24 left -- -- O
25 in -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 year -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

29 Highlights -- -- O
30 in -- -- O
31 history -- -- O
32 on -- -- O
33 this -- -- O
34 date -- -- O
35 : -- -- O

36 1492 -- -- O
37 - -- -- O
38 Christopher -- -- B-PER
39 Columbus -- -- I-PER
40 notes -- -- O
41 in -- -- O
42 his -- -- O
43 journal -- -- O
44 the -- -- O
45 use -- -- O
46 of -- -- O
47 tobacco -- -- O
48 among -- -- O
49 Indians -- -- O
50 _ -- -- O
51 the -- -- O
52 first -- -- O
53 recorded -- -- O
54 reference -- -- O
55 to -- -- O
56 tobacco -- -- O
57 by -- -- O
58 a -- -- O
59 European -- -- O
60 . -- -- O

61 1577 -- -- O
62 - -- -- O
63 Sir -- -- O
64 Francis -- -- B-PER
65 Drake -- -- I-PER
66 of -- -- O
67 England -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
68 leaves -- -- O
69 on -- -- O
70 a -- -- O
71 voyage -- -- O
72 around -- -- O
73 the -- -- O
74 world -- -- O
75 . -- -- O

76 1806 -- -- O
77 - -- -- O
78 Army -- -- B-ORG.Militaryorganization.Governmentarmedforces
79 officer -- -- O
80 Zebulon -- -- B-PER.Militarypersonnel.Militaryofficer
81 Pike -- -- I-PER.Militarypersonnel.Militaryofficer
82 spots -- -- O
83 the -- -- O
84 mountaintop -- -- O
85 _ -- -- O
86 now -- -- O
87 known -- -- O
88 as -- -- O
89 Pike's -- -- B-LOC.Geographicpoint
90 Peak -- -- I-LOC.Geographicpoint
91 _ -- -- O
92 and -- -- O
93 starts -- -- O
94 to -- -- O
95 climb -- -- O
96 it -- -- O
97 , -- -- O
98 but -- -- O
99 is -- -- O
100 arrested -- -- O
101 by -- -- O
102 Spanish -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
103 authorities -- -- O
104 for -- -- O
105 trespassing -- -- O
106 . -- -- O

107 1889 -- -- O
108 - -- -- O
109 Brazil's -- -- O
110 King -- -- O
111 Pedro -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
112 II -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
113 abdicates -- -- O
114 , -- -- O
115 and -- -- O
116 Brazil -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
117 is -- -- O
118 proclaimed -- -- O
119 a -- -- O
120 republic -- -- O
121 . -- -- O

122 1920 -- -- O
123 - -- -- O
124 League -- -- B-ORG.International
125 of -- -- I-ORG.International
126 Nations -- -- I-ORG.International
127 Assembly -- -- I-ORG.International
128 holds -- -- O
129 first -- -- O
130 meeting -- -- O
131 in -- -- O
132 Geneva -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
133 . -- -- O

134 1928 -- -- O
135 - -- -- O
136 Fascist -- -- B-ORG.Government.Council
137 Grand -- -- I-ORG.Government.Council
138 Council -- -- I-ORG.Government.Council
139 becomes -- -- O
140 part -- -- O
141 of -- -- O
142 Italian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
143 constitution -- -- O
144 . -- -- O

145 1939 -- -- O
146 - -- -- O
147 U.S -- -- O
148 . -- -- O
149 President -- -- O
150 Franklin -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
151 Roosevelt -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
152 lays -- -- O
153 the -- -- O
154 cornerstone -- -- O
155 of -- -- O
156 the -- -- O
157 Jefferson -- -- B-FAC.Building
158 Memorial -- -- I-FAC.Building
159 in -- -- O
160 Washington -- -- O
161 , -- -- O
162 D.C -- -- O
163 . -- -- O

164 1940 -- -- O
165 - -- -- O
166 The -- -- O
167 first -- -- O
168 75,000 -- -- O
169 American -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
170 men -- -- O
171 are -- -- O
172 called -- -- O
173 to -- -- O
174 the -- -- O
175 Armed -- -- B-ORG.Militaryorganization.Governmentarmedforces
176 Forces -- -- I-ORG.Militaryorganization.Governmentarmedforces
177 duty -- -- O
178 under -- -- O
179 peacetime -- -- O
180 conscription -- -- O
181 . -- -- O

182 1963 -- -- O
183 - -- -- O
184 Cuban -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
185 President -- -- O
186 Fidel -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
187 Castro -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
188 warns -- -- O
189 the -- -- O
190 United -- -- B-GPE.Organizationofcountries.Organizationofcountries
191 Nations -- -- I-GPE.Organizationofcountries.Organizationofcountries
192 that -- -- O
193 his -- -- O
194 country -- -- O
195 will -- -- O
196 shoot -- -- O
197 down -- -- O
198 any -- -- O
199 U.S -- -- O
200 . -- -- O
201 military -- -- O
202 plane -- -- O
203 entering -- -- O
204 its -- -- O
205 airspace -- -- O
206 on -- -- O
207 a -- -- O
208 reconnaissance -- -- O
209 mission -- -- O
210 , -- -- O
211 saying -- -- O
212 that -- -- O
213 the -- -- O
214 United -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
215 States -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
216 already -- -- O
217 verified -- -- O
218 the -- -- O
219 withdrawal -- -- O
220 of -- -- O
221 Soviet -- -- B-GPE.Organizationofcountries.Organizationofcountries
222 strategic -- -- O
223 missiles -- -- O
224 from -- -- O
225 Cuba -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
226 by -- -- O
227 high-seas -- -- O
228 inspection -- -- O
229 . -- -- O

230 1969 -- -- O
231 - -- -- O
232 A -- -- O
233 Vietnam -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
234 War -- -- O
235 protest -- -- O
236 gathers -- -- O
237 250,000 -- -- O
238 people -- -- O
239 in -- -- O
240 Washington -- -- O
241 , -- -- O
242 D.C -- -- O
243 . -- -- O

244 1976 -- -- O
245 - -- -- O
246 Syrian -- -- B-ORG.Militaryorganization.Governmentarmedforces
247 army -- -- I-ORG.Militaryorganization.Governmentarmedforces
248 takes -- -- O
249 control -- -- O
250 of -- -- O
251 Beirut -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
252 , -- -- O
253 ending -- -- O
254 an -- -- O
255 18-month -- -- O
256 civil -- -- O
257 war -- -- O
258 in -- -- O
259 Lebanon -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
260 . -- -- O

261 1977 -- -- O
262 - -- -- O
263 Israel -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
264 sends -- -- O
265 formal -- -- O
266 invitation -- -- O
267 to -- -- O
268 Egypt's -- -- O
269 President -- -- O
270 Anwar -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
271 Sadat -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
272 to -- -- O
273 visit -- -- O
274 Jerusalem -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
275 and -- -- O
276 address -- -- O
277 the -- -- O
278 Israeli -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
279 parliament -- -- O
280 . -- -- O

281 1982 -- -- O
282 - -- -- O
283 Funeral -- -- O
284 services -- -- O
285 are -- -- O
286 held -- -- O
287 in -- -- O
288 Moscow's -- -- O
289 Red -- -- B-FAC.Structure.Plaza
290 Square -- -- I-FAC.Structure.Plaza
291 for -- -- O
292 the -- -- O
293 late -- -- O
294 Soviet -- -- B-GPE.Organizationofcountries.Organizationofcountries
295 President -- -- O
296 Leonid -- -- O
297 I -- -- O
298 . -- -- O
299 Brezhnev -- -- O
300 . -- -- O

301 1985 -- -- O
302 - -- -- O
303 Britain -- -- B-LOC.Land
304 and -- -- O
305 Ireland -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
306 sign -- -- O
307 an -- -- O
308 accord -- -- O
309 giving -- -- O
310 Dublin -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
311 an -- -- O
312 official -- -- O
313 consultative -- -- O
314 role -- -- O
315 in -- -- O
316 governing -- -- O
317 Northern -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
318 Ireland -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
319 . -- -- O

320 1986 -- -- O
321 - -- -- O
322 A -- -- O
323 government -- -- O
324 tribunal -- -- O
325 in -- -- O
326 Nicaragua -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
327 convicts -- -- O
328 American -- -- O
329 Eugene -- -- B-PER
330 Hasenfus -- -- I-PER
331 on -- -- O
332 charges -- -- O
333 of -- -- O
334 delivering -- -- O
335 arms -- -- O
336 to -- -- O
337 Contra -- -- B-ORG.Militaryorganization.Nongovernmentmilitia
338 rebels -- -- O
339 , -- -- O
340 and -- -- O
341 sentences -- -- O
342 him -- -- O
343 to -- -- O
344 30 -- -- O
345 years -- -- O
346 in -- -- O
347 prison -- -- O
348 . -- -- O

349 He -- -- O
350 is -- -- O
351 pardoned -- -- O
352 a -- -- O
353 month -- -- O
354 later -- -- O
355 . -- -- O

356 1988 -- -- O
357 - -- -- O
358 The -- -- O
359 Palestine -- -- B-ORG.Government.Legislativebody
360 National -- -- I-ORG.Government.Legislativebody
361 Council -- -- I-ORG.Government.Legislativebody
362 , -- -- O
363 the -- -- O
364 legislative -- -- O
365 body -- -- O
366 of -- -- O
367 the -- -- O
368 PLO -- -- B-ORG.Politicalorganization.Party
369 , -- -- O
370 proclaims -- -- O
371 the -- -- O
372 establishment -- -- O
373 of -- -- O
374 an -- -- O
375 independent -- -- O
376 Palestinian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
377 state -- -- O
378 at -- -- O
379 the -- -- O
380 close -- -- O
381 of -- -- O
382 a -- -- O
383 four-day -- -- O
384 conference -- -- O
385 in -- -- O
386 Algiers -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
387 . -- -- O

388 1991 -- -- O
389 - -- -- O
390 The -- -- O
391 U.N -- -- O
392 . -- -- O
393 Environment -- -- O
394 Program -- -- O
395 reports -- -- O
396 worldwide -- -- O
397 production -- -- O
398 and -- -- O
399 use -- -- O
400 of -- -- O
401 chemicals -- -- O
402 believed -- -- O
403 to -- -- O
404 cause -- -- O
405 erosion -- -- O
406 of -- -- O
407 the -- -- O
408 ozone -- -- O
409 layer -- -- O
410 has -- -- O
411 declined -- -- O
412 40 -- -- O
413 percent -- -- O
414 over -- -- O
415 the -- -- O
416 last -- -- O
417 five -- -- O
418 years -- -- O
419 . -- -- O

420 1992 -- -- O
421 - -- -- O
422 Shining -- -- B-ORG.Politicalorganization.Party
423 Path -- -- I-ORG.Politicalorganization.Party
424 rebels -- -- O
425 detonate -- -- O
426 two -- -- O
427 bombs -- -- O
428 in -- -- O
429 Lima -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
430 , -- -- O
431 Peru -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
432 , -- -- O
433 wounding -- -- O
434 10 -- -- O
435 people -- -- O
436 . -- -- O

437 1993 -- -- O
438 - -- -- O
439 Gunmen -- -- O
440 in -- -- O
441 Lebanon -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
442 kill -- -- O
443 a -- -- O
444 senior -- -- O
445 aide -- -- O
446 of -- -- O
447 Palestinian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
448 leader -- -- O
449 Yasser -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
450 Arafat -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
451 ; -- -- O
452 a -- -- O
453 judge -- -- O
454 in -- -- O
455 Mineola -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.Village
456 , -- -- O
457 New -- -- B-GPE.Provincestate.Provincestate
458 York -- -- I-GPE.Provincestate.Provincestate
459 , -- -- O
460 sentences -- -- O
461 Joey -- -- B-PER
462 Buttafuoco -- -- I-PER
463 to -- -- O
464 six -- -- O
465 months -- -- O
466 in -- -- O
467 jail -- -- O
468 for -- -- O
469 the -- -- O
470 statutory -- -- O
471 rape -- -- O
472 of -- -- O
473 Amy -- -- B-PER
474 Fisher -- -- I-PER
475 , -- -- O
476 who -- -- O
477 shot -- -- O
478 and -- -- O
479 wounded -- -- O
480 Buttafuoco's -- -- O
481 wife -- -- O
482 , -- -- O
483 Mary -- -- B-PER
484 Jo -- -- I-PER
485 . -- -- O

486 1994 -- -- O
487 - -- -- O
488 Dug-in -- -- O
489 Bosnian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
490 government -- -- O
491 troops -- -- O
492 struggle -- -- O
493 to -- -- O
494 repel -- -- O
495 Serbs -- -- O
496 from -- -- O
497 overrunning -- -- O
498 the -- -- O
499 Bihac -- -- B-LOC.Position
500 pocket -- -- I-LOC.Position
501 , -- -- O
502 a -- -- O
503 U.N.-declared -- -- O
504 safe -- -- O
505 zone -- -- O
506 . -- -- O

507 1995 -- -- O
508 - -- -- O
509 European -- -- B-GPE.Organizationofcountries.Organizationofcountries
510 Union -- -- I-GPE.Organizationofcountries.Organizationofcountries
511 ambassadors -- -- O
512 approve -- -- O
513 a -- -- O
514 total -- -- O
515 arms -- -- O
516 embargo -- -- O
517 to -- -- O
518 punish -- -- O
519 Nigeria's -- -- O
520 military -- -- O
521 regime -- -- O
522 for -- -- O
523 the -- -- O
524 execution -- -- O
525 of -- -- O
526 nine -- -- O
527 political -- -- O
528 activists -- -- O
529 . -- -- O

530 1996 -- -- O
531 - -- -- O
532 Voters -- -- O
533 in -- -- O
534 Sao -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
535 Paulo -- -- I-GPE.Urbanarea.City
536 , -- -- O
537 Brazil -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
538 , -- -- O
539 elect -- -- O
540 Celso -- -- B-PER.Politician.Mayor
541 Pitta -- -- I-PER.Politician.Mayor
542 as -- -- O
543 their -- -- O
544 first -- -- O
545 black -- -- O
546 mayor -- -- O
547 . -- -- O

548 1997 -- -- O
549 - -- -- O
550 Russian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
551 President -- -- O
552 Boris -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
553 Yeltsin -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
554 fires -- -- O
555 two -- -- O
556 cabinet -- -- O
557 ministers -- -- O
558 after -- -- O
559 it -- -- O
560 is -- -- O
561 revealed -- -- O
562 that -- -- O
563 Anatolij -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
564 Chubais -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
565 , -- -- O
566 Russia's -- -- O
567 leading -- -- O
568 economic -- -- O
569 reformer -- -- O
570 , -- -- O
571 took -- -- O
572 money -- -- O
573 for -- -- O
574 a -- -- O
575 book -- -- O
576 from -- -- O
577 a -- -- O
578 financial -- -- O
579 institution -- -- O
580 . -- -- O

581 1998 -- -- O
582 - -- -- O
583 U.S -- -- O
584 . -- -- O
585 President -- -- O
586 Bill -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
587 Clinton -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
588 announces -- -- O
589 that -- -- O
590 Iraq -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
591 has -- -- O
592 ``backed -- -- O
593 down -- -- O
594 '' -- -- O
595 and -- -- O
596 has -- -- O
597 promised -- -- O
598 to -- -- O
599 cooperate -- -- O
600 unconditionally -- -- O
601 with -- -- O
602 U.N -- -- O
603 . -- -- O
604 weapons -- -- O
605 inspectors -- -- O
606 . -- -- O

607 1999 -- -- O
608 - -- -- O
609 Chinese -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
610 and -- -- O
611 U.S -- -- O
612 . -- -- O
613 negotiators -- -- O
614 sign -- -- O
615 a -- -- O
616 breakthrough -- -- O
617 agreement -- -- O
618 in -- -- O
619 Beijing -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
620 that -- -- O
621 removes -- -- O
622 trade -- -- O
623 barriers -- -- O
624 and -- -- O
625 clears -- -- O
626 the -- -- O
627 biggest -- -- O
628 hurdle -- -- O
629 to -- -- O
630 China's -- -- O
631 entry -- -- O
632 into -- -- O
633 the -- -- O
634 World -- -- B-ORG.International
635 Trade -- -- I-ORG.International
636 Organization -- -- I-ORG.International
637 . -- -- O

638 2000 -- -- O
639 - -- -- O
640 Two -- -- O
641 Palestinian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
642 laborers -- -- O
643 trying -- -- O
644 to -- -- O
645 skirt -- -- O
646 an -- -- O
647 Israeli -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
648 checkpoint -- -- O
649 near -- -- O
650 Jerusalem -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
651 are -- -- O
652 shot -- -- O
653 and -- -- O
654 wounded -- -- O
655 by -- -- O
656 undercover -- -- O
657 police -- -- O
658 as -- -- O
659 Palestinians -- -- O
660 mark -- -- O
661 the -- -- O
662 12th -- -- O
663 anniversary -- -- O
664 of -- -- O
665 their -- -- O
666 symbolic -- -- O
667 independence -- -- O
668 declaration -- -- O
669 . -- -- O

670 2001 -- -- O
671 - -- -- O
672 A -- -- O
673 judge -- -- O
674 rules -- -- O
675 that -- -- O
676 Britain -- -- B-LOC.Land
677 has -- -- O
678 no -- -- O
679 laws -- -- O
680 governing -- -- O
681 human -- -- O
682 cloning -- -- O
683 , -- -- O
684 despite -- -- O
685 Parliament's -- -- O
686 attempt -- -- O
687 to -- -- O
688 make -- -- O
689 it -- -- O
690 the -- -- O
691 first -- -- O
692 nation -- -- O
693 to -- -- O
694 permit -- -- O
695 and -- -- O
696 regulate -- -- O
697 research -- -- O
698 using -- -- O
699 cloned -- -- O
700 embryos -- -- O
701 . -- -- O

702 2002 -- -- O
703 - -- -- O
704 Colombian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
705 army -- -- O
706 troops -- -- O
707 rescued -- -- O
708 Bishop -- -- O
709 Jorge -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
710 Enrique -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
711 Jimenez -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
712 , -- -- O
713 one -- -- O
714 of -- -- O
715 Latin -- -- O
716 American's -- -- O
717 leading -- -- O
718 Roman -- -- B-ORG
719 Catholic -- -- I-ORG
720 bishops -- -- O
721 , -- -- O
722 and -- -- O
723 another -- -- O
724 priest -- -- O
725 after -- -- O
726 a -- -- O
727 gunbattle -- -- O
728 with -- -- O
729 their -- -- O
730 rebel -- -- O
731 captors -- -- O
732 in -- -- O
733 the -- -- O
734 Andean -- -- B-LOC
735 mountains -- -- O
736 . -- -- O

737 Today's -- -- O
738 Birthdays -- -- O
739 : -- -- O

740 William -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
741 Pitt -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
742 , -- -- O
743 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
744 prime -- -- O
745 minister -- -- O
746 ( -- -- O
747 1708-1779 -- -- O
748 ); -- -- O
749 William -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition.Scientist
750 Herschel -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition.Scientist
751 , -- -- O
752 German-born -- -- O
753 astronomer -- -- O
754 and -- -- O
755 discoverer -- -- O
756 of -- -- O
757 Uranus -- -- B-LOC
758 ( -- -- O
759 1738-1822 -- -- O
760 ); -- -- O
761 Erwin -- -- B-PER.Militarypersonnel.Militaryofficer
762 Rommel -- -- I-PER.Militarypersonnel.Militaryofficer
763 , -- -- O
764 German -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
765 general -- -- O
766 ( -- -- O
767 1891-1944 -- -- O
768 ); -- -- O
769 Petula -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
770 Clark -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
771 , -- -- O
772 English -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
773 popular -- -- O
774 singer -- -- O
775 ( -- -- O
776 1934 -- -- O
777 --); -- -- O
778 Sam -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
779 Waterston -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
780 , -- -- O
781 U.S -- -- O
782 . -- -- O
783 actor -- -- O
784 ( -- -- O
785 1940 -- -- O
786 --); -- -- O
787 Rachel -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
788 True -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
789 , -- -- O
790 U.S -- -- O
791 . -- -- O
792 actress -- -- O
793 ( -- -- O
794 1969 -- -- O
795 --). -- -- O

796 Thought -- -- O
797 For -- -- O
798 Today -- -- O
799 : -- -- O

800 In -- -- O
801 a -- -- O
802 time -- -- O
803 of -- -- O
804 war -- -- O
805 ... -- -- O
806 the -- -- O
807 task -- -- O
808 of -- -- O
809 news-writers -- -- O
810 is -- -- O
811 easy -- -- O
812 ; -- -- O
813 they -- -- O
814 have -- -- O
815 nothing -- -- O
816 to -- -- O
817 do -- -- O
818 but -- -- O
819 to -- -- O
820 tell -- -- O
821 that -- -- O
822 the -- -- O
823 battle -- -- O
824 is -- -- O
825 expected -- -- O
826 , -- -- O
827 and -- -- O
828 afterward -- -- O
829 that -- -- O
830 a -- -- O
831 battle -- -- O
832 has -- -- O
833 been -- -- O
834 fought -- -- O
835 , -- -- O
836 in -- -- O
837 which -- -- O
838 we -- -- O
839 and -- -- O
840 our -- -- O
841 friends -- -- O
842 , -- -- O
843 whether -- -- O
844 conquering -- -- O
845 or -- -- O
846 conquered -- -- O
847 , -- -- O
848 did -- -- O
849 all -- -- O
850 , -- -- O
851 and -- -- O
852 our -- -- O
853 enemies -- -- O
854 did -- -- O
855 nothing -- -- O
856 _ -- -- O
857 Samuel -- -- B-PER.Professionalposition
858 Johnson -- -- I-PER.Professionalposition
859 , -- -- O
860 English -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
861 critic -- -- O
862 ( -- -- O
863 1709-1784 -- -- O
864 ). -- -- O


0 Britain -- -- B-LOC.Land
1 planned -- -- O
2 to -- -- O
3 send -- -- O
4 troops -- -- O
5 to -- -- O
6 Cyrpus -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
7 after -- -- O
8 1974 -- -- O
9 coup -- -- O
10 : -- -- O
11 records -- -- O
12 ( -- -- O
13 EMBARGO -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 RELEASABLE -- -- O
16 Saturday -- -- O
17 0001 -- -- O
18 GMT -- -- O
19 ) -- -- O

20 LONDON -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
21 , -- -- O
22 Jan -- -- O
23 1 -- -- O
24 ( -- -- O
25 AFP -- -- O
26 ) -- -- O

27 Britain -- -- B-LOC.Land
28 considered -- -- O
29 sending -- -- O
30 thousands -- -- O
31 of -- -- O
32 troops -- -- O
33 to -- -- O
34 Cyrpus -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
35 in -- -- O
36 1974 -- -- O
37 to -- -- O
38 reinstate -- -- O
39 the -- -- O
40 Mediterranean -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
41 island's -- -- O
42 president -- -- O
43 after -- -- O
44 he -- -- O
45 was -- -- O
46 deposed -- -- O
47 by -- -- O
48 a -- -- O
49 coup -- -- O
50 , -- -- O
51 newly-released -- -- O
52 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
53 government -- -- O
54 files -- -- O
55 showed -- -- O
56 Saturday -- -- O
57 . -- -- O

58 At -- -- O
59 the -- -- O
60 request -- -- O
61 of -- -- O
62 then -- -- O
63 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
64 prime -- -- O
65 minister -- -- O
66 James -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
67 Callaghan -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
68 , -- -- O
69 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
70 defence -- -- O
71 officials -- -- O
72 looked -- -- O
73 at -- -- O
74 the -- -- O
75 possibility -- -- O
76 of -- -- O
77 sending -- -- O
78 12,000 -- -- O
79 soldiers -- -- O
80 to -- -- O
81 Cyprus -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
82 in -- -- O
83 July -- -- O
84 1974 -- -- O
85 to -- -- O
86 reinstate -- -- O
87 Archbishop -- -- O
88 Makarios -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
89 as -- -- O
90 president -- -- O
91 . -- -- O

92 However -- -- O
93 , -- -- O
94 the -- -- O
95 military -- -- O
96 warned -- -- O
97 that -- -- O
98 such -- -- O
99 a -- -- O
100 move -- -- O
101 risked -- -- O
102 seeing -- -- O
103 thousands -- -- O
104 of -- -- O
105 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
106 troops -- -- O
107 mired -- -- O
108 in -- -- O
109 a -- -- O
110 situation -- -- O
111 " -- -- O
112 similar -- -- O
113 to -- -- O
114 Northern -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
115 Ireland -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
116 ", -- -- O
117 where -- -- O
118 soldiers -- -- O
119 spent -- -- O
120 decades -- -- O
121 caught -- -- O
122 in -- -- O
123 the -- -- O
124 middle -- -- O
125 of -- -- O
126 sectarian -- -- O
127 conflict -- -- O
128 . -- -- O

129 In -- -- O
130 the -- -- O
131 end -- -- O
132 , -- -- O
133 Turkey -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
134 responded -- -- O
135 to -- -- O
136 the -- -- O
137 Greek-sponsored -- -- O
138 coup -- -- O
139 by -- -- O
140 invading -- -- O
141 Cyprus -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
142 , -- -- O
143 eventually -- -- O
144 bringing -- -- O
145 Makarios -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
146 back -- -- O
147 to -- -- O
148 power -- -- O
149 and -- -- O
150 leading -- -- O
151 to -- -- O
152 the -- -- O
153 division -- -- O
154 of -- -- O
155 the -- -- O
156 island -- -- O
157 which -- -- O
158 still -- -- O
159 exists -- -- O
160 today -- -- O
161 . -- -- O

162 Britain -- -- B-LOC.Land
163 , -- -- O
164 which -- -- O
165 ruled -- -- O
166 Cyprus -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
167 as -- -- O
168 a -- -- O
169 colony -- -- O
170 until -- -- O
171 1960 -- -- O
172 , -- -- O
173 considered -- -- O
174 stepping -- -- O
175 in -- -- O
176 first -- -- O
177 , -- -- O
178 according -- -- O
179 to -- -- O
180 the -- -- O
181 formerly -- -- O
182 confidential -- -- O
183 government -- -- O
184 papers -- -- O
185 , -- -- O
186 released -- -- O
187 Saturday -- -- O
188 by -- -- O
189 the -- -- O
190 National -- -- B-ORG.Government.Agency
191 Archives -- -- I-ORG.Government.Agency
192 . -- -- O

193 There -- -- O
194 were -- -- O
195 real -- -- O
196 risks -- -- O
197 to -- -- O
198 this -- -- O
199 , -- -- O
200 the -- -- O
201 military -- -- O
202 briefing -- -- O
203 paper -- -- O
204 warned -- -- O
205 . -- -- O

206 " -- -- O
207 Whilst -- -- O
208 we -- -- O
209 believe -- -- O
210 that -- -- O
211 there -- -- O
212 will -- -- O
213 be -- -- O
214 sections -- -- O
215 of -- -- O
216 the -- -- O
217 Cyprus -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
218 population -- -- O
219 which -- -- O
220 will -- -- O
221 welcome -- -- O
222 the -- -- O
223 return -- -- O
224 of -- -- O
225 Makarios -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
226 , -- -- O
227 and -- -- O
228 may -- -- O
229 even -- -- O
230 actively -- -- O
231 assist -- -- O
232 us -- -- O
233 , -- -- O
234 it -- -- O
235 would -- -- O
236 be -- -- O
237 unrealistic -- -- O
238 not -- -- O
239 to -- -- O
240 accept -- -- O
241 that -- -- O
242 there -- -- O
243 will -- -- O
244 be -- -- O
245 sizeable -- -- O
246 elements -- -- O
247 who -- -- O
248 will -- -- O
249 actively -- -- O
250 oppose -- -- O
251 us -- -- O
252 by -- -- O
253 resorting -- -- O
254 to -- -- O
255 guerrilla -- -- O
256 warfare -- -- O
257 ," -- -- O
258 it -- -- O
259 said -- -- O
260 . -- -- O

261 " -- -- O
262 Bitter -- -- O
263 experience -- -- O
264 has -- -- O
265 shown -- -- O
266 us -- -- O
267 that -- -- O
268 even -- -- O
269 a -- -- O
270 small -- -- O
271 number -- -- O
272 of -- -- O
273 dedicated -- -- O
274 men -- -- O
275 with -- -- O
276 support -- -- O
277 from -- -- O
278 the -- -- O
279 local -- -- O
280 population -- -- O
281 can -- -- O
282 pin -- -- O
283 down -- -- O
284 an -- -- O
285 inordinately -- -- O
286 large -- -- O
287 force -- -- O
288 for -- -- O
289 an -- -- O
290 indefinite -- -- O
291 period -- -- O
292 , -- -- O
293 and -- -- O
294 we -- -- O
295 might -- -- O
296 well -- -- O
297 end -- -- O
298 up -- -- O
299 by -- -- O
300 facing -- -- O
301 an -- -- O
302 open-ended -- -- O
303 and -- -- O
304 expensive -- -- O
305 situation -- -- O
306 similar -- -- O
307 to -- -- O
308 Northern -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
309 Ireland -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
310 ." -- -- O

311 There -- -- O
312 were -- -- O
313 around -- -- O
314 13,000 -- -- O
315 dependents -- -- O
316 of -- -- O
317 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
318 service -- -- O
319 personnel -- -- O
320 in -- -- O
321 Cyprus -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
322 at -- -- O
323 the -- -- O
324 time -- -- O
325 , -- -- O
326 and -- -- O
327 the -- -- O
328 document -- -- O
329 also -- -- O
330 raises -- -- O
331 concerns -- -- O
332 about -- -- O
333 exposing -- -- O
334 them -- -- O
335 to -- -- O
336 possible -- -- O
337 danger -- -- O
338 . -- -- O


0 2nd -- -- O
1 LD -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 Writethru -- -- O
4 : -- -- O
5 Kyrgyz -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
6 president -- -- O
7 signs -- -- O
8 law -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 close -- -- O
11 U.S -- -- O
12 . -- -- O
13 air -- -- O
14 base -- -- O

15 MOSCOW -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
16 , -- -- O
17 Feb -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

19 20 -- -- O
20 ( -- -- O
21 Xinhua -- -- O
22 ) -- -- O

23 Kyrgyz -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
24 President -- -- O
25 Kurmanbek -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
26 Bakiyev -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
27 on -- -- O
28 Friday -- -- O
29 signed -- -- O
30 in -- -- O
31 the -- -- O
32 capital -- -- O
33 of -- -- O
34 Bishkek -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
35 a -- -- O
36 law -- -- O
37 to -- -- O
38 officially -- -- O
39 close -- -- O
40 the -- -- O
41 U.S -- -- O
42 . -- -- O
43 air -- -- O
44 base -- -- O
45 for -- -- O
46 anti-terror -- -- O
47 operations -- -- O
48 in -- -- O
49 Afghanistan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
50 , -- -- O
51 Russian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
52 news -- -- O
53 agencies -- -- O
54 reported -- -- O
55 . -- -- O

56 The -- -- O
57 president's -- -- O
58 signature -- -- O
59 came -- -- O
60 after -- -- O
61 the -- -- O
62 Kyrgyz -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
63 parliament -- -- O
64 voted -- -- O
65 overwhelmingly -- -- O
66 on -- -- O
67 Thursday -- -- O
68 in -- -- O
69 favor -- -- O
70 of -- -- O
71 the -- -- O
72 closure -- -- O
73 . -- -- O

74 The -- -- O
75 U.S.military -- -- O
76 will -- -- O
77 have -- -- O
78 180 -- -- O
79 days -- -- O
80 to -- -- O
81 remove -- -- O
82 its -- -- O
83 soldiers -- -- O
84 and -- -- O
85 equipment -- -- O
86 out -- -- O
87 of -- -- O
88 the -- -- O
89 air -- -- O
90 base -- -- O
91 once -- -- O
92 it -- -- O
93 is -- -- O
94 notified -- -- O
95 by -- -- O
96 the -- -- O
97 Kyrgyz -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
98 government -- -- O
99 . -- -- O

100 " -- -- O
101 Bakiyev -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
102 has -- -- O
103 signed -- -- O
104 the -- -- O
105 bill -- -- O
106 passed -- -- O
107 by -- -- O
108 the -- -- O
109 parliament -- -- O
110 on -- -- O
111 Thursday -- -- O
112 , -- -- O
113 terminating -- -- O
114 the -- -- O
115 agreement -- -- O
116 with -- -- O
117 the -- -- O
118 United -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
119 States -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
120 ," -- -- O
121 Interfax -- -- B-ORG.Commercialorganization.Newsagency
122 quoted -- -- O
123 the -- -- O
124 president's -- -- O
125 press -- -- O
126 service -- -- O
127 as -- -- O
128 saying -- -- O
129 . -- -- O

130 The -- -- O
131 law -- -- O
132 comes -- -- O
133 into -- -- O
134 force -- -- O
135 from -- -- O
136 the -- -- O
137 day -- -- O
138 of -- -- O
139 signing -- -- O
140 , -- -- O
141 the -- -- O
142 press -- -- O
143 office -- -- O
144 said -- -- O
145 . -- -- O

146 Kyrgyzstan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
147 concluded -- -- O
148 an -- -- O
149 agreement -- -- O
150 with -- -- O
151 the -- -- O
152 United -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
153 States -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
154 on -- -- O
155 the -- -- O
156 Manas -- -- B-FAC.Installation.Militaryinstallation
157 air -- -- I-FAC.Installation.Militaryinstallation
158 base -- -- I-FAC.Installation.Militaryinstallation
159 in -- -- O
160 December -- -- O
161 2001 -- -- O
162 . -- -- O

163 The -- -- O
164 air -- -- O
165 base -- -- O
166 currently -- -- O
167 hosts -- -- O
168 more -- -- O
169 than -- -- O
170 1,000 -- -- O
171 military -- -- O
172 personnel -- -- O
173 . -- -- O

174 Bakiyev -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
175 said -- -- O
176 in -- -- O
177 February -- -- O
178 that -- -- O
179 he -- -- O
180 had -- -- O
181 decided -- -- O
182 to -- -- O
183 close -- -- O
184 the -- -- O
185 air -- -- O
186 base -- -- O
187 , -- -- O
188 as -- -- O
189 the -- -- O
190 U.S -- -- O
191 . -- -- O
192 was -- -- O
193 not -- -- O
194 paying -- -- O
195 enough -- -- O
196 rent -- -- O
197 . -- -- O

198 The -- -- O
199 announcement -- -- O
200 of -- -- O
201 the -- -- O
202 closure -- -- O
203 came -- -- O
204 after -- -- O
205 Russia -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
206 offered -- -- O
207 Kyrgyzstan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
208 more -- -- O
209 than -- -- O
210 2 -- -- O
211 billion -- -- O
212 U.S -- -- O
213 . -- -- O
214 dollars -- -- O
215 in -- -- O
216 aid -- -- O
217 . -- -- O

218 However -- -- O
219 , -- -- O
220 both -- -- O
221 Kyrgyzstan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
222 and -- -- O
223 Russia -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
224 denied -- -- O
225 any -- -- O
226 links -- -- O
227 between -- -- O
228 the -- -- O
229 Manas -- -- B-FAC.Installation.Militaryinstallation
230 closure -- -- O
231 and -- -- O
232 Moscow's -- -- O
233 financial -- -- O
234 help -- -- O
235 . -- -- O

236 The -- -- O
237 closure -- -- O
238 would -- -- O
239 further -- -- O
240 strain -- -- O
241 coalition -- -- O
242 supply -- -- O
243 lines -- -- O
244 at -- -- O
245 a -- -- O
246 time -- -- O
247 when -- -- O
248 U.S -- -- O
249 . -- -- O
250 President -- -- O
251 Barack -- -- B-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
252 Obama -- -- I-PER.Politician.Headofgovernment
253 is -- -- O
254 planning -- -- O
255 to -- -- O
256 send -- -- O
257 more -- -- O
258 troops -- -- O
259 to -- -- O
260 Afghanistan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
261 . -- -- O

262 The -- -- O
263 new -- -- O
264 U.S -- -- O
265 . -- -- O
266 administration -- -- O
267 is -- -- O
268 considering -- -- O
269 resuming -- -- O
270 military -- -- O
271 cooperation -- -- O
272 with -- -- O
273 Uzbekistan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
274 after -- -- O
275 the -- -- O
276 closure -- -- O
277 of -- -- O
278 the -- -- O
279 Manas -- -- B-FAC.Installation.Militaryinstallation
280 base -- -- O
281 , -- -- O
282 to -- -- O
283 ensure -- -- O
284 logistic -- -- O
285 supplies -- -- O
286 to -- -- O
287 Afghanistan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
288 . -- -- O

289 Russia -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
290 , -- -- O
291 which -- -- O
292 has -- -- O
293 an -- -- O
294 air -- -- O
295 base -- -- O
296 in -- -- O
297 Kant -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea
298 , -- -- O
299 a -- -- O
300 short -- -- O
301 distance -- -- O
302 from -- -- O
303 the -- -- O
304 Manas -- -- B-FAC.Installation.Militaryinstallation
305 , -- -- O
306 has -- -- O
307 recently -- -- O
308 said -- -- O
309 it -- -- O
310 was -- -- O
311 ready -- -- O
312 to -- -- O
313 broaden -- -- O
314 cooperation -- -- O
315 with -- -- O
316 Washington -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
317 on -- -- O
318 non -- -- O
319 - -- -- O
320 military -- -- O
321 supplies -- -- O
322 to -- -- O
323 Afghanistan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
324 via -- -- O
325 the -- -- O
326 so -- -- O
327 - -- -- O
328 called -- -- O
329 " -- -- O
330 northern -- -- O
331 corridor -- -- O
332 ," -- -- O
333 which -- -- O
334 is -- -- O
335 likely -- -- O
336 to -- -- O
337 cross -- -- O
338 Russia -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
339 into -- -- O
340 central -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
341 Asia -- -- I-LOC.Position.Region
342 before -- -- O
343 entering -- -- O
344 northern -- -- O
345 Afghanistan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
346 . -- -- O


0 CGames -- -- O
1 : -- -- O
2 India -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
3 suffers -- -- O
4 blow -- -- O
5 as -- -- O
6 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
7 fighters -- -- O
8 dominate -- -- O

9 NEW -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
10 DELHI -- -- I-GPE.Urbanarea.City
11 , -- -- O
12 Oct -- -- O
13 11 -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 2010 -- -- O
16 ( -- -- O
17 AFP -- -- O
18 ) -- -- O

19 India's -- -- O
20 hopes -- -- O
21 of -- -- O
22 boxing -- -- O
23 glory -- -- O
24 suffered -- -- O
25 a -- -- O
26 blow -- -- O
27 on -- -- O
28 Monday -- -- O
29 , -- -- O
30 as -- -- O
31 all -- -- O
32 three -- -- O
33 of -- -- O
34 the -- -- O
35 country's -- -- O
36 fighters -- -- O
37 lost -- -- O
38 their -- -- O
39 semi-final -- -- O
40 bouts -- -- O
41 in -- -- O
42 a -- -- O
43 first -- -- O
44 session -- -- O
45 dominated -- -- O
46 by -- -- O
47 Britain's -- -- O
48 " -- -- O
49 home -- -- O
50 nations -- -- O
51 ". -- -- O

52 Light -- -- O
53 flyweight -- -- O
54 Amandeep -- -- B-PER
55 Singh -- -- I-PER
56 , -- -- O
57 lightweight -- -- O
58 Jai -- -- B-PER
59 Bhagwan -- -- I-PER
60 and -- -- O
61 welterweight -- -- O
62 Dilbag -- -- B-PER
63 Singh -- -- I-PER
64 crashed -- -- O
65 out -- -- O
66 , -- -- O
67 disappointing -- -- O
68 a -- -- O
69 noisy -- -- O
70 , -- -- O
71 partisan -- -- O
72 crowd -- -- O
73 at -- -- O
74 the -- -- O
75 Talkatora -- -- B-FAC.Structure
76 Indoor -- -- I-FAC.Structure
77 Stadium -- -- I-FAC.Structure
78 in -- -- O
79 New -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
80 Delhi -- -- I-GPE.Urbanarea.City
81 . -- -- O

82 All -- -- O
83 three -- -- O
84 pick -- -- O
85 up -- -- O
86 bronze -- -- O
87 medals -- -- O
88 , -- -- O
89 though -- -- O
90 , -- -- O
91 leaving -- -- O
92 four -- -- O
93 boxers -- -- O
94 from -- -- O
95 the -- -- O
96 hosts -- -- O
97 , -- -- O
98 including -- -- O
99 Indian -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
100 boxing's -- -- O
101 poster -- -- O
102 boy -- -- O
103 Vijender -- -- B-PER
104 Singh -- -- I-PER
105 , -- -- O
106 to -- -- O
107 carry -- -- O
108 the -- -- O
109 nation's -- -- O
110 hopes -- -- O
111 in -- -- O
112 the -- -- O
113 evening -- -- O
114 session -- -- O
115 . -- -- O

116 Topping -- -- O
117 the -- -- O
118 British -- -- B-LOC.Land
119 wins -- -- O
120 were -- -- O
121 Northern -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
122 Ireland -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
123 , -- -- O
124 who -- -- O
125 saw -- -- O
126 European -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
127 champion -- -- O
128 Paddy -- -- B-PER
129 Barnes -- -- I-PER
130 go -- -- O
131 through -- -- O
132 with -- -- O
133 Paddy -- -- B-PER
134 Gallagher -- -- I-PER
135 and -- -- O
136 Thomas -- -- B-PER
137 McCarthy -- -- I-PER
138 . -- -- O

139 Olympic -- -- O
140 bronze -- -- O
141 medallist -- -- O
142 Barnes -- -- B-PER
143 saw -- -- O
144 off -- -- O
145 a -- -- O
146 challenge -- -- O
147 from -- -- O
148 Amandeep -- -- B-PER
149 Singh -- -- I-PER
150 in -- -- O
151 his -- -- O
152 bout -- -- O
153 , -- -- O
154 while -- -- O
155 Gallagher -- -- B-PER
156 held -- -- O
157 on -- -- O
158 for -- -- O
159 a -- -- O
160 win -- -- O
161 against -- -- O
162 Dilbag -- -- B-PER
163 Singh -- -- I-PER
164 . -- -- O

165 McCarthy -- -- B-PER
166 beat -- -- O
167 Kenya's -- -- O
168 2006 -- -- O
169 bronze -- -- O
170 medallist -- -- O
171 Joshua -- -- B-PER
172 Makonjio -- -- I-PER
173 in -- -- O
174 the -- -- O
175 light -- -- O
176 heavyweight -- -- O
177 division -- -- O
178 and -- -- O
179 goes -- -- O
180 on -- -- O
181 to -- -- O
182 meet -- -- O
183 Callum -- -- B-PER
184 Johnson -- -- I-PER
185 , -- -- O
186 who -- -- O
187 is -- -- O
188 hoping -- -- O
189 to -- -- O
190 retain -- -- O
191 the -- -- O
192 light -- -- O
193 heavyweight -- -- O
194 crown -- -- O
195 for -- -- O
196 Scotland -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
197 . -- -- O

198 Barnes -- -- B-PER
199 , -- -- O
200 who -- -- O
201 trains -- -- O
202 at -- -- O
203 the -- -- O
204 same -- -- O
205 gym -- -- O
206 that -- -- O
207 produced -- -- O
208 former -- -- O
209 WBA -- -- B-ORG.Association
210 featherweight -- -- O
211 champion -- -- O
212 Barry -- -- B-PER
213 McGuigan -- -- I-PER
214 , -- -- O
215 said -- -- O
216 he -- -- O
217 was -- -- O
218 confident -- -- O
219 going -- -- O
220 into -- -- O
221 the -- -- O
222 final -- -- O
223 . -- -- O

224 But -- -- O
225 his -- -- O
226 opponent -- -- O
227 , -- -- O
228 defending -- -- O
229 champion -- -- O
230 Jafet -- -- B-PER
231 Uotoni -- -- I-PER
232 from -- -- O
233 Namibia -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
234 , -- -- O
235 is -- -- O
236 out -- -- O
237 to -- -- O
238 stop -- -- O
239 him -- -- O
240 . -- -- O

241 " -- -- O
242 My -- -- O
243 main -- -- O
244 aim -- -- O
245 is -- -- O
246 to -- -- O
247 win -- -- O
248 the -- -- O
249 gold -- -- O
250 ," -- -- O
251 said -- -- O
252 Uotoni -- -- B-PER
253 after -- -- O
254 beating -- -- O
255 Muhammad -- -- B-PER
256 Waseem -- -- I-PER
257 from -- -- O
258 Pakistan -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
259 10-1 -- -- O
260 . -- -- O

261 " -- -- O
262 I -- -- O
263 want -- -- O
264 to -- -- O
265 break -- -- O
266 a -- -- O
267 new -- -- O
268 record -- -- O
269 for -- -- O
270 my -- -- O
271 country -- -- O
272 and -- -- O
273 bring -- -- O
274 back -- -- O
275 two -- -- O
276 gold -- -- O
277 medals -- -- O
278 . -- -- O

279 " -- -- O
280 I -- -- O
281 want -- -- O
282 to -- -- O
283 take -- -- O
284 back -- -- O
285 my -- -- O
286 title -- -- O
287 . -- -- O

288 It -- -- O
289 is -- -- O
290 like -- -- O
291 my -- -- O
292 wife -- -- O
293 . -- -- O

294 I -- -- O
295 dont -- -- O
296 want -- -- O
297 anyone -- -- O
298 to -- -- O
299 take -- -- O
300 my -- -- O
301 wife -- -- O
302 and -- -- O
303 if -- -- O
304 anyone -- -- O
305 tries -- -- O
306 to -- -- O
307 , -- -- O
308 Ill -- -- O
309 stop -- -- O
310 them -- -- O
311 ." -- -- O

312 Young -- -- O
313 Wales -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
314 bantamweight -- -- O
315 Sean -- -- B-PER
316 McGoldrick -- -- I-PER
317 provided -- -- O
318 the -- -- O
319 upset -- -- O
320 of -- -- O
321 the -- -- O
322 day -- -- O
323 by -- -- O
324 beating -- -- O
325 the -- -- O
326 silver -- -- O
327 medallist -- -- O
328 from -- -- O
329 Melbourne -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
330 in -- -- O
331 2006 -- -- O
332 , -- -- O
333 Louis -- -- B-PER
334 Julie -- -- I-PER
335 of -- -- O
336 Mauritius -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
337 . -- -- O

338 The -- -- O
339 18-year-old -- -- O
340 from -- -- O
341 Newport -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
342 , -- -- O
343 who -- -- O
344 faces -- -- O
345 Manju -- -- B-PER
346 Wanniarachchi -- -- I-PER
347 of -- -- O
348 Sri -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
349 Lanka -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
350 , -- -- O
351 said -- -- O
352 he -- -- O
353 hoped -- -- O
354 the -- -- O
355 victory -- -- O
356 against -- -- O
357 the -- -- O
358 Olympic -- -- O
359 bronze -- -- O
360 medallist -- -- O
361 , -- -- O
362 proved -- -- O
363 that -- -- O
364 his -- -- O
365 training -- -- O
366 had -- -- O
367 paid -- -- O
368 off -- -- O
369 and -- -- O
370 he -- -- O
371 was -- -- O
372 on -- -- O
373 the -- -- O
374 way -- -- O
375 to -- -- O
376 becoming -- -- O
377 a -- -- O
378 world -- -- O
379 class -- -- O
380 fighter -- -- O
381 . -- -- O

382 " -- -- O
383 I'm -- -- O
384 here -- -- O
385 for -- -- O
386 gold -- -- O
387 . -- -- O

388 I'm -- -- O
389 going -- -- O
390 to -- -- O
391 give -- -- O
392 it -- -- O
393 my -- -- O
394 best -- -- O
395 shot -- -- O
396 ," -- -- O
397 he -- -- O
398 added -- -- O
399 . -- -- O

400 The -- -- O
401 teenager -- -- O
402 , -- -- O
403 who -- -- O
404 is -- -- O
405 still -- -- O
406 at -- -- O
407 school -- -- O
408 , -- -- O
409 is -- -- O
410 now -- -- O
411 guaranteed -- -- O
412 at -- -- O
413 least -- -- O
414 a -- -- O
415 silver -- -- O
416 medal -- -- O
417 in -- -- O
418 his -- -- O
419 first -- -- O
420 senior -- -- O
421 tournament -- -- O
422 and -- -- O
423 just -- -- O
424 his -- -- O
425 third -- -- O
426 international -- -- O
427 . -- -- O

428 His -- -- O
429 2-1 -- -- O
430 points -- -- O
431 win -- -- O
432 over -- -- O
433 Julie -- -- B-PER
434 happened -- -- O
435 when -- -- O
436 he -- -- O
437 should -- -- O
438 have -- -- O
439 been -- -- O
440 in -- -- O
441 lessons -- -- O
442 back -- -- O
443 home -- -- O
444 . -- -- O

445 " -- -- O
446 I'm -- -- O
447 sure -- -- O
448 the -- -- O
449 teachers -- -- O
450 will -- -- O
451 excuse -- -- O
452 me -- -- O
453 ," -- -- O
454 he -- -- O
455 joked -- -- O
456 . -- -- O

457 Wanniarachchi's -- -- O
458 appearance -- -- O
459 in -- -- O
460 the -- -- O
461 final -- -- O
462 comes -- -- O
463 after -- -- O
464 he -- -- O
465 secured -- -- O
466 the -- -- O
467 island -- -- O
468 nation -- -- O
469 its -- -- O
470 first -- -- O
471 Commonwealth -- -- B-ORG.Association
472 boxing -- -- O
473 medal -- -- O
474 for -- -- O
475 60 -- -- O
476 years -- -- O
477 on -- -- O
478 Sunday -- -- O
479 . -- -- O

480 The -- -- O
481 30-year-old -- -- O
482 was -- -- O
483 ecstatic -- -- O
484 after -- -- O
485 his -- -- O
486 win -- -- O
487 against -- -- O
488 Botswana's -- -- O
489 Tirafolo -- -- B-PER
490 Seoko -- -- I-PER
491 and -- -- O
492 kissed -- -- O
493 the -- -- O
494 feet -- -- O
495 of -- -- O
496 his -- -- O
497 coach -- -- O
498 and -- -- O
499 trainer -- -- O
500 at -- -- O
501 the -- -- O
502 bell -- -- O
503 . -- -- O

504 European -- -- B-LOC.Land.Continent
505 silver -- -- O
506 medallist -- -- O
507 Tom -- -- B-PER
508 Stalker -- -- I-PER
509 , -- -- O
510 who -- -- O
511 beat -- -- O
512 India's -- -- O
513 Bhagwan -- -- B-PER
514 , -- -- O
515 now -- -- O
516 faces -- -- O
517 Scotland's -- -- O
518 Josh -- -- O
519 Taylor -- -- O
520 , -- -- O
521 who -- -- O
522 beat -- -- O
523 Tonga's -- -- O
524 Lomalito -- -- B-PER
525 Moala -- -- I-PER
526 . -- -- O

527 Stalker's -- -- O
528 10-5 -- -- O
529 win -- -- O
530 was -- -- O
531 a -- -- O
532 bad-tempered -- -- O
533 affair -- -- O
534 that -- -- O
535 saw -- -- O
536 the -- -- O
537 England -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
538 fighter -- -- O
539 suffer -- -- O
540 a -- -- O
541 series -- -- O
542 of -- -- O
543 low -- -- O
544 blows -- -- O
545 . -- -- O

546 " -- -- O
547 I -- -- O
548 didnt -- -- O
549 panic -- -- O
550 when -- -- O
551 he -- -- O
552 was -- -- O
553 floating -- -- O
554 inside -- -- O
555 because -- -- O
556 I -- -- O
557 can -- -- O
558 take -- -- O
559 a -- -- O
560 body -- -- O
561 shot -- -- O
562 but -- -- O
563 not -- -- O
564 low -- -- O
565 blows -- -- O
566 . -- -- O

567 It -- -- O
568 was -- -- O
569 a -- -- O
570 real -- -- O
571 slugfest -- -- O
572 ," -- -- O
573 he -- -- O
574 said -- -- O
575 . -- -- O

576 Callum -- -- B-PER
577 Smith -- -- I-PER
578 , -- -- O
579 who -- -- O
580 like -- -- O
581 Stalker -- -- B-PER
582 comes -- -- O
583 from -- -- O
584 Liverpool -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
585 , -- -- O
586 also -- -- O
587 made -- -- O
588 it -- -- O
589 to -- -- O
590 the -- -- O
591 final -- -- O
592 after -- -- O
593 winning -- -- O
594 his -- -- O
595 welterweight -- -- O
596 bout -- -- O
597 against -- -- O
598 Carl -- -- B-PER
599 Hield -- -- I-PER
600 of -- -- O
601 The -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
602 Bahamas -- -- I-GPE.Country.Country
603 . -- -- O

604 " -- -- O
605 It's -- -- O
606 a -- -- O
607 good -- -- O
608 day -- -- O
609 for -- -- O
610 Liverpool -- -- B-GPE.Urbanarea.City
611 ," -- -- O
612 said -- -- O
613 the -- -- O
614 20-year-old -- -- O
615 , -- -- O
616 whose -- -- O
617 brothers -- -- O
618 Paul -- -- B-PER
619 ( -- -- O
620 boxing -- -- O
621 silver -- -- O
622 in -- -- O
623 2002 -- -- O
624 ) -- -- O
625 and -- -- O
626 Stephen -- -- B-PER
627 ( -- -- O
628 gold -- -- O
629 in -- -- O
630 2006 -- -- O
631 ) -- -- O
632 have -- -- O
633 both -- -- O
634 won -- -- O
635 Commonwealth -- -- B-ORG.Association
636 medals -- -- O
637 . -- -- O

638 The -- -- O
639 welterweight -- -- O
640 said -- -- O
641 their -- -- O
642 experience -- -- O
643 has -- -- O
644 helped -- -- O
645 him -- -- O
646 prepare -- -- O
647 for -- -- O
648 the -- -- O
649 tournament -- -- O
650 and -- -- O
651 was -- -- O
652 happy -- -- O
653 to -- -- O
654 be -- -- O
655 facing -- -- O
656 Northern -- -- O
657 Ireland's -- -- O
658 Gallagher -- -- B-PER
659 in -- -- O
660 the -- -- O
661 final -- -- O
662 . -- -- O

663 " -- -- O
664 I -- -- O
665 just -- -- O
666 take -- -- O
667 every -- -- O
668 fight -- -- O
669 as -- -- O
670 it -- -- O
671 comes -- -- O
672 . -- -- O

673 I -- -- O
674 take -- -- O
675 every -- -- O
676 fight -- -- O
677 as -- -- O
678 a -- -- O
679 final -- -- O
680 and -- -- O
681 that's -- -- O
682 what -- -- O
683 I've -- -- O
684 done -- -- O
685 ," -- -- O
686 he -- -- O
687 said -- -- O
688 . -- -- O


0 Wall -- -- B-FAC.Way.Street
1 Street -- -- I-FAC.Way.Street
2 mostly -- -- O
3 lower -- -- O
4 as -- -- O
5 rally -- -- O
6 fizzles -- -- O
7 ; -- -- O
8 Dow -- -- B-VAL
9 slips -- -- O
10 0.27 -- -- O
11 percent -- -- O

12 NEW -- -- B-GPE.Provincestate.Provincestate
13 YORK -- -- I-GPE.Provincestate.Provincestate
14 , -- -- O
15 May -- -- O
16 19 -- -- O
17 ( -- -- O
18 AFP -- -- O
19 ) -- -- O

20 An -- -- O
21 early -- -- O
22 rally -- -- O
23 on -- -- O
24 Wall -- -- B-FAC.Way.Street
25 Street -- -- I-FAC.Way.Street
26 faded -- -- O
27 Wednesday -- -- O
28 , -- -- O
29 leaving -- -- O
30 stocks -- -- O
31 mostly -- -- O
32 lower -- -- O
33 after -- -- O
34 crude -- -- O
35 oil -- -- O
36 futures -- -- O
37 shot -- -- O
38 higher -- -- O
39 late -- -- O
40 in -- -- O
41 the -- -- O
42 session -- -- O
43 . -- -- O

44 After -- -- O
45 gaining -- -- O
46 more -- -- O
47 than -- -- O
48 100 -- -- O
49 points -- -- O
50 in -- -- O
51 early -- -- O
52 trade -- -- O
53 , -- -- O
54 the -- -- O
55 Dow -- -- B-VAL
56 Jones -- -- I-VAL
57 Industrial -- -- I-VAL
58 Average -- -- I-VAL
59 finished -- -- O
60 with -- -- O
61 a -- -- O
62 loss -- -- O
63 of -- -- O
64 27.39 -- -- O
65 points -- -- O
66 ( -- -- O
67 0.27 -- -- O
68 percent -- -- O
69 ) -- -- O
70 at -- -- O
71 9,941.12 -- -- O
72 at -- -- O
73 the -- -- O
74 closing -- -- O
75 bell -- -- O
76 . -- -- O

77 The -- -- O
78 tech-heavy -- -- O
79 Nasdaq -- -- O
80 also -- -- O
81 saw -- -- O
82 a -- -- O
83 strong -- -- O
84 rally -- -- O
85 fade -- -- O
86 , -- -- O
87 and -- -- O
88 ended -- -- O
89 nearly -- -- O
90 flat -- -- O
91 , -- -- O
92 with -- -- O
93 a -- -- O
94 fractional -- -- O
95 gain -- -- O
96 of -- -- O
97 0.43 -- -- O
98 point -- -- O
99 at -- -- O
100 1,898.25 -- -- O
101 , -- -- O
102 based -- -- O
103 on -- -- O
104 preliminary -- -- O
105 closing -- -- O
106 figures -- -- O
107 . -- -- O

108 The -- -- O
109 collapse -- -- O
110 of -- -- O
111 the -- -- O
112 stock -- -- O
113 rally -- -- O
114 came -- -- O
115 as -- -- O
116 oil -- -- O
117 futures -- -- O
118 took -- -- O
119 off -- -- O
120 , -- -- O
121 nearing -- -- O
122 record -- -- O
123 highs -- -- O
124 amid -- -- O
125 bloodshed -- -- O
126 in -- -- O
127 the -- -- O
128 Middle -- -- B-LOC.Position.Region
129 East -- -- I-LOC.Position.Region
130 and -- -- O
131 US -- -- B-GPE.Country.Country
132 President -- -- O
133 George -- -- O
134 W -- -- O
135 . -- -- O
136 Bush's -- -- O
137 refusal -- -- O
138 to -- -- O
139 release -- -- O
140 emergency -- -- O
141 oil -- -- O
142 reserves -- -- O
143 . -- -- O
