1 Kenyan -- -- B-GPE
2 President -- -- O
3 Vows -- -- O
4 Harsh -- -- O
5 Action -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 Declares -- -- O
8 Mourning -- -- O
9 Period -- -- O

1 President -- -- O
2 Uhuru -- -- B-PER
3 Kenyatta -- -- I-PER
4 has -- -- O
5 announced -- -- O
6 three -- -- O
7 days -- -- O
8 of -- -- O
9 national -- -- O
10 mourning -- -- O
11 , -- -- O
12 following -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 deaths -- -- O
15 of -- -- O
16 almost -- -- O
17 150 -- -- O
18 people -- -- O
19 in -- -- O
20 one -- -- O
21 of -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 worst -- -- O
24 massacres -- -- O
25 in -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 country -- -- O
28 's -- -- O
29 history -- -- O
30 . -- -- O

1 Kenyatta -- -- B-PER
2 promised -- -- O
3 to -- -- O
4 " -- -- O
5 fight -- -- O
6 terrorism -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 end -- -- O
10 . -- -- O
11 " -- -- O

1 In -- -- O
2 his -- -- O
3 first -- -- O
4 televised -- -- O
5 address -- -- O
6 since -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 attack -- -- O
9 ended -- -- O
10 on -- -- O
11 Thursday -- -- O
12 , -- -- O
13 Kenyatta -- -- B-PER
14 condemned -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 " -- -- O
17 barbaric -- -- O
18 slaughter -- -- O
19 " -- -- O
20 and -- -- O
21 asked -- -- O
22 help -- -- O
23 from -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 Muslim -- -- O
26 community -- -- O
27 in -- -- O
28 rooting -- -- O
29 out -- -- O
30 radical -- -- O
31 elements -- -- O
32 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 My -- -- O
3 administration -- -- O
4 shall -- -- O
5 respond -- -- O
6 in -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 severest -- -- O
9 way -- -- O
10 possible -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 attack -- -- O
14 and -- -- O
15 any -- -- O
16 other -- -- O
17 attack -- -- O
18 to -- -- O
19 us -- -- O
20 , -- -- O
21 " -- -- O
22 Kenyan -- -- B-GPE
23 president -- -- B-PER
24 said -- -- O
25 , -- -- O
26 speaking -- -- O
27 from -- -- O
28 the -- -- O
29 capital -- -- O
30 Nairobi -- -- B-GPE
31 on -- -- O
32 Saturday -- -- O
33 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 Thursday -- -- O
3 wounded -- -- O
4 Kenya -- -- B-GPE
5 , -- -- O
6 Thursday -- -- O
7 wounded -- -- O
8 families -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 friends -- -- O
11 and -- -- O
12 communities -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 victims -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 attack -- -- O
19 . -- -- O
20 " -- -- O

1 Al -- -- O
2 Qaeda-linked -- -- O
3 al-Shabab -- -- B-ORG
4 gunmen -- -- O
5 killed -- -- O
6 around -- -- O
7 150 -- -- O
8 people -- -- O
9 at -- -- O
10 Garissa -- -- B-ORG
11 University -- -- I-ORG
12 College -- -- I-ORG
13 campus -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 as -- -- O
16 retaliation -- -- O
17 for -- -- O
18 Kenyan -- -- B-GPE
19 participation -- -- O
20 in -- -- O
21 a -- -- O
22 mission -- -- O
23 against -- -- O
24 Shabab -- -- B-ORG
25 in -- -- O
26 Somalia -- -- B-GPE
27 . -- -- O

1 Most -- -- O
2 of -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 victims -- -- O
5 in -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 Thursday -- -- O
8 massacre -- -- O
9 were -- -- O
10 students -- -- O
11 attending -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 college -- -- O
14 situated -- -- O
15 some -- -- O
16 200 -- -- O
17 km -- -- O
18 ( -- -- O
19 120 -- -- O
20 miles -- -- O
21 ) -- -- O
22 from -- -- O
23 the -- -- O
24 Somali -- -- B-GPE
25 border -- -- O
26 . -- -- O

1 Four -- -- O
2 of -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 attackers -- -- O
5 were -- -- O
6 killed -- -- O
7 after -- -- O
8 a -- -- O
9 15-hour -- -- O
10 siege -- -- O
11 , -- -- O
12 while -- -- O
13 one -- -- O
14 was -- -- O
15 reportedly -- -- O
16 arrested -- -- O
17 . -- -- O

1 ' -- -- O
2 We -- -- O
3 will -- -- O
4 bring -- -- O
5 them -- -- O
6 all -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 justice -- -- O
9 ' -- -- O

1 In -- -- O
2 his -- -- O
3 Saturday -- -- O
4 address -- -- O
5 to -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 nation -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 Kenyatta -- -- B-PER
10 said -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 task -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 countering -- -- O
15 terrorism -- -- O
16 had -- -- O
17 been -- -- O
18 made -- -- O
19 all -- -- O
20 the -- -- O
21 more -- -- O
22 difficult -- -- O
23 by -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 fact -- -- O
26 " -- -- O
27 the -- -- O
28 planners -- -- O
29 and -- -- O
30 financiers -- -- O
31 of -- -- O
32 this -- -- O
33 brutality -- -- O
34 are -- -- O
35 deeply -- -- O
36 embedded -- -- O
37 in -- -- O
38 our -- -- O
39 communities -- -- O
40 , -- -- O
41 " -- -- O
42 and -- -- O
43 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 We -- -- O
3 will -- -- O
4 fight -- -- O
5 terrorism -- -- O
6 to -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 end -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 " -- -- O
11 Kenyatta -- -- B-PER
12 said -- -- O
13 . -- -- O

1 Five -- -- O
2 men -- -- O
3 have -- -- O
4 been -- -- O
5 arrested -- -- O
6 in -- -- O
7 wake -- -- O
8 of -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 attacks -- -- O
11 , -- -- O
12 for -- -- O
13 alleged -- -- O
14 connection -- -- O
15 with -- -- O
16 Shabab -- -- B-ORG
17 militants -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 Kenyan -- -- B-GPE
2 authorities -- -- O
3 also -- -- O
4 put -- -- O
5 a -- -- O
6 $ -- -- O
7 220,000 -- -- O
8 ( -- -- O
9 200,000 -- -- O
10 euro -- -- O
11 ) -- -- O
12 bounty -- -- O
13 on -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 head -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 alleged -- -- O
19 mastermind -- -- O
20 of -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 attack -- -- O
23 , -- -- O
24 Mohamed -- -- B-PER
25 Mohamud -- -- I-PER
26 , -- -- O
27 - -- -- O
28 also -- -- O
29 known -- -- O
30 as -- -- O
31 Dulyadin -- -- B-PER
32 Gamadhere -- -- I-PER
33 - -- -- O
34 who -- -- O
35 is -- -- O
36 believed -- -- O
37 to -- -- O
38 be -- -- O
39 in -- -- O
40 Somalia -- -- B-GPE
41 . -- -- O

1 Mohamud -- -- B-PER
2 is -- -- O
3 a -- -- O
4 former -- -- O
5 teacher -- -- O
6 at -- -- O
7 a -- -- O
8 Kenyan -- -- B-GPE
9 Islamic -- -- O
10 Madrassa -- -- O
11 school -- -- O
12 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 I -- -- O
3 want -- -- O
4 you -- -- O
5 to -- -- O
6 know -- -- O
7 that -- -- O
8 our -- -- O
9 security -- -- O
10 forces -- -- O
11 are -- -- O
12 pursuing -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 remaining -- -- O
15 accomplices -- -- O
16 . -- -- O

1 We -- -- O
2 will -- -- O
3 bring -- -- O
4 all -- -- O
5 of -- -- O
6 them -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 justice -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 " -- -- O
11 Kenyatta -- -- B-PER
12 said -- -- O
13 , -- -- O
14 adding -- -- O
15 that -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 authorities -- -- O
18 were -- -- O
19 in -- -- O
20 " -- -- O
21 active -- -- O
22 pursuit -- -- O
23 " -- -- O
24 of -- -- O
25 the -- -- O
26 mastermind -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 Kenyatta -- -- B-PER
2 also -- -- O
3 declared -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 three-day -- -- O
6 mourning -- -- O
7 period -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 with -- -- O
10 flags -- -- O
11 in -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 country -- -- O
14 flying -- -- O
15 at -- -- O
16 half -- -- O
17 mast -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 Dead -- -- O
2 gunmen -- -- O
3 on -- -- O
4 display -- -- O

1 Also -- -- O
2 on -- -- O
3 Saturday -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 Kenyan -- -- B-ORG
6 police -- -- I-ORG
7 drove -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 four -- -- O
10 bloated -- -- O
11 and -- -- O
12 naked -- -- O
13 corpses -- -- O
14 of -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 purported -- -- O
17 attackers -- -- O
18 through -- -- O
19 the -- -- O
20 streets -- -- O
21 , -- -- O
22 saying -- -- O
23 the -- -- O
24 display -- -- O
25 was -- -- O
26 made -- -- O
27 to -- -- O
28 help -- -- O
29 in -- -- O
30 determining -- -- O
31 the -- -- O
32 attackers -- -- O
33 identity -- -- O
34 . -- -- O

1 Hundreds -- -- O
2 of -- -- O
3 people -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 including -- -- O
6 children -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 came -- -- O
9 out -- -- O
10 to -- -- O
11 see -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 dead -- -- O
14 bodies -- -- O
15 , -- -- O
16 which -- -- O
17 were -- -- O
18 driven -- -- O
19 almost -- -- O
20 half -- -- O
21 a -- -- O
22 kilometer -- -- O
23 in -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 back -- -- O
26 of -- -- O
27 a -- -- O
28 pick -- -- O
29 up -- -- O
30 truck -- -- O
31 before -- -- O
32 being -- -- O
33 returned -- -- O
34 to -- -- O
35 hospital -- -- O
36 . -- -- O

1 While -- -- O
2 some -- -- O
3 jeered -- -- O
4 and -- -- O
5 took -- -- O
6 photos -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 other -- -- O
9 threw -- -- O
10 stones -- -- O
11 at -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 dead -- -- O
14 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 The -- -- O
3 intention -- -- O
4 was -- -- O
5 not -- -- O
6 a -- -- O
7 parade -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 but -- -- O
10 rather -- -- O
11 for -- -- O
12 public -- -- O
13 identification -- -- O
14 so -- -- O
15 that -- -- O
16 if -- -- O
17 anyone -- -- O
18 can -- -- O
19 recognise -- -- O
20 them -- -- O
21 whether -- -- O
22 they -- -- O
23 are -- -- O
24 a -- -- O
25 relative -- -- O
26 or -- -- O
27 someone -- -- O
28 who -- -- O
29 knows -- -- O
30 them -- -- O
31 , -- -- O
32 " -- -- O
33 local -- -- O
34 police -- -- O
35 chief -- -- O
36 Benjamin -- -- O
37 Ong -- -- O
38 'ombe -- -- O
39 said -- -- O
40 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 Too -- -- O
3 many -- -- O
4 people -- -- O
5 turned -- -- O
6 out -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 so -- -- O
9 we -- -- O
10 had -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 return -- -- O
13 them -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 " -- -- O
16 he -- -- O
17 added -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 Many -- -- O
2 of -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 citizens -- -- O
5 said -- -- O
6 they -- -- O
7 were -- -- O
8 disgusted -- -- O
9 by -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 showing -- -- O
12 of -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 bodies -- -- O
15 , -- -- O
16 which -- -- O
17 were -- -- O
18 starting -- -- O
19 to -- -- O
20 decay -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 Instead -- -- O
3 of -- -- O
4 driving -- -- O
5 bodies -- -- O
6 around -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 streets -- -- O
9 now -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 security -- -- O
13 forces -- -- O
14 should -- -- O
15 had -- -- O
16 pro-actively -- -- O
17 gone -- -- O
18 out -- -- O
19 to -- -- O
20 stop -- -- O
21 them -- -- O
22 from -- -- O
23 killing -- -- O
24 students -- -- O
25 , -- -- O
26 " -- -- O
27 a -- -- O
28 student -- -- O
29 Ahmed -- -- B-PER
30 Yusuf -- -- I-PER
31 said -- -- O
32 . -- -- O

1 dj -- -- O
2 / -- -- O
3 rc -- -- O
4 ( -- -- O
5 AFP -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 AP -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 Reuters -- -- O
10 ) -- -- O

1 DHS -- -- B-ORG
2 Official -- -- O
3 Gave -- -- O
4 Special -- -- O
5 Favors -- -- O
6 To -- -- O
7 Hillary -- -- B-PER
8 Clinton -- -- I-PER
9 ’ -- -- O
10 s -- -- O
11 Brother -- -- O

1 Alejandro -- -- B-PER
2 Mayorkas -- -- I-PER
3 , -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 former -- -- O
6 director -- -- O
7 of -- -- O
8 U.S. -- -- B-ORG
9 Customs -- -- I-ORG
10 and -- -- I-ORG
11 Immigration -- -- I-ORG
12 Services -- -- I-ORG
13 , -- -- O
14 favored -- -- O
15 projects -- -- O
16 championed -- -- O
17 by -- -- O
18 Nevada -- -- B-GPE
19 U.S. -- -- B-GPE
20 Sen. -- -- O
21 Harry -- -- B-PER
22 Reid -- -- I-PER
23 , -- -- O
24 Virginia -- -- B-GPE
25 Gov. -- -- O
26 Terry -- -- B-PER
27 McAuliffe -- -- I-PER
28 , -- -- O
29 and -- -- O
30 Hillary -- -- B-PER
31 Clinton -- -- I-PER
32 ’ -- -- O
33 s -- -- O
34 brother -- -- O
35 Tony -- -- B-PER
36 Rodham -- -- I-PER
37 , -- -- O
38 according -- -- O
39 to -- -- O
40 an -- -- O
41 explosive -- -- O
42 new -- -- O
43 report -- -- O
44 from -- -- O
45 the -- -- O
46 Department -- -- B-ORG
47 of -- -- I-ORG
48 Homeland -- -- I-ORG
49 Security -- -- I-ORG
50 inspector -- -- O
51 ’ -- -- O
52 s -- -- O
53 general -- -- O
54 ( -- -- O
55 IG -- -- B-ORG
56 ) -- -- O
57 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 IG -- -- B-ORG
3 concluded -- -- O
4 its -- -- O
5 investigation -- -- O
6 into -- -- O
7 whether -- -- O
8 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
9 , -- -- O
10 now -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 deputy -- -- O
13 secretary -- -- O
14 at -- -- O
15 DHS -- -- B-ORG
16 , -- -- O
17 “ -- -- O
18 exerted -- -- O
19 improper -- -- O
20 influence -- -- O
21 ” -- -- O
22 in -- -- O
23 the -- -- O
24 adjudication -- -- O
25 of -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 Employee-Based -- -- O
28 Fifth -- -- O
29 Preference -- -- O
30 ( -- -- O
31 EB-5 -- -- O
32 ) -- -- O
33 , -- -- O
34 which -- -- O
35 allows -- -- O
36 aliens -- -- O
37 to -- -- O
38 invest -- -- O
39 $ -- -- O
40 500,000 -- -- O
41 in -- -- O
42 U.S. -- -- B-GPE
43 companies -- -- O
44 in -- -- O
45 order -- -- O
46 to -- -- O
47 gain -- -- O
48 residency -- -- O
49 for -- -- O
50 themselves -- -- O
51 and -- -- O
52 their -- -- O
53 families -- -- O
54 . -- -- O

1 And -- -- O
2 indeed -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 IG -- -- B-ORG
6 determined -- -- O
7 that -- -- O
8 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
9 did -- -- O
10 improperly -- -- O
11 exert -- -- O
12 his -- -- O
13 influence -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 and -- -- O
16 on -- -- O
17 behalf -- -- O
18 of -- -- O
19 companies -- -- O
20 with -- -- O
21 ties -- -- O
22 to -- -- O
23 Reid -- -- B-PER
24 , -- -- O
25 McAuliffe -- -- B-PER
26 , -- -- O
27 and -- -- O
28 Rodham -- -- B-PER
29 . -- -- O

1 “ -- -- O
2 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
3 communicated -- -- O
4 with -- -- O
5 stakeholders -- -- O
6 on -- -- O
7 substantive -- -- O
8 issues -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 outside -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 normal -- -- O
14 adjudicatory -- -- O
15 process -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 and -- -- O
18 intervened -- -- O
19 with -- -- O
20 the -- -- O
21 career -- -- O
22 USCIS -- -- B-ORG
23 staff -- -- O
24 in -- -- O
25 ways -- -- O
26 that -- -- O
27 benefited -- -- O
28 the -- -- O
29 stakeholders -- -- O
30 , -- -- O
31 ” -- -- O
32 the -- -- O
33 report -- -- O
34 reads -- -- O
35 , -- -- O
36 noting -- -- O
37 that -- -- O
38 in -- -- O
39 each -- -- O
40 of -- -- O
41 those -- -- O
42 cases -- -- O
43 the -- -- O
44 outcome -- -- O
45 would -- -- O
46 have -- -- O
47 been -- -- O
48 different -- -- O
49 if -- -- O
50 not -- -- O
51 for -- -- O
52 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
53 ’ -- -- O
54 intervention -- -- O
55 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 report -- -- O
3 also -- -- O
4 noted -- -- O
5 that -- -- O
6 more -- -- O
7 than -- -- O
8 15 -- -- O
9 USCIS -- -- B-ORG
10 employees -- -- O
11 at -- -- O
12 all -- -- O
13 levels -- -- O
14 conveyed -- -- O
15 “ -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 same -- -- O
18 factual -- -- O
19 scenario -- -- O
20 : -- -- O
21 certain -- -- O
22 applicants -- -- O
23 and -- -- O
24 stakeholders -- -- O
25 received -- -- O
26 preferential -- -- O
27 access -- -- O
28 to -- -- O
29 DHS -- -- B-ORG
30 leadership -- -- O
31 and -- -- O
32 preferential -- -- O
33 treatment -- -- O
34 in -- -- O
35 either -- -- O
36 the -- -- O
37 handling -- -- O
38 of -- -- O
39 their -- -- O
40 application -- -- O
41 or -- -- O
42 petition -- -- O
43 or -- -- O
44 regarding -- -- O
45 the -- -- O
46 merits -- -- O
47 of -- -- O
48 the -- -- O
49 application -- -- O
50 or -- -- O
51 petition -- -- O
52 . -- -- O
53 ” -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 IG -- -- B-ORG
3 , -- -- O
4 which -- -- O
5 began -- -- O
6 its -- -- O
7 investigations -- -- O
8 in -- -- O
9 Sept -- -- O
10 . -- -- O

1 2012 -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 also -- -- O
4 found -- -- O
5 that -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 number -- -- O
8 and -- -- O
9 variety -- -- O
10 of -- -- O
11 witnesses -- -- O
12 was -- -- O
13 “ -- -- O
14 highly -- -- O
15 unusual -- -- O
16 ” -- -- O
17 and -- -- O
18 characterized -- -- O
19 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
20 ’ -- -- O
21 level -- -- O
22 of -- -- O
23 intervention -- -- O
24 as -- -- O
25 “ -- -- O
26 unprecedented -- -- O
27 . -- -- O
28 ” -- -- O

1 In -- -- O
2 one -- -- O
3 case -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
6 intervened -- -- O
7 on -- -- O
8 behalf -- -- O
9 of -- -- O
10 GreenTech -- -- B-ORG
11 Automotive -- -- I-ORG
12 , -- -- O
13 an -- -- O
14 electric -- -- O
15 car -- -- O
16 company -- -- O
17 controlled -- -- O
18 by -- -- O
19 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
20 Coast -- -- I-ORG
21 Funds -- -- I-ORG
22 Management -- -- I-ORG
23 . -- -- O

1 McAuliffe -- -- B-PER
2 was -- -- O
3 chairman -- -- O
4 of -- -- O
5 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
6 Coast -- -- I-ORG
7 ’ -- -- O
8 s -- -- O
9 board -- -- O
10 while -- -- O
11 Tony -- -- B-PER
12 Rodham -- -- I-PER
13 was -- -- O
14 CEO -- -- O
15 . -- -- O

1 In -- -- O
2 an -- -- O
3 unrelated -- -- O
4 case -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 Rodham -- -- B-PER
7 ’ -- -- O
8 s -- -- O
9 position -- -- O
10 with -- -- O
11 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
12 Coast -- -- I-ORG
13 earned -- -- O
14 him -- -- O
15 a -- -- O
16 spot -- -- O
17 on -- -- O
18 the -- -- O
19 board -- -- O
20 of -- -- O
21 a -- -- O
22 gold -- -- O
23 mining -- -- O
24 company -- -- O
25 with -- -- O
26 interests -- -- O
27 in -- -- O
28 Haiti -- -- B-GPE
29 . -- -- O

1 Rodham -- -- B-PER
2 met -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 owner -- -- O
5 of -- -- O
6 that -- -- O
7 company -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 VCS -- -- B-ORG
10 Mining -- -- I-ORG
11 , -- -- O
12 at -- -- O
13 an -- -- O
14 event -- -- O
15 for -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 Clinton -- -- B-ORG
18 Global -- -- I-ORG
19 Initiative -- -- I-ORG
20 , -- -- O
21 his -- -- O
22 sister -- -- O
23 ’ -- -- O
24 s -- -- O
25 charity -- -- O
26 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 IG -- -- B-ORG
3 report -- -- O
4 shows -- -- O
5 that -- -- O
6 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
7 became -- -- O
8 involved -- -- O
9 in -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
12 Coast -- -- I-ORG
13 ’ -- -- O
14 s -- -- O
15 application -- -- O
16 in -- -- O
17 July -- -- O
18 2010 -- -- O
19 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 opposed -- -- O
3 USCIS -- -- B-ORG
4 employees -- -- O
5 ’ -- -- O
6 decision -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 deny -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 company -- -- O
11 ’ -- -- O
12 s -- -- O
13 EB-5 -- -- O
14 visa -- -- O
15 applications -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 though -- -- O
18 staffers -- -- O
19 felt -- -- O
20 that -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 GreenTech -- -- B-ORG
23 project -- -- O
24 fell -- -- O
25 outside -- -- O
26 of -- -- O
27 the -- -- O
28 scope -- -- O
29 of -- -- O
30 the -- -- O
31 program -- -- O
32 and -- -- O
33 that -- -- O
34 it -- -- O
35 was -- -- O
36 “ -- -- O
37 really -- -- O
38 not -- -- O
39 so -- -- O
40 good -- -- O
41 of -- -- O
42 a -- -- O
43 project -- -- O
44 . -- -- O
45 ” -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 McAuliffe -- -- B-PER
3 pushed -- -- O
4 for -- -- O
5 EB-5 -- -- O
6 and -- -- O
7 continuously -- -- O
8 called -- -- O
9 and -- -- O
10 met -- -- O
11 with -- -- O
12 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
13 on -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 matter -- -- O
16 . -- -- O

1 According -- -- O
2 to -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 IG -- -- B-ORG
5 report -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 after -- -- O
8 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
9 Coast -- -- I-ORG
10 ’ -- -- O
11 s -- -- O
12 application -- -- O
13 was -- -- O
14 initially -- -- O
15 denied -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
18 took -- -- O
19 a -- -- O
20 deep -- -- O
21 and -- -- O
22 special -- -- O
23 interest -- -- O
24 in -- -- O
25 the -- -- O
26 project -- -- O
27 , -- -- O
28 telling -- -- O
29 staff -- -- O
30 that -- -- O
31 he -- -- O
32 would -- -- O
33 personally -- -- O
34 oversee -- -- O
35 it -- -- O
36 . -- -- O

1 During -- -- O
2 one -- -- O
3 meeting -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 he -- -- O
6 shocked -- -- O
7 staffers -- -- O
8 by -- -- O
9 saying -- -- O
10 that -- -- O
11 he -- -- O
12 would -- -- O
13 take -- -- O
14 materials -- -- O
15 related -- -- O
16 to -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 application -- -- O
19 home -- -- O
20 so -- -- O
21 that -- -- O
22 he -- -- O
23 could -- -- O
24 work -- -- O
25 on -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 case -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

1 Many -- -- O
2 USCIS -- -- B-ORG
3 staff -- -- O
4 believed -- -- O
5 that -- -- O
6 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
7 ’ -- -- O
8 interest -- -- O
9 in -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 project -- -- O
12 indicated -- -- O
13 that -- -- O
14 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
15 Coast -- -- I-ORG
16 was -- -- O
17 “ -- -- O
18 wired -- -- O
19 in -- -- O
20 ” -- -- O
21 to -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 agency -- -- O
24 . -- -- O

1 In -- -- O
2 early -- -- O
3 2013 -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
6 backed -- -- O
7 off -- -- O
8 of -- -- O
9 his -- -- O
10 hands-on -- -- O
11 involvement -- -- O
12 with -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 application -- -- O
15 . -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 it -- -- O
3 was -- -- O
4 understood -- -- O
5 within -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 agency -- -- O
8 that -- -- O
9 he -- -- O
10 still -- -- O
11 hoped -- -- O
12 to -- -- O
13 see -- -- O
14 its -- -- O
15 application -- -- O
16 approved -- -- O
17 . -- -- O

1 On -- -- O
2 Jan -- -- O
3 . -- -- O

1 29 -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 2013 -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 Rodham -- -- B-PER
6 sent -- -- O
7 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
8 sent -- -- O
9 an -- -- O
10 email -- -- O
11 regarded -- -- O
12 processing -- -- O
13 delays -- -- O
14 . -- -- O

1 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
2 forwarded -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 email -- -- O
5 to -- -- O
6 staff -- -- O
7 with -- -- O
8 a -- -- O
9 “ -- -- O
10 high -- -- O
11 importance -- -- O
12 ” -- -- O
13 designation -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 according -- -- O
16 to -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 inspector -- -- B-ORG
19 general -- -- I-ORG
20 . -- -- O

1 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
2 Coast -- -- I-ORG
3 ’ -- -- O
4 s -- -- O
5 fourth -- -- O
6 amendment -- -- O
7 for -- -- O
8 application -- -- O
9 was -- -- O
10 approved -- -- O
11 in -- -- O
12 Feb -- -- O
13 . -- -- O

1 2014 -- -- O
2 . -- -- O

1 Mayorkas -- -- B-PER
2 has -- -- O
3 previously -- -- O
4 denied -- -- O
5 exerting -- -- O
6 undue -- -- O
7 influence -- -- O
8 on -- -- O
9 behalf -- -- O
10 of -- -- O
11 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
12 Coast -- -- I-ORG
13 . -- -- O

1 Back -- -- O
2 in -- -- O
3 July -- -- O
4 2013 -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 after -- -- O
7 he -- -- O
8 was -- -- O
9 tapped -- -- O
10 by -- -- O
11 President -- -- O
12 Obama -- -- B-PER
13 to -- -- O
14 take -- -- O
15 over -- -- O
16 as -- -- O
17 DHS -- -- B-ORG
18 deputy -- -- O
19 secretary -- -- O
20 , -- -- O
21 he -- -- O
22 responded -- -- O
23 to -- -- O
24 news -- -- O
25 that -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 IG -- -- B-ORG
28 was -- -- O
29 investigating -- -- O
30 his -- -- O
31 relationship -- -- O
32 with -- -- O
33 McAuliffe -- -- B-PER
34 and -- -- O
35 Gulf -- -- B-ORG
36 Coast -- -- I-ORG
37 saying -- -- O
38 that -- -- O
39 it -- -- O
40 was -- -- O
41 “ -- -- O
42 unequivocally -- -- O
43 false -- -- O
44 ” -- -- O
45 that -- -- O
46 he -- -- O
47 had -- -- O
48 played -- -- O
49 favorites -- -- O
50 . -- -- O

1 Chioma -- -- B-PER
2 Ogwuegbu -- -- I-PER
3 : -- -- O
4 Why -- -- O
5 I -- -- O
6 chose -- -- O
7 General -- -- O
8 Buhari -- -- B-PER
9 over -- -- O
10 Goodluck -- -- B-PER
11 Jonathan -- -- I-PER

1 Last -- -- O
2 October -- -- O
3 after -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 APC -- -- B-ORG
6 presidential -- -- O
7 primaries -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 I -- -- O
10 tweeted -- -- O
11 these -- -- O
12 words -- -- O
13 ‘ -- -- O
14 I -- -- O
15 will -- -- O
16 never -- -- O
17 vote -- -- O
18 Buhari -- -- B-PER
19 . -- -- O
20 ’ -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 had -- -- O
3 my -- -- O
4 reasons -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 major -- -- O
8 one -- -- O
9 being -- -- O
10 my -- -- O
11 conviction -- -- O
12 that -- -- O
13 voting -- -- O
14 a -- -- O
15 former -- -- O
16 military -- -- O
17 dictator -- -- O
18 does -- -- O
19 not -- -- O
20 bode -- -- O
21 well -- -- O
22 for -- -- O
23 a -- -- O
24 democracy -- -- O
25 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 same -- -- O
3 reason -- -- O
4 was -- -- O
5 why -- -- O
6 I -- -- O
7 never -- -- O
8 voted -- -- O
9 General -- -- O
10 Olusegun -- -- B-PER
11 Obasanjo -- -- I-PER
12 the -- -- O
13 two -- -- O
14 times -- -- O
15 he -- -- O
16 contested -- -- O
17 and -- -- O
18 won -- -- O
19 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 same -- -- O
3 reason -- -- O
4 I -- -- O
5 never -- -- O
6 voted -- -- O
7 Buhari -- -- B-PER
8 in -- -- O
9 2011 -- -- O
10 nor -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 other -- -- O
13 times -- -- O
14 he -- -- O
15 had -- -- O
16 contested -- -- O
17 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 felt -- -- O
3 that -- -- O
4 all -- -- O
5 former -- -- O
6 military -- -- O
7 dictators -- -- O
8 had -- -- O
9 had -- -- O
10 their -- -- O
11 time -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 it -- -- O
14 was -- -- O
15 time -- -- O
16 for -- -- O
17 us -- -- O
18 to -- -- O
19 move -- -- O
20 on -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 knew -- -- O
3 General -- -- O
4 Muhammad -- -- B-PER
5 Buhari -- -- I-PER
6 ’ -- -- O
7 s -- -- O
8 antecedents -- -- O
9 and -- -- O
10 track -- -- O
11 record -- -- O
12 , -- -- O
13 that -- -- O
14 of -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 upright -- -- O
17 , -- -- O
18 somewhat -- -- O
19 rigid -- -- O
20 no-nonsense -- -- O
21 former -- -- O
22 military -- -- O
23 man -- -- O
24 who -- -- O
25 did -- -- O
26 not -- -- O
27 compromise -- -- O
28 his -- -- O
29 values -- -- O
30 or -- -- O
31 his -- -- O
32 integrity -- -- O
33 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 had -- -- O
3 always -- -- O
4 run -- -- O
5 on -- -- O
6 an -- -- O
7 anti-corruption -- -- O
8 campaign -- -- O
9 platform -- -- O
10 with -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 aura -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 someone -- -- O
15 who -- -- O
16 did -- -- O
17 not -- -- O
18 mind -- -- O
19 to -- -- O
20 go -- -- O
21 it -- -- O
22 alone -- -- O
23 if -- -- O
24 that -- -- O
25 was -- -- O
26 what -- -- O
27 was -- -- O
28 required -- -- O
29 of -- -- O
30 him -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 admired -- -- O
3 that -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 but -- -- O
6 I -- -- O
7 was -- -- O
8 not -- -- O
9 convinced -- -- O
10 that -- -- O
11 was -- -- O
12 all -- -- O
13 that -- -- O
14 was -- -- O
15 required -- -- O
16 for -- -- O
17 me -- -- O
18 to -- -- O
19 give -- -- O
20 him -- -- O
21 my -- -- O
22 vote -- -- O
23 . -- -- O

1 Especially -- -- O
2 not -- -- O
3 after -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 massacre -- -- O
6 that -- -- O
7 took -- -- O
8 place -- -- O
9 during -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 2011 -- -- O
12 elections -- -- O
13 and -- -- O
14 all -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 inciting -- -- O
17 statements -- -- O
18 that -- -- O
19 were -- -- O
20 attributed -- -- O
21 to -- -- O
22 him -- -- O
23 . -- -- O

1 Up -- -- O
2 until -- -- O
3 February -- -- O
4 8th -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 I -- -- O
7 had -- -- O
8 not -- -- O
9 decided -- -- O
10 whom -- -- O
11 I -- -- O
12 would -- -- O
13 vote -- -- O
14 or -- -- O
15 rather -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 I -- -- O
18 had -- -- O
19 decided -- -- O
20 I -- -- O
21 would -- -- O
22 vote -- -- O
23 neither -- -- O
24 Buhari -- -- B-PER
25 nor -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 incumbent -- -- O
28 , -- -- O
29 President -- -- O
30 Goodluck -- -- B-PER
31 Jonathan -- -- I-PER
32 but -- -- O
33 I -- -- O
34 did -- -- O
35 not -- -- O
36 have -- -- O
37 any -- -- O
38 other -- -- O
39 candidate -- -- O
40 . -- -- O

1 Sometimes -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 I -- -- O
4 toyed -- -- O
5 with -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 idea -- -- O
8 of -- -- O
9 voting -- -- O
10 Oluremi -- -- B-PER
11 Sonaiya -- -- I-PER
12 of -- -- O
13 KOWA -- -- B-ORG
14 Party -- -- O
15 but -- -- O
16 I -- -- O
17 did -- -- O
18 not -- -- O
19 know -- -- O
20 her -- -- O
21 track -- -- O
22 record -- -- O
23 . -- -- O

1 As -- -- O
2 for -- -- O
3 Jonathan -- -- B-PER
4 , -- -- O
5 I -- -- O
6 did -- -- O
7 not -- -- O
8 vote -- -- O
9 him -- -- O
10 in -- -- O
11 2011 -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 it -- -- O
14 felt -- -- O
15 like -- -- O
16 in -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 4 -- -- O
19 years -- -- O
20 since -- -- O
21 then -- -- O
22 he -- -- O
23 had -- -- O
24 proven -- -- O
25 why -- -- O
26 I -- -- O
27 thought -- -- O
28 it -- -- O
29 was -- -- O
30 a -- -- O
31 bad -- -- O
32 idea -- -- O
33 to -- -- O
34 not -- -- O
35 vote -- -- O
36 him -- -- O
37 . -- -- O

1 From -- -- O
2 mismanaging -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 economy -- -- O
5 to -- -- O
6 mishandling -- -- O
7 that -- -- O
8 nation -- -- O
9 ’ -- -- O
10 s -- -- O
11 security -- -- O
12 challenges -- -- O
13 , -- -- O
14 Jonathan -- -- B-PER
15 has -- -- O
16 proven -- -- O
17 himself -- -- O
18 to -- -- O
19 be -- -- O
20 an -- -- O
21 incompetent -- -- O
22 leader -- -- O
23 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 abduction -- -- O
3 of -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 Chibok -- -- B-GPE
6 girls -- -- O
7 and -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 loss -- -- O
10 of -- -- O
11 Nigeria -- -- B-GPE
12 ’ -- -- O
13 s -- -- O
14 territories -- -- O
15 to -- -- O
16 insurgency -- -- O
17 due -- -- O
18 to -- -- O
19 mostly -- -- O
20 a -- -- O
21 lack -- -- O
22 of -- -- O
23 political -- -- O
24 will -- -- O
25 to -- -- O
26 tackle -- -- O
27 it -- -- O
28 convinced -- -- O
29 me -- -- O
30 that -- -- O
31 Jonathan -- -- B-PER
32 does -- -- O
33 not -- -- O
34 have -- -- O
35 what -- -- O
36 it -- -- O
37 takes -- -- O
38 to -- -- O
39 remain -- -- O
40 president -- -- O
41 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 have -- -- O
3 a -- -- O
4 5 -- -- O
5 year-old -- -- O
6 somewhat -- -- O
7 precocious -- -- O
8 daughter -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 she -- -- O
11 has -- -- O
12 a -- -- O
13 mouth -- -- O
14 on -- -- O
15 her -- -- O
16 . -- -- O

1 Recently -- -- O
2 whilst -- -- O
3 we -- -- O
4 were -- -- O
5 driving -- -- O
6 somewhere -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 Kaline -- -- B-PER
9 ’ -- -- O
10 s -- -- O
11 song -- -- O
12 ‘ -- -- O
13 Bring -- -- O
14 Them -- -- O
15 Home -- -- O
16 ’ -- -- O
17 ( -- -- O
18 a -- -- O
19 tribute -- -- O
20 to -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 Chibok -- -- B-GPE
23 girls -- -- O
24 ) -- -- O
25 came -- -- O
26 on -- -- O
27 the -- -- O
28 radio -- -- O
29 . -- -- O

1 My -- -- O
2 daughter -- -- O
3 said -- -- O
4 to -- -- O
5 me -- -- O
6 somberly -- -- O
7 , -- -- O

1 ‘ -- -- O
2 Mommy -- -- B-PER
3 , -- -- O
4 if -- -- O
5 somebody -- -- O
6 took -- -- O
7 me -- -- O
8 away -- -- O
9 from -- -- O
10 you -- -- O
11 , -- -- O
12 I -- -- O
13 would -- -- O
14 miss -- -- O
15 you -- -- O
16 so -- -- O
17 much -- -- O
18 ? -- -- O
19 ’ -- -- O

1 It -- -- O
2 saddened -- -- O
3 me -- -- O
4 that -- -- O
5 Nigeria -- -- B-GPE
6 had -- -- O
7 become -- -- O
8 a -- -- O
9 country -- -- O
10 where -- -- O
11 a -- -- O
12 5 -- -- O
13 year-old -- -- O
14 could -- -- O
15 live -- -- O
16 under -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 apprehension -- -- O
19 that -- -- O
20 some -- -- O
21 unknown -- -- O
22 persons -- -- O
23 could -- -- O
24 come -- -- O
25 steal -- -- O
26 her -- -- O
27 away -- -- O
28 from -- -- O
29 her -- -- O
30 family -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 Who -- -- O
2 should -- -- O
3 get -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 blame -- -- O
6 for -- -- O
7 that -- -- O
8 if -- -- O
9 not -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 nation -- -- O
12 ’ -- -- O
13 s -- -- O
14 chief -- -- O
15 security -- -- O
16 officer -- -- O
17 , -- -- O
18 Dr -- -- O
19 Goodluck -- -- B-PER
20 Ebele -- -- I-PER
21 Jonathan -- -- I-PER
22 ? -- -- O

1 On -- -- O
2 top -- -- O
3 of -- -- O
4 all -- -- O
5 of -- -- O
6 this -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 to -- -- O
9 me -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 biggest -- -- O
12 testament -- -- O
13 to -- -- O
14 Jonathan -- -- B-PER
15 ’ -- -- O
16 s -- -- O
17 failure -- -- O
18 as -- -- O
19 a -- -- O
20 president -- -- O
21 is -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 fact -- -- O
24 that -- -- O
25 Buhari -- -- B-PER
26 has -- -- O
27 become -- -- O
28 a -- -- O
29 viable -- -- O
30 alternative -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 However -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 Buhari -- -- B-PER
4 has -- -- O
5 not -- -- O
6 just -- -- O
7 become -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 viable -- -- O
10 alternative -- -- O
11 because -- -- O
12 of -- -- O
13 Jonathan -- -- B-PER
14 ’ -- -- O
15 s -- -- O
16 incompetence -- -- O
17 but -- -- O
18 also -- -- O
19 because -- -- O
20 this -- -- O
21 time -- -- O
22 he -- -- O
23 has -- -- O
24 aligned -- -- O
25 himself -- -- O
26 with -- -- O
27 a -- -- O
28 competent -- -- O
29 , -- -- O
30 accomplished -- -- O
31 team -- -- O
32 . -- -- O

1 His -- -- O
2 campaign -- -- O
3 team -- -- O
4 has -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 right -- -- O
7 mix -- -- O
8 of -- -- O
9 technocrats -- -- O
10 and -- -- O
11 politicians -- -- O
12 . -- -- O

1 His -- -- O
2 choice -- -- O
3 of -- -- O
4 Professor -- -- O
5 Yemi -- -- B-PER
6 Osinbajo -- -- I-PER
7 , -- -- O
8 Professor -- -- O
9 of -- -- O
10 Law -- -- O
11 and -- -- O
12 a -- -- O
13 former -- -- O
14 attorney -- -- O
15 general -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 Lagos -- -- B-GPE
18 , -- -- O
19 as -- -- O
20 vice -- -- O
21 presidential -- -- O
22 candidate -- -- O
23 speaks -- -- O
24 volumes -- -- O
25 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 first -- -- O
3 time -- -- O
4 I -- -- O
5 encountered -- -- O
6 Osinbajo -- -- B-PER
7 was -- -- O
8 in -- -- O
9 March -- -- O
10 2013 -- -- O
11 when -- -- O
12 he -- -- O
13 held -- -- O
14 a -- -- O
15 meeting -- -- O
16 with -- -- O
17 some -- -- O
18 social -- -- O
19 media -- -- O
20 influencers -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 spoke -- -- O
3 so -- -- O
4 eloquently -- -- O
5 about -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 APC -- -- B-ORG
8 ’ -- -- O
9 s -- -- O
10 plans -- -- O
11 and -- -- O
12 with -- -- O
13 a -- -- O
14 deep -- -- O
15 understanding -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 Nigeria -- -- B-GPE
18 ’ -- -- O
19 s -- -- O
20 challenges -- -- O
21 and -- -- O
22 how -- -- O
23 they -- -- O
24 could -- -- O
25 be -- -- O
26 tackled -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 left -- -- O
3 that -- -- O
4 meeting -- -- O
5 hoping -- -- O
6 he -- -- O
7 would -- -- O
8 one -- -- O
9 day -- -- O
10 be -- -- O
11 able -- -- O
12 to -- -- O
13 work -- -- O
14 for -- -- O
15 Nigeria -- -- B-GPE
16 at -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 national -- -- O
19 level -- -- O
20 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 was -- -- O
3 impressed -- -- O
4 when -- -- O
5 Buhari -- -- B-PER
6 chose -- -- O
7 him -- -- O
8 as -- -- O
9 running -- -- O
10 mate -- -- O
11 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 am -- -- O
3 not -- -- O
4 religious -- -- O
5 so -- -- O
6 my -- -- O
7 vote -- -- O
8 will -- -- O
9 not -- -- O
10 be -- -- O
11 based -- -- O
12 on -- -- O
13 religion -- -- O
14 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 am -- -- O
3 a -- -- O
4 nationalist -- -- O
5 so -- -- O
6 my -- -- O
7 vote -- -- O
8 will -- -- O
9 not -- -- O
10 be -- -- O
11 based -- -- O
12 on -- -- O
13 ethnic -- -- O
14 sentiments -- -- O
15 . -- -- O

1 Yet -- -- O
2 my -- -- O
3 vote -- -- O
4 will -- -- O
5 be -- -- O
6 based -- -- O
7 on -- -- O
8 sentiments -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 it -- -- O
11 will -- -- O
12 be -- -- O
13 based -- -- O
14 on -- -- O
15 emotions -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 on -- -- O
18 love -- -- O
19 for -- -- O
20 my -- -- O
21 country -- -- O
22 , -- -- O
23 love -- -- O
24 for -- -- O
25 my -- -- O
26 child -- -- O
27 and -- -- O
28 for -- -- O
29 myself -- -- O
30 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 do -- -- O
3 not -- -- O
4 want -- -- O
5 my -- -- O
6 beloved -- -- O
7 country -- -- O
8 to -- -- O
9 continue -- -- O
10 down -- -- O
11 this -- -- O
12 path -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 perdition -- -- O
15 , -- -- O
16 I -- -- O
17 still -- -- O
18 want -- -- O
19 my -- -- O
20 daughter -- -- O
21 to -- -- O
22 have -- -- O
23 a -- -- O
24 place -- -- O
25 she -- -- O
26 calls -- -- O
27 home -- -- O
28 20 -- -- O
29 years -- -- O
30 from -- -- O
31 now -- -- O
32 . -- -- O

1 Buhari -- -- B-PER
2 with -- -- O
3 his -- -- O
4 current -- -- O
5 team -- -- O
6 can -- -- O
7 put -- -- O
8 a -- -- O
9 stop -- -- O
10 this -- -- O
11 journey -- -- O
12 towards -- -- O
13 destruction -- -- O
14 . -- -- O

1 For -- -- O
2 this -- -- O
3 reason -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 I -- -- O
6 choose -- -- O
7 General -- -- O
8 Muhammad -- -- B-PER
9 Buhari -- -- I-PER
10 , -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 bring -- -- O
13 Nigeria -- -- B-GPE
14 back -- -- O
15 to -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 right -- -- O
18 path -- -- O
19 . -- -- O

1 UAE -- -- B-GPE
2 official -- -- O
3 warns -- -- O
4 of -- -- O
5 potential -- -- O
6 for -- -- O
7 ISIS-Shabab -- -- O
8 link -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 United -- -- B-GPE
3 Arab -- -- I-GPE
4 Emirates -- -- I-GPE
5 ' -- -- O
6 top -- -- O
7 diplomat -- -- O
8 warned -- -- O
9 Wednesday -- -- O
10 that -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 Islamic -- -- B-ORG
13 State -- -- I-ORG
14 of -- -- O
15 Iraq -- -- B-GPE
16 and -- -- O
17 Syria -- -- B-GPE
18 ( -- -- O
19 ISIS -- -- B-ORG
20 ) -- -- O
21 group -- -- O
22 could -- -- O
23 team -- -- O
24 up -- -- O
25 with -- -- O
26 Islamic -- -- O
27 militants -- -- O
28 in -- -- O
29 Somalia -- -- B-GPE
30 , -- -- O
31 saying -- -- O
32 that -- -- O
33 more -- -- O
34 should -- -- O
35 be -- -- O
36 done -- -- O
37 to -- -- O
38 prepare -- -- O
39 for -- -- O
40 such -- -- O
41 a -- -- O
42 threat -- -- O
43 . -- -- O

1 ISIS -- -- B-ORG
2 that -- -- O
3 now -- -- O
4 controls -- -- O
5 large -- -- O
6 parts -- -- O
7 of -- -- O
8 Iraq -- -- B-GPE
9 and -- -- O
10 Syria -- -- B-GPE
11 - -- -- O
12 also -- -- O
13 known -- -- O
14 by -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 Arabic -- -- O
17 acronym -- -- O
18 Daesh -- -- B-ORG
19 - -- -- O
20 and -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 Somali -- -- B-GPE
23 militant -- -- O
24 Islamic -- -- O
25 group -- -- O
26 al-Shabab -- -- B-ORG
27 share -- -- O
28 a -- -- O
29 common -- -- O
30 pedigree -- -- O
31 in -- -- O
32 that -- -- O
33 they -- -- O
34 both -- -- O
35 have -- -- O
36 had -- -- O
37 links -- -- O
38 to -- -- O
39 al-Qaeda -- -- B-ORG
40 . -- -- O

1 They -- -- O
2 frequently -- -- O
3 use -- -- O
4 similar -- -- O
5 tactics -- -- O
6 such -- -- O
7 as -- -- O
8 explosives-laden -- -- O
9 cars -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 suicide -- -- O
12 bombers -- -- O
13 and -- -- O
14 attacks -- -- O
15 on -- -- O
16 civilians -- -- O
17 . -- -- O

1 They -- -- O
2 operate -- -- O
3 independently -- -- O
4 for -- -- O
5 now -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 but -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 Emirati -- -- B-GPE
10 foreign -- -- O
11 minister -- -- O
12 , -- -- O
13 Sheik -- -- O
14 Abdullah -- -- B-PER
15 bin -- -- I-PER
16 Zayed -- -- I-PER
17 Al -- -- I-PER
18 Nahyan -- -- I-PER
19 , -- -- O
20 suggested -- -- O
21 that -- -- O
22 could -- -- O
23 change -- -- O
24 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 What -- -- O
3 really -- -- O
4 scares -- -- O
5 us -- -- O
6 now -- -- O
7 is -- -- O
8 what -- -- O
9 we -- -- O
10 see -- -- O
11 from -- -- O
12 Daesh -- -- B-ORG
13 , -- -- O
14 and -- -- O
15 are -- -- O
16 we -- -- O
17 going -- -- O
18 to -- -- O
19 see -- -- O
20 in -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 future -- -- O
23 any -- -- O
24 sort -- -- O
25 of -- -- O
26 collaboration -- -- O
27 between -- -- O
28 different -- -- O
29 terrorist -- -- O
30 groups -- -- O
31 like -- -- O
32 Daesh -- -- B-ORG
33 and -- -- O
34 al-Shabab -- -- B-ORG
35 ? -- -- O
36 " -- -- O

1 Sheik -- -- O
2 Abdullah -- -- B-PER
3 said -- -- O
4 in -- -- O
5 an -- -- O
6 address -- -- O
7 at -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 opening -- -- O
10 of -- -- O
11 a -- -- O
12 conference -- -- O
13 focused -- -- O
14 on -- -- O
15 counter-piracy -- -- O
16 in -- -- O
17 Somalia -- -- B-GPE
18 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 I -- -- O
3 think -- -- O
4 we -- -- O
5 should -- -- O
6 start -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 ask -- -- O
9 ourselves -- -- O
10 : -- -- O
11 how -- -- O
12 ready -- -- O
13 we -- -- O
14 are -- -- O
15 as -- -- O
16 countries -- -- O
17 , -- -- O
18 companies -- -- O
19 and -- -- O
20 international -- -- O
21 organizations -- -- O
22 in -- -- O
23 facing -- -- O
24 these -- -- O
25 big -- -- O
26 threats -- -- O
27 , -- -- O
28 " -- -- O
29 he -- -- O
30 added -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 Sheik -- -- O
2 Abdullah -- -- B-PER
3 did -- -- O
4 not -- -- O
5 cite -- -- O
6 any -- -- O
7 specific -- -- O
8 intelligence -- -- O
9 pointing -- -- O
10 to -- -- O
11 active -- -- O
12 collaboration -- -- O
13 between -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 groups -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 but -- -- O
18 there -- -- O
19 has -- -- O
20 been -- -- O
21 speculation -- -- O
22 that -- -- O
23 the -- -- O
24 Somali -- -- B-GPE
25 rebels -- -- O
26 would -- -- O
27 shift -- -- O
28 their -- -- O
29 allegiance -- -- O
30 from -- -- O
31 al-Qaeda -- -- B-ORG
32 to -- -- O
33 ISIS -- -- B-ORG
34 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 Emirates -- -- B-GPE
3 is -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 Western-allied -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 seven-state -- -- O
8 federation -- -- O
9 that -- -- O
10 includes -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 Gulf -- -- B-LOC
13 shipping -- -- O
14 and -- -- O
15 commercial -- -- O
16 hub -- -- O
17 of -- -- O
18 Dubai -- -- B-GPE
19 and -- -- O
20 the -- -- O
21 oil-rich -- -- O
22 capital -- -- O
23 , -- -- O
24 Abu -- -- B-GPE
25 Dhabi -- -- I-GPE
26 . -- -- O

1 It -- -- O
2 is -- -- O
3 home -- -- O
4 to -- -- O
5 a -- -- O
6 sizable -- -- O
7 Somali -- -- B-GPE
8 expatriate -- -- O
9 population -- -- O
10 and -- -- O
11 is -- -- O
12 among -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 most -- -- O
15 prominent -- -- O
16 Arab -- -- O
17 allies -- -- O
18 taking -- -- O
19 part -- -- O
20 in -- -- O
21 U.S.-led -- -- O
22 airstrikes -- -- O
23 against -- -- O
24 ISIS -- -- B-ORG
25 . -- -- O

1 Al-Shabab -- -- B-ORG
2 last -- -- O
3 month -- -- O
4 named -- -- O
5 a -- -- O
6 new -- -- O
7 leader -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 Ahmad -- -- B-PER
10 Umar -- -- I-PER
11 , -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 reaffirmed -- -- O
14 its -- -- O
15 alignment -- -- O
16 with -- -- O
17 al-Qaeda -- -- B-ORG
18 after -- -- O
19 its -- -- O
20 longtime -- -- O
21 head -- -- O
22 , -- -- O
23 Ahmed -- -- B-PER
24 Abdi -- -- I-PER
25 Godane -- -- I-PER
26 , -- -- O
27 was -- -- O
28 killed -- -- O
29 in -- -- O
30 a -- -- O
31 U.S. -- -- B-GPE
32 airstrike -- -- O
33 105 -- -- O
34 miles -- -- O
35 ( -- -- O
36 170 -- -- O
37 kilometers -- -- O
38 ) -- -- O
39 south -- -- O
40 of -- -- O
41 the -- -- O
42 Somali -- -- B-GPE
43 capital -- -- O
44 of -- -- O
45 Mogadishu -- -- B-GPE
46 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 Islamic -- -- B-ORG
3 State -- -- I-ORG
4 group -- -- O
5 itself -- -- O
6 began -- -- O
7 as -- -- O
8 an -- -- O
9 Iraqi -- -- B-GPE
10 affiliate -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 al-Qaeda -- -- B-ORG
13 , -- -- O
14 but -- -- O
15 it -- -- O
16 was -- -- O
17 kicked -- -- O
18 out -- -- O
19 of -- -- O
20 the -- -- O
21 terror -- -- O
22 network -- -- O
23 earlier -- -- O
24 this -- -- O
25 year -- -- O
26 . -- -- O

1 AP -- -- B-ORG
2 sues -- -- O
3 State -- -- B-ORG
4 Department -- -- I-ORG
5 , -- -- O
6 seeking -- -- O
7 access -- -- O
8 to -- -- O
9 Clinton -- -- B-PER
10 records -- -- O

1 The -- -- B-ORG
2 Associated -- -- I-ORG
3 Press -- -- I-ORG
4 filed -- -- O
5 a -- -- O
6 lawsuit -- -- O
7 Wednesday -- -- O
8 against -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 State -- -- B-ORG
11 Department -- -- I-ORG
12 to -- -- O
13 force -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 release -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 email -- -- O
18 correspondence -- -- O
19 and -- -- O
20 government -- -- O
21 documents -- -- O
22 from -- -- O
23 Hillary -- -- B-PER
24 Rodham -- -- I-PER
25 Clinton -- -- I-PER
26 's -- -- O
27 tenure -- -- O
28 as -- -- O
29 secretary -- -- O
30 of -- -- O
31 state -- -- O
32 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 legal -- -- O
3 action -- -- O
4 comes -- -- O
5 after -- -- O
6 repeated -- -- O
7 requests -- -- O
8 filed -- -- O
9 under -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 U.S. -- -- B-GPE
12 Freedom -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 Information -- -- O
15 Act -- -- O
16 have -- -- O
17 gone -- -- O
18 unfulfilled -- -- O
19 . -- -- O

1 They -- -- O
2 include -- -- O
3 one -- -- O
4 request -- -- O
5 AP -- -- B-ORG
6 made -- -- O
7 five -- -- O
8 years -- -- O
9 ago -- -- O
10 and -- -- O
11 others -- -- O
12 pending -- -- O
13 since -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 summer -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 2013 -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 FOIA -- -- O
3 requests -- -- O
4 and -- -- O
5 lawsuit -- -- O
6 seek -- -- O
7 materials -- -- O
8 related -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 her -- -- O
11 public -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 private -- -- O
14 calendars -- -- O
15 , -- -- O
16 correspondence -- -- O
17 involving -- -- O
18 longtime -- -- O
19 aides -- -- O
20 likely -- -- O
21 to -- -- O
22 play -- -- O
23 key -- -- O
24 roles -- -- O
25 in -- -- O
26 her -- -- O
27 expected -- -- O
28 campaign -- -- O
29 for -- -- O
30 president -- -- O
31 , -- -- O
32 and -- -- O
33 Clinton-related -- -- O
34 emails -- -- O
35 about -- -- O
36 the -- -- O
37 Osama -- -- B-PER
38 bin -- -- I-PER
39 Laden -- -- I-PER
40 raid -- -- O
41 and -- -- O
42 National -- -- B-ORG
43 Security -- -- I-ORG
44 Agency -- -- I-ORG
45 surveillance -- -- O
46 practices -- -- O
47 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 After -- -- O
3 careful -- -- O
4 deliberation -- -- O
5 and -- -- O
6 exhausting -- -- O
7 our -- -- O
8 other -- -- O
9 options -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 The -- -- B-ORG
12 Associated -- -- I-ORG
13 Press -- -- I-ORG
14 is -- -- O
15 taking -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 necessary -- -- O
18 legal -- -- O
19 steps -- -- O
20 to -- -- O
21 gain -- -- O
22 access -- -- O
23 to -- -- O
24 these -- -- O
25 important -- -- O
26 documents -- -- O
27 , -- -- O
28 which -- -- O
29 will -- -- O
30 shed -- -- O
31 light -- -- O
32 on -- -- O
33 actions -- -- O
34 by -- -- O
35 the -- -- O
36 State -- -- B-ORG
37 Department -- -- I-ORG
38 and -- -- O
39 former -- -- O
40 Secretary -- -- O
41 Clinton -- -- B-PER
42 , -- -- O
43 a -- -- O
44 presumptive -- -- O
45 2016 -- -- O
46 presidential -- -- O
47 candidate -- -- O
48 , -- -- O
49 during -- -- O
50 some -- -- O
51 of -- -- O
52 the -- -- O
53 most -- -- O
54 significant -- -- O
55 issues -- -- O
56 of -- -- O
57 our -- -- O
58 time -- -- O
59 , -- -- O
60 " -- -- O
61 said -- -- O
62 Karen -- -- B-PER
63 Kaiser -- -- I-PER
64 , -- -- O
65 AP -- -- B-ORG
66 's -- -- O
67 general -- -- O
68 counsel -- -- O
69 . -- -- O

1 Said -- -- O
2 AP -- -- B-ORG
3 Executive -- -- O
4 Editor -- -- O
5 Kathleen -- -- B-PER
6 Carroll -- -- I-PER
7 , -- -- O
8 " -- -- O
9 The -- -- O
10 Freedom -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 Information -- -- O
13 Act -- -- O
14 exists -- -- O
15 to -- -- O
16 give -- -- O
17 citizens -- -- O
18 a -- -- O
19 clear -- -- O
20 view -- -- O
21 of -- -- O
22 what -- -- O
23 government -- -- O
24 officials -- -- O
25 are -- -- O
26 doing -- -- O
27 on -- -- O
28 their -- -- O
29 behalf -- -- O
30 . -- -- O

1 When -- -- O
2 that -- -- O
3 view -- -- O
4 is -- -- O
5 denied -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 next -- -- O
9 resort -- -- O
10 is -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 courts -- -- O
13 . -- -- O
14 " -- -- O

1 State -- -- B-ORG
2 Department -- -- I-ORG
3 spokesman -- -- O
4 Alec -- -- B-PER
5 Gerlach -- -- I-PER
6 declined -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 comment -- -- O
9 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 had -- -- O
3 previously -- -- O
4 cited -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 department -- -- B-ORG
7 's -- -- O
8 heavy -- -- O
9 annual -- -- O
10 load -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 FOIA -- -- O
13 requests -- -- O
14 — -- -- O
15 19,000 -- -- O
16 last -- -- O
17 year -- -- O
18 — -- -- O
19 in -- -- O
20 saying -- -- O
21 that -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 department -- -- B-ORG
24 " -- -- O
25 does -- -- O
26 its -- -- O
27 best -- -- O
28 to -- -- O
29 meet -- -- O
30 its -- -- O
31 FOIA -- -- O
32 responsibilities -- -- O
33 . -- -- O
34 " -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 said -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 department -- -- B-ORG
5 takes -- -- O
6 requests -- -- O
7 " -- -- O
8 first -- -- O
9 in -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 first -- -- O
12 out -- -- O
13 , -- -- O
14 " -- -- O
15 but -- -- O
16 noted -- -- O
17 that -- -- O
18 timing -- -- O
19 depends -- -- O
20 on -- -- O
21 " -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 complexity -- -- O
24 of -- -- O
25 the -- -- O
26 request -- -- O
27 . -- -- O
28 " -- -- O

1 Carroll -- -- B-PER
2 said -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 AP -- -- B-ORG
5 intends -- -- O
6 to -- -- O
7 file -- -- O
8 additional -- -- O
9 requests -- -- O
10 using -- -- O
11 FOIA -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 other -- -- O
14 tools -- -- O
15 following -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 disclosure -- -- O
18 last -- -- O
19 week -- -- O
20 that -- -- O
21 Clinton -- -- B-PER
22 used -- -- O
23 a -- -- O
24 private -- -- O
25 email -- -- O
26 account -- -- O
27 run -- -- O
28 on -- -- O
29 a -- -- O
30 server -- -- O
31 on -- -- O
32 her -- -- O
33 property -- -- O
34 outside -- -- O
35 New -- -- B-GPE
36 York -- -- I-GPE
37 while -- -- O
38 working -- -- O
39 at -- -- O
40 the -- -- O
41 State -- -- B-ORG
42 Department -- -- I-ORG
43 . -- -- O

1 Clinton -- -- B-PER
2 on -- -- O
3 Tuesday -- -- O
4 said -- -- O
5 she -- -- O
6 sent -- -- O
7 and -- -- O
8 received -- -- O
9 about -- -- O
10 60,000 -- -- O
11 emails -- -- O
12 from -- -- O
13 her -- -- O
14 personal -- -- O
15 email -- -- O
16 address -- -- O
17 in -- -- O
18 her -- -- O
19 four -- -- O
20 years -- -- O
21 as -- -- O
22 President -- -- O
23 Barack -- -- B-PER
24 Obama -- -- I-PER
25 's -- -- O
26 secretary -- -- O
27 of -- -- O
28 state -- -- O
29 . -- -- O

1 She -- -- O
2 said -- -- O
3 roughly -- -- O
4 half -- -- O
5 were -- -- O
6 work-related -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 which -- -- O
9 she -- -- O
10 turned -- -- O
11 over -- -- O
12 to -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 State -- -- B-ORG
15 Department -- -- I-ORG
16 , -- -- O
17 while -- -- O
18 deleting -- -- O
19 tens -- -- O
20 of -- -- O
21 thousands -- -- O
22 more -- -- O
23 that -- -- O
24 were -- -- O
25 personal -- -- O
26 in -- -- O
27 nature -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 department -- -- B-ORG
3 says -- -- O
4 it -- -- O
5 will -- -- O
6 take -- -- O
7 several -- -- O
8 months -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 review -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 material -- -- O
13 Clinton -- -- B-PER
14 turned -- -- O
15 over -- -- O
16 last -- -- O
17 year -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 Once -- -- O
2 the -- -- O
3 review -- -- O
4 is -- -- O
5 complete -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 department -- -- B-ORG
9 said -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 emails -- -- O
13 will -- -- O
14 be -- -- O
15 posted -- -- O
16 online -- -- O
17 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 AP -- -- B-ORG
3 had -- -- O
4 sought -- -- O
5 Clinton-related -- -- O
6 correspondence -- -- O
7 before -- -- O
8 her -- -- O
9 use -- -- O
10 of -- -- O
11 a -- -- O
12 personal -- -- O
13 email -- -- O
14 account -- -- O
15 was -- -- O
16 publicly -- -- O
17 known -- -- O
18 , -- -- O
19 although -- -- O
20 Wednesday -- -- O
21 's -- -- O
22 court -- -- O
23 filing -- -- O
24 alleges -- -- O
25 that -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 State -- -- B-ORG
28 Department -- -- I-ORG
29 is -- -- O
30 responsible -- -- O
31 for -- -- O
32 including -- -- O
33 emails -- -- O
34 from -- -- O
35 that -- -- O
36 account -- -- O
37 in -- -- O
38 any -- -- O
39 public -- -- O
40 records -- -- O
41 request -- -- O
42 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 State -- -- B-ORG
3 's -- -- O
4 failure -- -- O
5 to -- -- O
6 ensure -- -- O
7 that -- -- O
8 Secretary -- -- O
9 Clinton -- -- B-PER
10 's -- -- O
11 governmental -- -- O
12 emails -- -- O
13 were -- -- O
14 retained -- -- O
15 and -- -- O
16 preserved -- -- O
17 by -- -- O
18 the -- -- O
19 agency -- -- O
20 , -- -- O
21 and -- -- O
22 its -- -- O
23 failure -- -- O
24 timely -- -- O
25 to -- -- O
26 seek -- -- O
27 out -- -- O
28 and -- -- O
29 search -- -- O
30 those -- -- O
31 emails -- -- O
32 in -- -- O
33 response -- -- O
34 to -- -- O
35 AP -- -- B-ORG
36 's -- -- O
37 requests -- -- O
38 , -- -- O
39 indicate -- -- O
40 at -- -- O
41 the -- -- O
42 very -- -- O
43 least -- -- O
44 that -- -- O
45 State -- -- B-ORG
46 has -- -- O
47 not -- -- O
48 engaged -- -- O
49 in -- -- O
50 the -- -- O
51 diligent -- -- O
52 , -- -- O
53 good-faith -- -- O
54 search -- -- O
55 that -- -- O
56 FOIA -- -- O
57 requires -- -- O
58 , -- -- O
59 " -- -- O
60 says -- -- O
61 AP -- -- B-ORG
62 's -- -- O
63 legal -- -- O
64 filing -- -- O
65 . -- -- O

1 Specifically -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 AP -- -- B-ORG
4 is -- -- O
5 seeking -- -- O
6 copies -- -- O
7 of -- -- O
8 Clinton -- -- B-PER
9 's -- -- O
10 full -- -- O
11 schedules -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 calendars -- -- O
14 from -- -- O
15 her -- -- O
16 four -- -- O
17 years -- -- O
18 as -- -- O
19 secretary -- -- O
20 of -- -- O
21 state -- -- O
22 ; -- -- O
23 documents -- -- O
24 related -- -- O
25 to -- -- O
26 her -- -- O
27 department -- -- B-ORG
28 's -- -- O
29 decision -- -- O
30 to -- -- O
31 grant -- -- O
32 a -- -- O
33 special -- -- O
34 position -- -- O
35 to -- -- O
36 longtime -- -- O
37 aide -- -- O
38 Huma -- -- B-PER
39 Abedin -- -- I-PER
40 ; -- -- O
41 related -- -- O
42 correspondence -- -- O
43 from -- -- O
44 longtime -- -- O
45 advisers -- -- O
46 Philippe -- -- B-PER
47 Reines -- -- I-PER
48 and -- -- O
49 Cheryl -- -- B-PER
50 Mills -- -- I-PER
51 , -- -- O
52 who -- -- O
53 , -- -- O
54 like -- -- O
55 Abedin -- -- B-PER
56 , -- -- O
57 are -- -- O
58 likely -- -- O
59 to -- -- O
60 play -- -- O
61 central -- -- O
62 roles -- -- O
63 in -- -- O
64 a -- -- O
65 Clinton -- -- B-PER
66 presidential -- -- O
67 campaign -- -- O
68 ; -- -- O
69 documents -- -- O
70 related -- -- O
71 to -- -- O
72 Clinton -- -- B-PER
73 's -- -- O
74 and -- -- O
75 the -- -- O
76 agency -- -- O
77 's -- -- O
78 roles -- -- O
79 in -- -- O
80 the -- -- O
81 Osama -- -- B-PER
82 bin -- -- I-PER
83 Laden -- -- I-PER
84 raid -- -- O
85 and -- -- O
86 National -- -- B-ORG
87 Security -- -- I-ORG
88 Agency -- -- I-ORG
89 surveillance -- -- O
90 practices -- -- O
91 ; -- -- O
92 and -- -- O
93 documents -- -- O
94 related -- -- O
95 to -- -- O
96 her -- -- O
97 role -- -- O
98 overseeing -- -- O
99 a -- -- O
100 major -- -- O
101 Defense -- -- B-ORG
102 Department -- -- I-ORG
103 contractor -- -- O
104 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 AP -- -- B-ORG
3 made -- -- O
4 most -- -- O
5 of -- -- O
6 its -- -- O
7 requests -- -- O
8 in -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 summer -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 2013 -- -- O
13 , -- -- O
14 although -- -- O
15 one -- -- O
16 was -- -- O
17 filed -- -- O
18 in -- -- O
19 March -- -- O
20 2010 -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 AP -- -- B-ORG
2 is -- -- O
3 also -- -- O
4 seeking -- -- O
5 attorney -- -- O
6 's -- -- O
7 fees -- -- O
8 related -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 lawsuit -- -- O
12 . -- -- O

1 Other -- -- O
2 organizations -- -- O
3 have -- -- O
4 also -- -- O
5 sued -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 State -- -- B-ORG
8 Department -- -- I-ORG
9 recently -- -- O
10 after -- -- O
11 lengthy -- -- O
12 delays -- -- O
13 responding -- -- O
14 to -- -- O
15 public -- -- O
16 record -- -- O
17 requests -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 In -- -- O
2 December -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 conservative -- -- O
6 political -- -- O
7 advocacy -- -- O
8 group -- -- O
9 Citizens -- -- B-ORG
10 United -- -- I-ORG
11 sued -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 State -- -- B-ORG
14 Department -- -- I-ORG
15 for -- -- O
16 failing -- -- O
17 to -- -- O
18 disclose -- -- O
19 flight -- -- O
20 records -- -- O
21 showing -- -- O
22 who -- -- O
23 accompanied -- -- O
24 Clinton -- -- B-PER
25 on -- -- O
26 overseas -- -- O
27 trips -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

1 Last -- -- O
2 week -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 National -- -- B-ORG
6 Security -- -- I-ORG
7 Archive -- -- I-ORG
8 , -- -- O
9 an -- -- O
10 organization -- -- O
11 that -- -- O
12 gathers -- -- O
13 declassified -- -- O
14 government -- -- O
15 records -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 filed -- -- O
18 a -- -- O
19 lawsuit -- -- O
20 after -- -- O
21 waiting -- -- O
22 more -- -- O
23 than -- -- O
24 seven -- -- O
25 years -- -- O
26 for -- -- O
27 the -- -- O
28 State -- -- B-ORG
29 Department -- -- I-ORG
30 to -- -- O
31 release -- -- O
32 of -- -- O
33 details -- -- O
34 of -- -- O
35 former -- -- O
36 secretary -- -- O
37 of -- -- O
38 state -- -- O
39 Henry -- -- B-PER
40 Kissinger -- -- I-PER
41 's -- -- O
42 telephone -- -- O
43 conversations -- -- O
44 . -- -- O

1 Thomas -- -- B-PER
2 Blanton -- -- I-PER
3 , -- -- O
4 director -- -- O
5 of -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 National -- -- B-ORG
8 Security -- -- I-ORG
9 Archive -- -- I-ORG
10 , -- -- O
11 predicted -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 State -- -- B-ORG
14 Department -- -- I-ORG
15 would -- -- O
16 speed -- -- O
17 up -- -- O
18 its -- -- O
19 review -- -- O
20 facing -- -- O
21 legal -- -- O
22 action -- -- O
23 , -- -- O
24 particularly -- -- O
25 given -- -- O
26 that -- -- O
27 Clinton -- -- B-PER
28 has -- -- O
29 said -- -- O
30 that -- -- O
31 her -- -- O
32 email -- -- O
33 correspondence -- -- O
34 doesn -- -- O
35 't -- -- O
36 include -- -- O
37 classified -- -- O
38 material -- -- O
39 . -- -- O

1 " -- -- O
2 When -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 government -- -- O
5 is -- -- O
6 under -- -- O
7 a -- -- O
8 court -- -- O
9 deadline -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 or -- -- O
12 really -- -- O
13 wants -- -- O
14 to -- -- O
15 review -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 they -- -- O
18 can -- -- O
19 whip -- -- O
20 through -- -- O
21 thousands -- -- O
22 of -- -- O
23 pages -- -- O
24 in -- -- O
25 a -- -- O
26 matter -- -- O
27 of -- -- O
28 weeks -- -- O
29 , -- -- O
30 which -- -- O
31 they -- -- O
32 should -- -- O
33 do -- -- O
34 here -- -- O
35 , -- -- O
36 " -- -- O
37 Blanton -- -- B-PER
38 said -- -- O
39 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 State -- -- B-ORG
3 Department -- -- I-ORG
4 generally -- -- O
5 takes -- -- O
6 about -- -- O
7 450 -- -- O
8 days -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 turn -- -- O
11 over -- -- O
12 records -- -- O
13 it -- -- O
14 considers -- -- O
15 to -- -- O
16 be -- -- O
17 part -- -- O
18 of -- -- O
19 complex -- -- O
20 requests -- -- O
21 under -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 Freedom -- -- O
24 of -- -- O
25 Information -- -- O
26 Act -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 is -- -- O
3 seven -- -- O
4 times -- -- O
5 longer -- -- O
6 than -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 Justice -- -- B-ORG
9 Department -- -- I-ORG
10 and -- -- O
11 CIA -- -- B-ORG
12 , -- -- O
13 and -- -- O
14 30 -- -- O
15 times -- -- O
16 longer -- -- O
17 than -- -- O
18 the -- -- O
19 Treasury -- -- B-ORG
20 Department -- -- I-ORG
21 . -- -- O

1 An -- -- O
2 inspector -- -- O
3 general -- -- O
4 's -- -- O
5 report -- -- O
6 in -- -- O
7 2012 -- -- O
8 criticized -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 State -- -- B-ORG
11 Department -- -- I-ORG
12 's -- -- O
13 practices -- -- O
14 as -- -- O
15 " -- -- O
16 inefficient -- -- O
17 and -- -- O
18 ineffective -- -- O
19 , -- -- O
20 " -- -- O
21 citing -- -- O
22 a -- -- O
23 heavy -- -- O
24 workload -- -- O
25 , -- -- O
26 small -- -- O
27 staff -- -- O
28 and -- -- O
29 interagency -- -- O
30 problems -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 Slain -- -- O
2 Russian -- -- B-GPE
3 ’ -- -- O
4 s -- -- O
5 Complicated -- -- O
6 Romantic -- -- O
7 Life -- -- O
8 May -- -- O
9 Be -- -- O
10 Key -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 Case -- -- O

1 Boris -- -- B-PER
2 Nemtsov -- -- I-PER
3 's -- -- O
4 tangled -- -- O
5 love -- -- O
6 life -- -- O
7 is -- -- O
8 revealed -- -- O
9 as -- -- O
10 model -- -- O
11 Anna -- -- B-PER
12 Duritskaya -- -- I-PER
13 helps -- -- O
14 police -- -- O
15 piece -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 puzzle -- -- O
18 together -- -- O

1 Ukrainian -- -- B-GPE
2 model -- -- O
3 Anna -- -- B-PER
4 Duritskaya -- -- I-PER
5 became -- -- O
6 a -- -- O
7 witness -- -- O
8 to -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 murder -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 prominent -- -- O
14 Russian -- -- B-GPE
15 opposition -- -- O
16 leader -- -- O
17 55-year-old -- -- O
18 Boris -- -- B-PER
19 Nemtsov -- -- I-PER
20 , -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 charismatic -- -- O
23 opposition -- -- O
24 figure -- -- O
25 and -- -- O
26 critic -- -- O
27 of -- -- O
28 President -- -- O
29 Vladimir -- -- B-PER
30 Putin -- -- I-PER
31 who -- -- O
32 was -- -- O
33 shot -- -- O
34 earlier -- -- O
35 today -- -- O
36 . -- -- O

1 Ms. -- -- O
2 Duritskaya -- -- B-PER
3 , -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 23-year-old -- -- O
6 Ukrainian -- -- B-GPE
7 citizen -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 was -- -- O
10 being -- -- O
11 interrogated -- -- O
12 by -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 police -- -- O
15 all -- -- O
16 night -- -- O
17 tonight -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 According -- -- O
2 to -- -- O
3 a -- -- O
4 source -- -- O
5 in -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 Russian -- -- B-GPE
8 police -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 young -- -- O
12 woman -- -- O
13 had -- -- O
14 “ -- -- O
15 a -- -- O
16 very -- -- O
17 close -- -- O
18 personal -- -- O
19 romantic -- -- O
20 relationship -- -- O
21 ” -- -- O
22 with -- -- O
23 the -- -- O
24 murdered -- -- O
25 politician -- -- O
26 , -- -- O
27 says -- -- O
28 TV -- -- O
29 program -- -- O
30 Vesti -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 relationship -- -- O
3 is -- -- O
4 already -- -- O
5 four -- -- O
6 years -- -- O
7 old -- -- O
8 — -- -- O
9 since -- -- O
10 she -- -- O
11 was -- -- O
12 19 -- -- O
13 years-old -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 in -- -- O
16 other -- -- O
17 words -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 Thanks -- -- O
2 to -- -- O
3 Ms. -- -- O
4 Duritskaya -- -- B-PER
5 , -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 police -- -- O
8 have -- -- O
9 been -- -- O
10 able -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 establish -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 chronology -- -- O
15 of -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 events -- -- O
18 of -- -- O
19 this -- -- O
20 tragic -- -- O
21 night -- -- O
22 . -- -- O

1 According -- -- O
2 to -- -- O
3 her -- -- O
4 account -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 she -- -- O
7 was -- -- O
8 waiting -- -- O
9 for -- -- O
10 Mr. -- -- O
11 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
12 since -- -- O
13 10 -- -- O
14 p.m. -- -- O
15 at -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 Bosco-café -- -- B-FAC
18 of -- -- O
19 the -- -- O
20 GUM -- -- B-FAC
21 shopping -- -- O
22 mall -- -- O
23 at -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 Red -- -- B-LOC
26 Square -- -- I-LOC
27 right -- -- O
28 across -- -- O
29 the -- -- O
30 Kremlin -- -- B-FAC
31 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 couple -- -- O
3 had -- -- O
4 dinner -- -- O
5 at -- -- O
6 around -- -- O
7 11 -- -- O
8 p.m. -- -- O

1 Moscow -- -- B-GPE
2 time -- -- O
3 and -- -- O
4 then -- -- O
5 left -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 mall -- -- O
8 and -- -- O
9 went -- -- O
10 for -- -- O
11 a -- -- O
12 walk -- -- O
13 toward -- -- O
14 Vasilievsky -- -- B-LOC
15 embankment -- -- I-LOC
16 right -- -- O
17 by -- -- O
18 the -- -- O
19 Kremlin -- -- B-FAC
20 walls -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 Their -- -- O
2 intended -- -- O
3 destination -- -- O
4 was -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 posh -- -- O
7 building -- -- O
8 half -- -- O
9 a -- -- O
10 mile -- -- O
11 away -- -- O
12 from -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 Kremlin -- -- B-FAC
15 where -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 murdered -- -- O
18 politician -- -- O
19 had -- -- O
20 an -- -- O
21 apartment -- -- O
22 . -- -- O

1 As -- -- O
2 they -- -- O
3 were -- -- O
4 crossing -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 Big -- -- B-FAC
7 New-Moskva -- -- I-FAC
8 Bridge -- -- I-FAC
9 , -- -- O
10 an -- -- O
11 unidentified -- -- O
12 man -- -- O
13 ran -- -- O
14 out -- -- O
15 of -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 underpass -- -- O
18 of -- -- O
19 the -- -- O
20 bridge -- -- O
21 and -- -- O
22 shot -- -- O
23 Mr. -- -- O
24 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
25 multiple -- -- O
26 times -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 Then -- -- O
2 he -- -- O
3 jumped -- -- O
4 into -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 passing -- -- O
7 white -- -- O
8 car -- -- O
9 without -- -- O
10 a -- -- O
11 license -- -- O
12 plate -- -- O
13 . -- -- O

1 Mr. -- -- O
2 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
3 died -- -- O
4 on -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 scene -- -- O
7 . -- -- O

1 According -- -- O
2 to -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 Speaker -- -- O
5 for -- -- O
6 Prosecutor -- -- B-ORG
7 General -- -- I-ORG
8 Office -- -- I-ORG
9 , -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 “ -- -- O
12 Ukrainian -- -- B-GPE
13 trace -- -- O
14 ” -- -- O
15 of -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 brazen -- -- O
18 murder -- -- O
19 is -- -- O
20 one -- -- O
21 possible -- -- O
22 motive -- -- O
23 of -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 crime -- -- O
26 because -- -- O
27 of -- -- O
28 Ms. -- -- O
29 Duritskaya -- -- B-PER
30 ’ -- -- O
31 s -- -- O
32 origin -- -- O
33 and -- -- O
34 recent -- -- O
35 arrival -- -- O
36 from -- -- O
37 Kiev -- -- B-GPE
38 . -- -- O

1 Other -- -- O
2 motives -- -- O
3 include -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 hit -- -- O
6 by -- -- O
7 his -- -- O
8 political -- -- O
9 enemies -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 including -- -- O
12 Russian -- -- B-GPE
13 nationalists -- -- O
14 and -- -- O
15 Islamic -- -- O
16 terrorists -- -- O
17 ; -- -- O
18 business -- -- O
19 deals -- -- O
20 of -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 victim -- -- O
23 ; -- -- O
24 and -- -- O
25 even -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 variant -- -- O
28 of -- -- O
29 Mr. -- -- O
30 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
31 ’ -- -- O
32 s -- -- O
33 murder -- -- O
34 being -- -- O
35 the -- -- O
36 “ -- -- O
37 sacred -- -- O
38 sacrifice -- -- O
39 ” -- -- O
40 by -- -- O
41 the -- -- O
42 Russia -- -- B-GPE
43 enemies -- -- O
44 that -- -- O
45 want -- -- O
46 to -- -- O
47 destabilize -- -- O
48 the -- -- O
49 political -- -- O
50 situation -- -- O
51 in -- -- O
52 the -- -- O
53 country -- -- O
54 . -- -- O

1 Boris -- -- B-PER
2 Nemtsov -- -- I-PER
3 is -- -- O
4 survived -- -- O
5 by -- -- O
6 his -- -- O
7 four -- -- O
8 children -- -- O
9 from -- -- O
10 three -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 his -- -- O
13 different -- -- O
14 “ -- -- O
15 wives -- -- O
16 . -- -- O
17 ” -- -- O

1 Mr. -- -- O
2 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
3 had -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 very -- -- O
6 unusual -- -- O
7 — -- -- O
8 some -- -- O
9 would -- -- O
10 say -- -- O
11 scandalous -- -- O
12 — -- -- O
13 relationship -- -- O
14 with -- -- O
15 a -- -- O
16 row -- -- O
17 of -- -- O
18 women -- -- O
19 . -- -- O

1 Although -- -- O
2 never -- -- O
3 divorced -- -- O
4 from -- -- O
5 his -- -- O
6 wife -- -- O
7 Raisa -- -- B-PER
8 , -- -- O
9 during -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 last -- -- O
12 20 -- -- O
13 years -- -- O
14 of -- -- O
15 his -- -- O
16 life -- -- O
17 he -- -- O
18 lived -- -- O
19 openly -- -- O
20 with -- -- O
21 a -- -- O
22 number -- -- O
23 of -- -- O
24 different -- -- O
25 female -- -- O
26 civil -- -- O
27 partners -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 has -- -- O
3 one -- -- O
4 daughter -- -- O
5 with -- -- O
6 his -- -- O
7 wife -- -- O
8 Raisa -- -- B-PER
9 , -- -- O
10 a -- -- O
11 son -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 a -- -- O
14 daughter -- -- O
15 with -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 socialite -- -- O
18 and -- -- O
19 TV -- -- O
20 host -- -- O
21 Ekaterina -- -- B-PER
22 Odintsova -- -- I-PER
23 and -- -- O
24 a -- -- O
25 daughter -- -- O
26 with -- -- O
27 his -- -- O
28 former -- -- O
29 secretary -- -- O
30 Irina -- -- B-PER
31 Koroleva -- -- I-PER
32 , -- -- O
33 who -- -- O
34 used -- -- O
35 to -- -- O
36 work -- -- O
37 for -- -- O
38 the -- -- O
39 Administration -- -- B-ORG
40 of -- -- I-ORG
41 the -- -- I-ORG
42 Russian -- -- I-ORG
43 President -- -- I-ORG
44 . -- -- O

1 According -- -- O
2 to -- -- O
3 Mr. -- -- O
4 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
5 ’ -- -- O
6 s -- -- O
7 friend -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 while -- -- O
10 celebrating -- -- O
11 his -- -- O
12 50th -- -- O
13 anniversary -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 Mr. -- -- O
16 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
17 had -- -- O
18 all -- -- O
19 his -- -- O
20 “ -- -- O
21 wives -- -- O
22 ” -- -- O
23 and -- -- O
24 children -- -- O
25 at -- -- O
26 the -- -- O
27 same -- -- O
28 table -- -- O
29 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 also -- -- O
3 never -- -- O
4 hid -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 fact -- -- O
7 that -- -- O
8 for -- -- O
9 a -- -- O
10 number -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 years -- -- O
13 he -- -- O
14 had -- -- O
15 a -- -- O
16 “ -- -- O
17 relationship -- -- O
18 ” -- -- O
19 with -- -- O
20 one -- -- O
21 Anastasia -- -- B-PER
22 Ogneva -- -- I-PER
23 , -- -- O
24 Dni.ru -- -- O
25 reports -- -- O
26 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 spotlight -- -- O
3 on -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 complicated -- -- O
6 personal -- -- O
7 life -- -- O
8 of -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 opposition -- -- O
11 leader -- -- O
12 burned -- -- O
13 brightly -- -- O
14 after -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 organized -- -- O
17 leak -- -- O
18 of -- -- O
19 his -- -- O
20 private -- -- O
21 telephone -- -- O
22 conversation -- -- O
23 about -- -- O
24 opposition -- -- O
25 journalist -- -- O
26 and -- -- O
27 socialite -- -- O
28 Bozhena -- -- B-PER
29 Rynska -- -- I-PER
30 exactly -- -- O
31 two -- -- O
32 years -- -- O
33 ago -- -- O
34 . -- -- O

1 During -- -- O
2 this -- -- O
3 conversation -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 Mr. -- -- O
6 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
7 had -- -- O
8 this -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 say -- -- O
11 about -- -- O
12 his -- -- O
13 colleague -- -- O
14 from -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 opposition -- -- O
17 : -- -- O
18 “ -- -- O
19 Fuck -- -- O
20 her -- -- O
21 ! -- -- O

1 She -- -- O
2 is -- -- O
3 The -- -- O
4 Bitch -- -- O
5 ! -- -- O

1 Just -- -- O
2 because -- -- O
3 I -- -- O
4 did -- -- O
5 not -- -- O
6 fuck -- -- O
7 her -- -- O
8 she -- -- O
9 was -- -- O
10 washing -- -- O
11 my -- -- O
12 dirty -- -- O
13 laundry -- -- O
14 and -- -- O
15 putting -- -- O
16 me -- -- O
17 down -- -- O
18 in -- -- O
19 her -- -- O
20 paper -- -- O
21 for -- -- O
22 a -- -- O
23 year -- -- O
24 . -- -- O

1 And -- -- O
2 she -- -- O
3 was -- -- O
4 writing -- -- O
5 not -- -- O
6 on -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 theme -- -- O
9 of -- -- O
10 me -- -- O
11 fucking -- -- O
12 her -- -- O
13 . -- -- O

1 Let -- -- O
2 ’ -- -- O
3 s -- -- O
4 organize -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 Club -- -- O
7 of -- -- O
8 Those -- -- O
9 Who -- -- O
10 Never -- -- O
11 Fucked -- -- O
12 Bozhena -- -- B-PER
13 Rynsky -- -- I-PER
14 ! -- -- O
15 ” -- -- O

1 Back -- -- O
2 then -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 opposition -- -- O
6 believes -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 leak -- -- O
10 was -- -- O
11 organized -- -- O
12 by -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 FSB -- -- B-ORG
15 security -- -- O
16 service -- -- O
17 and -- -- O
18 was -- -- O
19 directed -- -- O
20 at -- -- O
21 Mr. -- -- O
22 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
23 to -- -- O
24 discredit -- -- O
25 the -- -- O
26 politician -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 23-year-old -- -- O
3 Ms. -- -- O
4 Duritskaya -- -- B-PER
5 , -- -- O
6 who -- -- O
7 just -- -- O
8 arrived -- -- O
9 from -- -- O
10 Kiev -- -- B-GPE
11 , -- -- O
12 is -- -- O
13 not -- -- O
14 a -- -- O
15 suspect -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 but -- -- O
18 possibly -- -- O
19 was -- -- O
20 used -- -- O
21 by -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 criminals -- -- O
24 without -- -- O
25 her -- -- O
26 knowledge -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 She -- -- O
2 calls -- -- O
3 herself -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 model -- -- O
6 and -- -- O
7 an -- -- O
8 actress -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 although -- -- O
11 is -- -- O
12 not -- -- O
13 known -- -- O
14 for -- -- O
15 having -- -- O
16 any -- -- O
17 parts -- -- O
18 in -- -- O
19 movies -- -- O
20 or -- -- O
21 on -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 scene -- -- O
24 . -- -- O

1 She -- -- O
2 studied -- -- O
3 bookkeeping -- -- O
4 at -- -- O
5 Kiev -- -- B-ORG
6 University -- -- I-ORG
7 and -- -- O
8 worked -- -- O
9 for -- -- O
10 obscure -- -- O
11 model -- -- O
12 agencies -- -- O
13 that -- -- O
14 she -- -- O
15 left -- -- O
16 after -- -- O
17 having -- -- O
18 found -- -- O
19 the -- -- O
20 friendship -- -- O
21 of -- -- O
22 Mr. -- -- O
23 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
24 . -- -- O

1 Mr. -- -- O
2 Nemtsov -- -- B-PER
3 did -- -- O
4 not -- -- O
5 feel -- -- O
6 safe -- -- O
7 in -- -- O
8 Russia -- -- B-GPE
9 and -- -- O
10 two -- -- O
11 years -- -- O
12 ago -- -- O
13 seriously -- -- O
14 considered -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 possibility -- -- O
17 of -- -- O
18 applying -- -- O
19 for -- -- O
20 political -- -- O
21 asylum -- -- O
22 in -- -- O
23 Lithuania -- -- B-GPE
24 , -- -- O
25 according -- -- O
26 to -- -- O
27 the -- -- O
28 ex-Prime -- -- O
29 Minister -- -- O
30 of -- -- O
31 that -- -- O
32 country -- -- O
33 . -- -- O

1 Hillary -- -- B-PER
2 for -- -- O
3 Liberals -- -- O
4 : -- -- O
5 A -- -- O
6 Conversation -- -- O
7 With -- -- O
8 Walter -- -- B-PER
9 Shapiro -- -- I-PER

1 " -- -- O
2 As -- -- O
3 a -- -- O
4 campaigner -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 Hillary -- -- B-PER
7 can -- -- O
8 do -- -- O
9 a -- -- O
10 shot -- -- O
11 and -- -- O
12 a -- -- O
13 beer -- -- O
14 better -- -- O
15 than -- -- O
16 Barack -- -- B-PER
17 Obama -- -- I-PER
18 can -- -- O
19 , -- -- O
20 " -- -- O
21 Shapiro -- -- B-PER
22 says -- -- O
23 . -- -- O

1 So -- -- O
2 there -- -- O
3 's -- -- O
4 that -- -- O
5 . -- -- O

1 As -- -- O
2 a -- -- O
3 reporter -- -- O
4 and -- -- O
5 columnist -- -- O
6 for -- -- O
7 Time -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 Newsweek -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 Washington -- -- B-GPE
13 Post -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 USA -- -- B-GPE
16 Today -- -- O
17 , -- -- O
18 Esquire -- -- O
19 , -- -- O
20 Salon -- -- O
21 , -- -- O
22 and -- -- O
23 other -- -- O
24 publications -- -- O
25 , -- -- O
26 Walter -- -- B-PER
27 Shapiro -- -- I-PER
28 has -- -- O
29 covered -- -- O
30 nine -- -- O
31 presidential -- -- O
32 elections -- -- O
33 and -- -- O
34 the -- -- O
35 nation -- -- O
36 ’ -- -- O
37 s -- -- O
38 politics -- -- O
39 for -- -- O
40 four -- -- O
41 decades -- -- O
42 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 is -- -- O
3 currently -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 fellow -- -- O
6 at -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 Brennan -- -- B-ORG
9 Center -- -- I-ORG
10 for -- -- I-ORG
11 Justice -- -- I-ORG
12 at -- -- O
13 New -- -- B-ORG
14 York -- -- I-ORG
15 University -- -- I-ORG
16 and -- -- O
17 a -- -- O
18 lecturer -- -- O
19 in -- -- O
20 political -- -- O
21 science -- -- O
22 at -- -- O
23 Yale -- -- B-ORG
24 while -- -- O
25 he -- -- O
26 finishes -- -- O
27 a -- -- O
28 book -- -- O
29 about -- -- O
30 his -- -- O
31 great-uncle -- -- O
32 , -- -- O
33 a -- -- O
34 vaudevillian -- -- O
35 and -- -- O
36 con -- -- O
37 man -- -- O
38 who -- -- O
39 once -- -- O
40 swindled -- -- O
41 Hitler -- -- B-PER
42 . -- -- O

1 Shapiro -- -- B-PER
2 is -- -- O
3 also -- -- O
4 an -- -- O
5 accomplished -- -- O
6 Hillary-ologist -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 having -- -- O
9 first -- -- O
10 interviewed -- -- O
11 Hillary -- -- B-PER
12 Clinton -- -- I-PER
13 in -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
16 governor -- -- O
17 ’ -- -- O
18 s -- -- O
19 mansion -- -- O
20 for -- -- O
21 Time -- -- O
22 in -- -- O
23 September -- -- O
24 1992 -- -- O
25 . -- -- O

1 In -- -- O
2 early -- -- O
3 May -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 Shapiro -- -- B-PER
6 sat -- -- O
7 down -- -- O
8 with -- -- O
9 Prospect -- -- O
10 editor-at-large -- -- O
11 Harold -- -- B-PER
12 Meyerson -- -- I-PER
13 to -- -- O
14 talk -- -- O
15 about -- -- O
16 a -- -- O
17 question -- -- O
18 he -- -- O
19 ’ -- -- O
20 s -- -- O
21 internally -- -- O
22 debated -- -- O
23 for -- -- O
24 years -- -- O
25 : -- -- O
26 On -- -- O
27 balance -- -- O
28 , -- -- O
29 would -- -- O
30 a -- -- O
31 Hillary -- -- B-PER
32 Clinton -- -- I-PER
33 candidacy -- -- O
34 and -- -- O
35 presidency -- -- O
36 be -- -- O
37 a -- -- O
38 good -- -- O
39 or -- -- O
40 bad -- -- O
41 thing -- -- O
42 for -- -- O
43 the -- -- O
44 liberal -- -- O
45 cause -- -- O
46 ? -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 following -- -- O
3 discussion -- -- O
4 has -- -- O
5 been -- -- O
6 edited -- -- O
7 for -- -- O
8 concision -- -- O
9 and -- -- O
10 clarity -- -- O
11 . -- -- O

1 Harold -- -- B-PER
2 Meyerson -- -- I-PER
3 : -- -- O
4 Walter -- -- B-PER
5 , -- -- O
6 when -- -- O
7 liberals -- -- O
8 look -- -- O
9 at -- -- O
10 Hillary -- -- B-PER
11 Clinton -- -- I-PER
12 , -- -- O
13 what -- -- O
14 should -- -- O
15 they -- -- O
16 see -- -- O
17 ? -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 Democratic -- -- B-ORG
3 Party -- -- I-ORG
4 and -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 country -- -- O
7 have -- -- O
8 certainly -- -- O
9 changed -- -- O
10 since -- -- O
11 she -- -- O
12 was -- -- O
13 first -- -- O
14 lady -- -- O
15 , -- -- O
16 and -- -- O
17 even -- -- O
18 since -- -- O
19 she -- -- O
20 was -- -- O
21 a -- -- O
22 senator -- -- O
23 and -- -- O
24 secretary -- -- O
25 of -- -- O
26 state -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 Walter -- -- B-PER
2 Shapiro -- -- I-PER
3 : -- -- O
4 I -- -- O
5 ’ -- -- O
6 ve -- -- O
7 always -- -- O
8 thought -- -- O
9 that -- -- O
10 Bill -- -- B-PER
11 Clinton -- -- I-PER
12 was -- -- O
13 never -- -- O
14 really -- -- O
15 a -- -- O
16 person -- -- O
17 of -- -- O
18 the -- -- O
19 ’ -- -- O
20 60s -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 Bill -- -- B-PER
2 Clinton -- -- I-PER
3 started -- -- O
4 in -- -- O
5 1960 -- -- O
6 as -- -- O
7 a -- -- O
8 14-year-old -- -- O
9 who -- -- O
10 wanted -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 be -- -- O
13 governor -- -- O
14 of -- -- O
15 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
16 . -- -- O

1 He -- -- O
2 came -- -- O
3 out -- -- O
4 of -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 ’ -- -- O
7 60s -- -- O
8 as -- -- O
9 a -- -- O
10 24-year-old -- -- O
11 who -- -- O
12 wanted -- -- O
13 to -- -- O
14 be -- -- O
15 governor -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
18 without -- -- O
19 going -- -- O
20 to -- -- O
21 Vietnam -- -- O
22 . -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 Hillary -- -- B-PER
3 did -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 full -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 life-changing -- -- O
8 conversion -- -- O
9 from -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 obedient -- -- O
12 Goldwater -- -- O
13 Girl -- -- O
14 to -- -- O
15 delivering -- -- O
16 an -- -- O
17 ethereal -- -- O
18 but -- -- O
19 genuinely -- -- O
20 anti-war -- -- O
21 address -- -- O
22 at -- -- O
23 Wellesley -- -- B-ORG
24 in -- -- O
25 ’ -- -- O
26 69 -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 So -- -- O
2 in -- -- O
3 a -- -- O
4 sense -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 as -- -- O
7 far -- -- O
8 as -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 culture -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 time -- -- O
14 washing -- -- O
15 over -- -- O
16 someone -- -- O
17 , -- -- O
18 it -- -- O
19 washed -- -- O
20 over -- -- O
21 her -- -- O
22 more -- -- O
23 than -- -- O
24 it -- -- O
25 ever -- -- O
26 washed -- -- O
27 over -- -- O
28 Bill -- -- B-PER
29 . -- -- O

1 HM -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 Still -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 she -- -- O
6 spent -- -- O
7 so -- -- O
8 many -- -- O
9 years -- -- O
10 in -- -- O
11 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
12 , -- -- O
13 and -- -- O
14 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
15 ’ -- -- O
16 s -- -- O
17 political -- -- O
18 culture -- -- O
19 is -- -- O
20 not -- -- O
21 one -- -- O
22 with -- -- O
23 which -- -- O
24 most -- -- O
25 liberals -- -- O
26 are -- -- O
27 comfortable -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

1 Both -- -- O
2 Clintons -- -- O
3 were -- -- O
4 clearly -- -- O
5 supportive -- -- O
6 of -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 civil-rights -- -- O
9 revolution -- -- O
10 . -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 the -- -- O
3 other -- -- O
4 part -- -- O
5 of -- -- O
6 that -- -- O
7 culture -- -- O
8 is -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 Stephens -- -- B-ORG
11 investment -- -- I-ORG
12 firm -- -- I-ORG
13 and -- -- O
14 Wal-Mart -- -- B-ORG
15 , -- -- O
16 and -- -- O
17 to -- -- O
18 get -- -- O
19 somewhere -- -- O
20 in -- -- O
21 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
22 politics -- -- O
23 , -- -- O
24 you -- -- O
25 eventually -- -- O
26 have -- -- O
27 relations -- -- O
28 with -- -- O
29 them -- -- O
30 . -- -- O

1 Hillary -- -- B-PER
2 famously -- -- O
3 was -- -- O
4 on -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 Wal-Mart -- -- B-ORG
7 board -- -- O
8 for -- -- O
9 a -- -- O
10 while -- -- O
11 . -- -- O

1 WS -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 What -- -- O
4 stayed -- -- O
5 with -- -- O
6 me -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 and -- -- O
9 I -- -- O
10 still -- -- O
11 think -- -- O
12 it -- -- O
13 ’ -- -- O
14 s -- -- O
15 really -- -- O
16 important -- -- O
17 for -- -- O
18 understanding -- -- O
19 Hillary -- -- B-PER
20 , -- -- O
21 happened -- -- O
22 in -- -- O
23 March -- -- O
24 of -- -- O
25 1992 -- -- O
26 , -- -- O
27 at -- -- O
28 a -- -- O
29 debate -- -- O
30 before -- -- O
31 the -- -- O
32 Illinois -- -- B-GPE
33 primary -- -- O
34 . -- -- O

1 Jerry -- -- B-PER
2 Brown -- -- I-PER
3 ( -- -- O
4 Bill -- -- B-PER
5 Clinton -- -- I-PER
6 ’ -- -- O
7 s -- -- O
8 primary -- -- O
9 opponent -- -- O
10 ) -- -- O
11 went -- -- O
12 after -- -- O
13 Bill -- -- B-PER
14 Clinton -- -- I-PER
15 in -- -- O
16 part -- -- O
17 for -- -- O
18 the -- -- O
19 legal -- -- O
20 work -- -- O
21 that -- -- O
22 Hillary -- -- B-PER
23 did -- -- O
24 at -- -- O
25 Rose -- -- B-ORG
26 Law -- -- I-ORG
27 Firm -- -- I-ORG
28 on -- -- O
29 behalf -- -- O
30 of -- -- O
31 banks -- -- O
32 . -- -- O

1 And -- -- O
2 Hillary -- -- B-PER
3 at -- -- O
4 some -- -- O
5 point -- -- O
6 said -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 in -- -- O
9 effect -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 “ -- -- O
12 Of -- -- O
13 course -- -- O
14 I -- -- O
15 work -- -- O
16 for -- -- O
17 banks -- -- O
18 ; -- -- O
19 who -- -- O
20 do -- -- O
21 you -- -- O
22 expect -- -- O
23 me -- -- O
24 to -- -- O
25 work -- -- O
26 for -- -- O
27 if -- -- O
28 I -- -- O
29 ’ -- -- O
30 m -- -- O
31 a -- -- O
32 lawyer -- -- O
33 ? -- -- O
34 ” -- -- O

1 Well -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 there -- -- O
4 were -- -- O
5 , -- -- O
6 believe -- -- O
7 it -- -- O
8 or -- -- O
9 not -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 other -- -- O
12 clients -- -- O
13 in -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 state -- -- O
16 of -- -- O
17 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
18 in -- -- O
19 the -- -- O
20 1980s -- -- O
21 while -- -- O
22 her -- -- O
23 husband -- -- O
24 was -- -- O
25 governor -- -- O
26 . -- -- O

1 HM -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 That -- -- O
4 ’ -- -- O
5 s -- -- O
6 no -- -- O
7 small -- -- O
8 part -- -- O
9 of -- -- O
10 what -- -- O
11 gives -- -- O
12 liberals -- -- O
13 pause -- -- O
14 about -- -- O
15 Hillary -- -- B-PER
16 — -- -- O
17 who -- -- O
18 is -- -- O
19 , -- -- O
20 of -- -- O
21 course -- -- O
22 , -- -- O
23 still -- -- O
24 going -- -- O
25 around -- -- O
26 giving -- -- O
27 talks -- -- O
28 to -- -- O
29 the -- -- O
30 Goldman -- -- B-ORG
31 Sachses -- -- I-ORG
32 of -- -- O
33 the -- -- O
34 world -- -- O
35 . -- -- O

1 Is -- -- O
2 she -- -- O
3 too -- -- O
4 inextricably -- -- O
5 linked -- -- O
6 to -- -- O
7 that -- -- O
8 world -- -- O
9 ? -- -- O

1 One -- -- O
2 of -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 major -- -- O
5 issues -- -- O
6 liberals -- -- O
7 had -- -- O
8 with -- -- O
9 Obama -- -- B-PER
10 is -- -- O
11 that -- -- O
12 his -- -- O
13 economic -- -- O
14 team -- -- O
15 has -- -- O
16 been -- -- O
17 , -- -- O
18 like -- -- O
19 Bill -- -- B-PER
20 Clinton -- -- I-PER
21 ’ -- -- O
22 s -- -- O
23 , -- -- O
24 primarily -- -- O
25 Robert -- -- B-PER
26 Rubin -- -- I-PER
27 protégés -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 ’ -- -- O
3 s -- -- O
4 two -- -- O
5 straight -- -- O
6 Democratic -- -- B-ORG
7 presidencies -- -- O
8 with -- -- O
9 a -- -- O
10 Wall -- -- B-FAC
11 Street -- -- I-FAC
12 pedigree -- -- O
13 . -- -- O

1 WS -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 As -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 campaigner -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 Hillary -- -- B-PER
8 can -- -- O
9 do -- -- O
10 a -- -- O
11 shot -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 a -- -- O
14 beer -- -- O
15 better -- -- O
16 than -- -- O
17 Barack -- -- B-PER
18 Obama -- -- I-PER
19 can -- -- O
20 . -- -- O

1 She -- -- O
2 was -- -- O
3 an -- -- O
4 exceedingly -- -- O
5 good -- -- O
6 candidate -- -- O
7 when -- -- O
8 it -- -- O
9 was -- -- O
10 too -- -- O
11 late -- -- O
12 in -- -- O
13 the -- -- O
14 ’ -- -- O
15 08 -- -- O
16 primaries -- -- O
17 with -- -- O
18 white -- -- O
19 working-class -- -- O
20 voters -- -- O
21 in -- -- O
22 Pennsylvania -- -- B-GPE
23 , -- -- O
24 in -- -- O
25 Indiana -- -- B-GPE
26 , -- -- O
27 in -- -- O
28 states -- -- O
29 like -- -- O
30 that -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 said -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 everything -- -- O
5 in -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 ledger -- -- O
8 says -- -- O
9 she -- -- O
10 ’ -- -- O
11 s -- -- O
12 not -- -- O
13 a -- -- O
14 policy -- -- O
15 populist -- -- O
16 . -- -- O

1 Remember -- -- O
2 that -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 Bill -- -- B-PER
5 Clinton -- -- I-PER
6 administration -- -- O
7 at -- -- O
8 its -- -- O
9 most -- -- O
10 successful -- -- O
11 was -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 Democratic -- -- B-ORG
14 answer -- -- O
15 to -- -- O
16 Reaganism -- -- B-PER
17 . -- -- O

1 It -- -- O
2 was -- -- O
3 what -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 French -- -- O
6 call -- -- O
7 “ -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 spirit -- -- O
10 of -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 staircase -- -- O
13 ” -- -- O
14 — -- -- O
15 coming -- -- O
16 up -- -- O
17 with -- -- O
18 everything -- -- O
19 you -- -- O
20 should -- -- O
21 have -- -- O
22 said -- -- O
23 at -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 party -- -- O
26 just -- -- O
27 after -- -- O
28 you -- -- O
29 ’ -- -- O
30 ve -- -- O
31 left -- -- O
32 it -- -- O
33 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 administration -- -- O
3 said -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 let -- -- O
6 ’ -- -- O
7 s -- -- O
8 get -- -- O
9 off -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 table -- -- O
12 everything -- -- O
13 Reagan -- -- B-PER
14 criticized -- -- O
15 about -- -- O
16 the -- -- O
17 Democrats -- -- B-ORG
18 . -- -- O

1 It -- -- O
2 was -- -- O
3 welfare -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 so -- -- O
6 they -- -- O
7 ended -- -- O
8 it -- -- O
9 ; -- -- O
10 it -- -- O
11 was -- -- O
12 crime -- -- O
13 , -- -- O
14 so -- -- O
15 they -- -- O
16 came -- -- O
17 up -- -- O
18 with -- -- O
19 funding -- -- O
20 for -- -- O
21 100,000 -- -- O
22 more -- -- O
23 cops -- -- O
24 ; -- -- O
25 it -- -- O
26 was -- -- O
27 economic -- -- O
28 deficits -- -- O
29 , -- -- O
30 so -- -- O
31 they -- -- O
32 came -- -- O
33 up -- -- O
34 with -- -- O
35 a -- -- O
36 balanced -- -- O
37 budget -- -- O
38 . -- -- O

1 To -- -- O
2 some -- -- O
3 extent -- -- O
4 , -- -- O
5 electing -- -- O
6 Hillary -- -- B-PER
7 Clinton -- -- I-PER
8 in -- -- O
9 2016 -- -- O
10 could -- -- O
11 continue -- -- O
12 a -- -- O
13 debate -- -- O
14 with -- -- O
15 Ronald -- -- B-PER
16 Reagan -- -- I-PER
17 that -- -- O
18 no -- -- O
19 one -- -- O
20 else -- -- O
21 in -- -- O
22 American -- -- B-GPE
23 life -- -- O
24 is -- -- O
25 still -- -- O
26 having -- -- O
27 . -- -- O

1 The -- -- O
2 Democrats -- -- B-ORG
3 have -- -- O
4 mostly -- -- O
5 forgotten -- -- O
6 Reagan -- -- B-PER
7 , -- -- O
8 and -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 Republicans -- -- B-ORG
11 have -- -- O
12 turned -- -- O
13 him -- -- O
14 into -- -- O
15 this -- -- O
16 sainted -- -- O
17 soul -- -- O
18 of -- -- O
19 political -- -- O
20 constancy -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 a -- -- O
3 Hillary -- -- B-PER
4 presidency -- -- O
5 would -- -- O
6 be -- -- O
7 still -- -- O
8 framed -- -- O
9 by -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 Democratic -- -- B-ORG
12 memory -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 those -- -- O
15 horrible -- -- O
16 years -- -- O
17 in -- -- O
18 the -- -- O
19 wilderness -- -- O
20 in -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 1980s -- -- O
23 , -- -- O
24 when -- -- O
25 the -- -- O
26 Democrats -- -- B-ORG
27 got -- -- O
28 wiped -- -- O
29 out -- -- O
30 in -- -- O
31 three -- -- O
32 successive -- -- O
33 elections -- -- O
34 . -- -- O

1 HM -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 But -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 political -- -- O
6 landscape -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 demographic -- -- O
10 profile -- -- O
11 of -- -- O
12 voters -- -- O
13 has -- -- O
14 changed -- -- O
15 so -- -- O
16 much -- -- O
17 since -- -- O
18 then -- -- O
19 . -- -- O

1 More -- -- O
2 political -- -- O
3 space -- -- O
4 has -- -- O
5 opened -- -- O
6 up -- -- O
7 on -- -- O
8 the -- -- O
9 left -- -- O
10 ; -- -- O
11 the -- -- O
12 nation -- -- O
13 has -- -- O
14 plainly -- -- O
15 moved -- -- O
16 in -- -- O
17 a -- -- O
18 liberal -- -- O
19 direction -- -- O
20 on -- -- O
21 social -- -- O
22 issues -- -- O
23 ; -- -- O
24 there -- -- O
25 are -- -- O
26 very -- -- O
27 few -- -- O
28 Blue -- -- O
29 Dogs -- -- O
30 remaining -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 Is -- -- O
2 this -- -- O
3 defensive -- -- O
4 crouch -- -- O
5 against -- -- O
6 the -- -- O
7 Republicans -- -- B-ORG
8 a -- -- O
9 politically -- -- O
10 viable -- -- O
11 stance -- -- O
12 ? -- -- O

1 WS -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 I -- -- O
4 ’ -- -- O
5 m -- -- O
6 talking -- -- O
7 about -- -- O
8 what -- -- O
9 makes -- -- O
10 her -- -- O
11 tick -- -- O
12 . -- -- O

1 Of -- -- O
2 course -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 she -- -- O
5 won -- -- O
6 two -- -- O
7 elections -- -- O
8 in -- -- O
9 a -- -- O
10 very -- -- O
11 diverse -- -- O
12 state -- -- O
13 since -- -- O
14 Bill -- -- B-PER
15 ’ -- -- O
16 s -- -- O
17 presidency -- -- O
18 , -- -- O
19 and -- -- O
20 she -- -- O
21 won -- -- O
22 an -- -- O
23 awful -- -- O
24 lot -- -- O
25 of -- -- O
26 presidential -- -- O
27 primaries -- -- O
28 in -- -- O
29 ’ -- -- O
30 08 -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 She -- -- O
2 understands -- -- O
3 the -- -- O
4 diversity -- -- O
5 of -- -- O
6 America -- -- B-GPE
7 in -- -- O
8 2017 -- -- O
9 — -- -- O
10 except -- -- O
11 in -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 economic -- -- O
14 sense -- -- O
15 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 said -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 I -- -- O
5 don -- -- O
6 ’ -- -- O
7 t -- -- O
8 think -- -- O
9 she -- -- O
10 ’ -- -- O
11 s -- -- O
12 the -- -- O
13 candidate -- -- O
14 of -- -- O
15 Archie -- -- O
16 Bunker -- -- O
17 ’ -- -- O
18 s -- -- O
19 America -- -- B-GPE
20 . -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 the -- -- O
3 worst -- -- O
4 thing -- -- O
5 that -- -- O
6 could -- -- O
7 have -- -- O
8 happened -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 her -- -- O
11 in -- -- O
12 terms -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 framing -- -- O
15 any -- -- O
16 economic -- -- O
17 populist -- -- O
18 message -- -- O
19 was -- -- O
20 to -- -- O
21 run -- -- O
22 for -- -- O
23 the -- -- O
24 Senate -- -- B-ORG
25 from -- -- O
26 New -- -- B-GPE
27 York -- -- I-GPE
28 rather -- -- O
29 than -- -- O
30 , -- -- O
31 say -- -- O
32 , -- -- O
33 Arkansas -- -- B-GPE
34 . -- -- O

1 Not -- -- O
2 only -- -- O
3 do -- -- O
4 the -- -- O
5 Clintons -- -- O
6 have -- -- O
7 a -- -- O
8 certain -- -- O
9 psychological -- -- O
10 need -- -- O
11 for -- -- O
12 money -- -- O
13 — -- -- O
14 that -- -- O
15 would -- -- O
16 probably -- -- O
17 be -- -- O
18 a -- -- O
19 separate -- -- O
20 course -- -- O
21 in -- -- O
22 the -- -- O
23 Department -- -- O
24 of -- -- O
25 Hillary -- -- B-PER
26 Studies -- -- O
27 — -- -- O
28 but -- -- O
29 her -- -- O
30 constituents -- -- O
31 were -- -- O
32 Wall -- -- B-FAC
33 Street -- -- I-FAC
34 , -- -- O
35 and -- -- O
36 they -- -- O
37 were -- -- O
38 also -- -- O
39 the -- -- O
40 people -- -- O
41 who -- -- O
42 were -- -- O
43 funding -- -- O
44 all -- -- O
45 the -- -- O
46 Clinton -- -- B-PER
47 initiatives -- -- O
48 and -- -- O
49 giving -- -- O
50 speaking -- -- O
51 fees -- -- O
52 to -- -- O
53 Bill -- -- B-PER
54 . -- -- O

1 Ultimately -- -- O
2 she -- -- O
3 has -- -- O
4 an -- -- O
5 orthodox -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 mainstream -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 centrist -- -- O
10 , -- -- O
11 Eisenhower -- -- B-PER
12 Republican -- -- B-ORG
13 view -- -- O
14 of -- -- O
15 the -- -- O
16 economy -- -- O
17 . -- -- O

1 It -- -- O
2 is -- -- O
3 much -- -- O
4 to -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 left -- -- O
7 of -- -- O
8 today -- -- O
9 ’ -- -- O
10 s -- -- O
11 Republican -- -- B-ORG
12 Party -- -- I-ORG
13 since -- -- O
14 there -- -- O
15 are -- -- O
16 no -- -- O
17 Eisenhower -- -- B-PER
18 Republicans -- -- B-ORG
19 left -- -- O
20 , -- -- O
21 but -- -- O
22 it -- -- O
23 is -- -- O
24 also -- -- O
25 much -- -- O
26 less -- -- O
27 in -- -- O
28 keeping -- -- O
29 with -- -- O
30 large -- -- O
31 segments -- -- O
32 of -- -- O
33 the -- -- O
34 Democratic -- -- B-ORG
35 Party -- -- I-ORG
36 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 can -- -- O
3 see -- -- O
4 her -- -- O
5 being -- -- O
6 very -- -- O
7 involved -- -- O
8 in -- -- O
9 raising -- -- O
10 the -- -- O
11 minimum -- -- O
12 wage -- -- O
13 , -- -- O
14 because -- -- O
15 it -- -- O
16 ’ -- -- O
17 s -- -- O
18 not -- -- O
19 as -- -- O
20 if -- -- O
21 hedge-fund -- -- O
22 billionaires -- -- O
23 are -- -- O
24 on -- -- O
25 the -- -- O
26 barricades -- -- O
27 against -- -- O
28 it -- -- O
29 . -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 trying -- -- O
3 to -- -- O
4 do -- -- O
5 a -- -- O
6 better -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 tougher -- -- O
9 version -- -- O
10 of -- -- O
11 Dodd-Frank -- -- O
12 ? -- -- O

1 Let -- -- O
2 ’ -- -- O
3 s -- -- O
4 merely -- -- O
5 say -- -- O
6 that -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 polls -- -- O
9 would -- -- O
10 have -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 get -- -- O
13 very -- -- O
14 dismal -- -- O
15 for -- -- O
16 Hillary -- -- B-PER
17 leading -- -- O
18 up -- -- O
19 to -- -- O
20 the -- -- O
21 2020 -- -- O
22 election -- -- O
23 for -- -- O
24 that -- -- O
25 to -- -- O
26 even -- -- O
27 be -- -- O
28 on -- -- O
29 her -- -- O
30 agenda -- -- O
31 . -- -- O

1 HM -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 Let -- -- O
4 ’ -- -- O
5 s -- -- O
6 go -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 foreign -- -- O
9 policy -- -- O
10 . -- -- O

1 WS -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 If -- -- O
4 you -- -- O
5 wanted -- -- O
6 me -- -- O
7 to -- -- O
8 state -- -- O
9 my -- -- O
10 own -- -- O
11 personal -- -- O
12 reservations -- -- O
13 about -- -- O
14 Hillary -- -- B-PER
15 , -- -- O
16 I -- -- O
17 would -- -- O
18 have -- -- O
19 started -- -- O
20 with -- -- O
21 foreign -- -- O
22 policy -- -- O
23 . -- -- O

1 HM -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 What -- -- O
4 would -- -- O
5 those -- -- O
6 reservations -- -- O
7 be -- -- O
8 ? -- -- O

1 WS -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 First -- -- O
4 of -- -- O
5 all -- -- O
6 , -- -- O
7 other -- -- O
8 than -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 anti-war -- -- O
11 feeling -- -- O
12 , -- -- O
13 which -- -- O
14 is -- -- O
15 more -- -- O
16 generational -- -- O
17 than -- -- O
18 an -- -- O
19 elaborate -- -- O
20 , -- -- O
21 nuanced -- -- O
22 foreign-policy -- -- O
23 view -- -- O
24 , -- -- O
25 I -- -- O
26 don -- -- O
27 ’ -- -- O
28 t -- -- O
29 think -- -- O
30 she -- -- O
31 had -- -- O
32 terribly -- -- O
33 developed -- -- O
34 foreign-policy -- -- O
35 views -- -- O
36 during -- -- O
37 Bill -- -- B-PER
38 ’ -- -- O
39 s -- -- O
40 presidency -- -- O
41 . -- -- O

1 OK -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 there -- -- O
4 was -- -- O
5 the -- -- O
6 general -- -- O
7 , -- -- O
8 and -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 my -- -- O
11 mind -- -- O
12 , -- -- O
13 admirable -- -- O
14 tilt -- -- O
15 toward -- -- O
16 humanitarian -- -- O
17 intervention -- -- O
18 in -- -- O
19 both -- -- O
20 Haiti -- -- B-GPE
21 and -- -- O
22 , -- -- O
23 much -- -- O
24 more -- -- O
25 important -- -- O
26 , -- -- O
27 in -- -- O
28 Bosnia -- -- B-GPE
29 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 do -- -- O
3 not -- -- O
4 think -- -- O
5 she -- -- O
6 would -- -- O
7 have -- -- O
8 dithered -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 way -- -- O
11 Obama -- -- B-PER
12 has -- -- O
13 on -- -- O
14 Syria -- -- B-GPE
15 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 said -- -- O
3 , -- -- O
4 I -- -- O
5 ’ -- -- O
6 ve -- -- O
7 seen -- -- O
8 no -- -- O
9 evidence -- -- O
10 that -- -- O
11 she -- -- O
12 had -- -- O
13 too -- -- O
14 much -- -- O
15 anguish -- -- O
16 over -- -- O
17 her -- -- O
18 vote -- -- O
19 to -- -- O
20 authorize -- -- O
21 Bush -- -- B-PER
22 to -- -- O
23 go -- -- O
24 to -- -- O
25 war -- -- O
26 in -- -- O
27 Iraq -- -- B-GPE
28 . -- -- O

1 John -- -- B-PER
2 Kerry -- -- I-PER
3 turned -- -- O
4 himself -- -- O
5 into -- -- O
6 elaborate -- -- O
7 pretzel -- -- O
8 positions -- -- O
9 to -- -- O
10 try -- -- O
11 to -- -- O
12 justify -- -- O
13 that -- -- O
14 vote -- -- O
15 . -- -- O

1 Hillary -- -- B-PER
2 may -- -- O
3 have -- -- O
4 anguished -- -- O
5 about -- -- O
6 many -- -- O
7 things -- -- O
8 , -- -- O
9 but -- -- O
10 that -- -- O
11 does -- -- O
12 not -- -- O
13 seem -- -- O
14 to -- -- O
15 be -- -- O
16 in -- -- O
17 the -- -- O
18 Top -- -- O
19 10 -- -- O
20 Hillary -- -- B-PER
21 Anguish -- -- O
22 moments -- -- O
23 . -- -- O

1 HM -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 What -- -- O
4 do -- -- O
5 you -- -- O
6 think -- -- O
7 her -- -- O
8 hawkishness -- -- O
9 on -- -- O
10 Iraq -- -- B-GPE
11 would -- -- O
12 portend -- -- O
13 for -- -- O
14 foreign -- -- O
15 policy -- -- O
16 if -- -- O
17 Hillary -- -- B-PER
18 were -- -- O
19 president -- -- O
20 ? -- -- O

1 WS -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 While -- -- O
4 she -- -- O
5 is -- -- O
6 not -- -- O
7 a -- -- O
8 Dick -- -- B-PER
9 Cheney -- -- I-PER
10 groupie -- -- O
11 , -- -- O
12 in -- -- O
13 a -- -- O
14 situation -- -- O
15 where -- -- O
16 there -- -- O
17 is -- -- O
18 a -- -- O
19 range -- -- O
20 of -- -- O
21 military -- -- O
22 actions -- -- O
23 on -- -- O
24 the -- -- O
25 table -- -- O
26 and -- -- O
27 there -- -- O
28 ’ -- -- O
29 s -- -- O
30 a -- -- O
31 responsible -- -- O
32 , -- -- O
33 mainstream -- -- O
34 opinion -- -- O
35 within -- -- O
36 the -- -- O
37 administration -- -- O
38 toward -- -- O
39 using -- -- O
40 the -- -- O
41 military -- -- O
42 — -- -- O
43 and -- -- O
44 the -- -- O
45 foreign-policy -- -- O
46 community -- -- O
47 says -- -- O
48 military -- -- O
49 action -- -- O
50 is -- -- O
51 called -- -- O
52 for -- -- O
53 — -- -- O
54 she -- -- O
55 would -- -- O
56 probably -- -- O
57 go -- -- O
58 with -- -- O
59 it -- -- O
60 and -- -- O
61 cheerlead -- -- O
62 it -- -- O
63 on -- -- O
64 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 don -- -- O
3 ’ -- -- O
4 t -- -- O
5 think -- -- O
6 she -- -- O
7 ’ -- -- O
8 s -- -- O
9 going -- -- O
10 to -- -- O
11 invent -- -- O
12 a -- -- O
13 war -- -- O
14 with -- -- O
15 Mongolia -- -- B-GPE
16 out -- -- O
17 of -- -- O
18 some -- -- O
19 crazed -- -- O
20 geopolitical -- -- O
21 effort -- -- O
22 to -- -- O
23 encircle -- -- O
24 China -- -- B-GPE
25 . -- -- O

1 But -- -- O
2 hers -- -- O
3 would -- -- O
4 probably -- -- O
5 be -- -- O
6 a -- -- O
7 more -- -- O
8 hawkish -- -- O
9 administration -- -- O
10 than -- -- O
11 we -- -- O
12 have -- -- O
13 now -- -- O
14 with -- -- O
15 Obama -- -- B-PER
16 and -- -- O
17 John -- -- B-PER
18 Kerry -- -- I-PER
19 . -- -- O

1 I -- -- O
2 ’ -- -- O
3 m -- -- O
4 much -- -- O
5 less -- -- O
6 worried -- -- O
7 about -- -- O
8 her -- -- O
9 starting -- -- O
10 a -- -- O
11 war -- -- O
12 with -- -- O
13 Denmark -- -- B-GPE
14 , -- -- O
15 though -- -- O
16 , -- -- O
17 than -- -- O
18 I -- -- O
19 am -- -- O
20 by -- -- O
21 the -- -- O
22 fact -- -- O
23 that -- -- O
24 she -- -- O
25 is -- -- O
26 probably -- -- O
27 the -- -- O
28 Democratic -- -- B-ORG
29 presidential -- -- O
30 candidate -- -- O
31 who -- -- O
32 would -- -- O
33 do -- -- O
34 the -- -- O
35 least -- -- O
36 to -- -- O
37 rein -- -- O
38 in -- -- O
39 the -- -- O
40 National -- -- B-ORG
41 Security -- -- I-ORG
42 Agency -- -- I-ORG
43 and -- -- O
44 all -- -- O
45 the -- -- O
46 leftover -- -- O
47 aspects -- -- O
48 of -- -- O
49 the -- -- O
50 “ -- -- O
51 war -- -- O
52 on -- -- O
53 terror -- -- O
54 . -- -- O
55 ” -- -- O

1 Sadly -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 both -- -- O
4 Hillary -- -- B-PER
5 and -- -- O
6 Bill -- -- B-PER
7 know -- -- O
8 that -- -- O
9 civil -- -- O
10 liberties -- -- O
11 is -- -- O
12 that -- -- O
13 which -- -- O
14 closes -- -- O
15 on -- -- O
16 Saturday -- -- O
17 night -- -- O
18 . -- -- O

1 HM -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 Bill -- -- B-PER
4 Clinton -- -- I-PER
5 was -- -- O
6 not -- -- O
7 famed -- -- O
8 for -- -- O
9 his -- -- O
10 managerial -- -- O
11 prowess -- -- O
12 and -- -- O
13 neither -- -- O
14 is -- -- O
15 Barack -- -- B-PER
16 Obama -- -- I-PER
17 . -- -- O

1 That -- -- O
2 ’ -- -- O
3 s -- -- O
4 certainly -- -- O
5 part -- -- O
6 of -- -- O
7 the -- -- O
8 president -- -- O
9 ’ -- -- O
10 s -- -- O
11 job -- -- O
12 . -- -- O

1 Is -- -- O
2 Hillary -- -- B-PER
3 a -- -- O
4 better -- -- O
5 manager -- -- O
6 than -- -- O
7 Bill -- -- B-PER
8 ? -- -- O

1 WS -- -- B-PER
2 : -- -- O
3 I -- -- O
4 think -- -- O
5 she -- -- O
6 is -- -- O
7 much -- -- O
8 more -- -- O
9 than -- -- O
10 just -- -- O
11 that -- -- O
12 . -- -- O

1 If -- -- O
2 you -- -- O
3 have -- -- O
4 been -- -- O
5 through -- -- O
6 a -- -- O
7 disaster -- -- O
8 like -- -- O
9 the -- -- O
10 first -- -- O
11 two -- -- O
12 years -- -- O
13 of -- -- O
14 the -- -- O
15 Clinton -- -- B-PER
16 administration -- -- O
17 , -- -- O
18 you -- -- O
19 know -- -- O
20 what -- -- O
21 to -- -- O
22 do -- -- O
23 now -- -- O
24 . -- -- O

1 Flash -- -- O
2 forward -- -- O
3 to -- -- O
4 a -- -- O
5 White -- -- B-ORG
6 House -- -- I-ORG
7 in -- -- O
8 2017 -- -- O
9 . -- -- O

1 First -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 Bill -- -- B-PER
4 and -- -- O
5 Hillary -- -- B-PER
6 will -- -- O
7 have -- -- O
8 worked -- -- O
9 out -- -- O
10 their -- -- O
11 marriage -- -- O
12 , -- -- O
13 with -- -- O
14 her -- -- O
15 69 -- -- O
16 and -- -- O
17 him -- -- O
18 70 -- -- O
19 , -- -- O
20 as -- -- O
21 well -- -- O
22 as -- -- O
23 any -- -- O
24 couple -- -- O
25 is -- -- O
26 likely -- -- O
27 to -- -- O
28 . -- -- O

1 If -- -- O
2 ever -- -- O
3 there -- -- O
4 ’ -- -- O
5 s -- -- O
6 a -- -- O
7 marriage -- -- O
8 that -- -- O
9 by -- -- O
10 2017 -- -- O
11 has -- -- O
12 few -- -- O
13 surprises -- -- O
14 , -- -- O
15 it -- -- O
16 ’ -- -- O
17 s -- -- O
18 probably -- -- O
19 that -- -- O
20 one -- -- O
21 . -- -- O

1 Second -- -- O
2 , -- -- O
3 Hillary -- -- B-PER
4 has -- -- O
5 been -- -- O
6 through -- -- O
7 two -- -- O
8 disastrous -- -- O
9 , -- -- O
10 disorganized -- -- O
11 White -- -- B-ORG
12 Houses -- -- I-ORG
13 under -- -- O
14 Bill -- -- B-PER
15 Clinton -- -- I-PER
16 and -- -- O
17 Obama -- -- B-PER
18 . -- -- O
